OK so after install on Kali Linux We're going to proceed to install and the second machine in our lab
.
So the second machine is going to be exploitable exploitable is another Kali is another Linux machine
You can think of it as the opposite to call the So-Cal is designed so that you can use it to hack into
other devices middes light a will is designed so that you hack into it.
So it's designed for people who want to learn penetration testing.
It is designed so that it has a number of learning abilities and we're going to try to use the next
in order to hack to meet us floatable.
So this is going to be one of the target or victim machines you can download this from the following
link.
You will end up with a zip file like this one.
So sorry not this one like this one.
So once you uncompress it you'll get this directory.
Double click it and you'll see the following files.
So again you create a new machine here in virtual machine and I'm going to call it with us Teutul and
this is going to be a Linux machine.
And I'm going continue.
And I'm only going to give it a gigabyte of RAM should be enough
and then I'm going to use I remember with calisthenics we created a new virtual hard disk with this
we're going to use an existing one.
The reason for that is because the image that we have right now is actually it's designed for VM Ware
player.
So we're going to do is we're going to import the hard the hard disk file or the hard disk image in
here so that we're going to have a ready installation without having to install it the way we install
clinics.
So we're just going to use an existing virtual hard disk file and I'm just going to navigate to select
what it does.
I'm going to go into the Mityas portable directory and I'm going to select the dot MBK file.
So it's this file right here.
I'm going to click on open
and create.
So we're gonna start this machine right now.
OK.
So the machine has runouts completely installed.
As I said you don't really need to install anything we just imported a ready installation already hard
disk.
So was asking me for the username and the user name is and as admin and the password is the same so
it's MSF admin as well as we can see now.
We logged in.
Now this is only this machine has a terminal.
As you can see right now and it's giving you a warning that you should never expose this machine to
external internet connection because it is a very noble machine.
It is designed to be burnable.
Now right now it's only inside our lab it's only installed as a virtual machine.
So literally nobody outside our lab can access it.
So this is a really good way of using it.
Well now this is if the machine is installed.
As I said in the future we're going to talk about how we're going to try and hack into this machine
again.
Don't be intimidated by the terminal.
We're going to be using it a lot and we're going to learn how to use it step by step.
So at the moment just we have this installed and we're going to move on to the next step and we will
talk about this once we actually need to use it in the future.
So if you want to turn off this machine all you have to do is just type power off
and hit enter and selling you that you need to be rude.
So again I'll talk about this later for now.
You do power of.
So just run the command like this and asking you for the admin password
and that's it.
It's going off now.
And here we go.
The machine is off