In this chapter the name of the game is Google contacts.
Now I'm in Chrome you're one of the things I like about Chrome is kind of fun if you can come down here
actually and search by voice.
I'm going to do it the old fashioned way.
Come up here and actually type in G-Mac.
We're going to go there first.
And if I'm signed in which I think I am it will load my account from Gmail.
If you come over here to the word mail and click.
You've got contacts as well as tasks go to contacts.
What exactly are contacts.
You probably already know that.
But it is one place where all your contacts are but they don't just have to be contacts from Google
Apps for business real handycam.
This is my contact area and it can be anybody I want it to be served but these contacts are going to
be probably a little bit different I suppose.
Let's just take a walk through the application for context.
Let's just talk about what we're going to talk about in this chapter.
Over here you have a new contact but which will do making new contacts.
This one my contacts are only one.
But don't forget something or starting from scratch if you're here because you've been using these apps
but you want to know more about them you may have a whole bunch of people in here.
I only have one so far.
I do have her start.
So if I had a whole bunch of people start I could sort them by start I imported right here on 3:19 and
basically then I deleted them I want to show you how you do that.
But it will tell you the last time you actually imported some contacts the most contacted other contacts
directory is the one place where whether they are your contacts or not you can see everybody.
Now if you remember if you've been following through these lessons from the beginning the only people
we added Besides me were Bonnie and James.
So they're all here.
Over here we have new group.
Now that's important because we're going to start talking about groups in this chapter groups can really
help you focus in and get things done faster.
And we have an import context down here if I hover over here I get Bonnies people which.
I can contact her e-mail her anything I want to do.
Let's go back to my contacts up here.
If you click this little button you can say show me everybody.
Show me none.
Show me starter and starred in this case I only have one so that's that big of a deal.
Over here we have the ability to add an over here if we click more.
We can do things like manage import export print find and merge duplicates is something that I really
like because I bring contacts in a lot through CXXVI files come separate value files might have 20 30
people in it and it's really nice to know if you accidentally have a duplicate.
It will take care of that for you.
Restoring contacts is kind of fun too because you can delete people say a week ago and go on it and
I wish I hadn't done that and actually restore them in sort by first or last name.
Over here you have two chevrons which allow you to go forward or backward.
If you have a lot of people and of course we have our settings button right over here we can change
the display density from comfortable to compact configure the inbox.
I don't think I've showed you that yet.
It does allow me to select tabs to enable for primary social promotions updates forms if I want to use
those as tabs and go ahead and get back out of here.
And of course we have settings themes if you want to change the theme in how this comprises basically
the contact's user interface.
And during these lessons what we're going to do is add delete control manage our different contexts.
So let's go out and get started.