If you're not in your G-mail go ahead and go there and then go up to the word male on the pull down
menu and go down to ask Remember we can get these here we can get them in contact tasks.
Follow us.
So we have work on google training.
I've got koi pond with purchase fish food and clean filters.
I come up and look in my email and I remember that Jean's right here invited me on a fishing trip and
we're taking off for you over to pick you up about 3:45.
That's his e-mail to me and I would like to add that to my tasks.
That's pretty cool.
Watch this.
Come over here and click here.
Ticket right there.
Now you can do more than one book to the word more.
And check this out.
Add to tasks I don't have to make task.
It's going to make it for me.
And there is an advantage to doing it this way.
There's the related e-mail right there.
Let's say we go back out of here and we get into say context that we don't have the e-mails anymore
and we look over at our tasks and we see that fishing trip what was in that e-mail I forget time.
And I can come over here and click related e-mail no matter where I am it will take me to the e-mail
that gives you a lot of power using e-mails in conjunction with tasks.
Now we can come over to this Chevron right here and we can add more details like the due date is Sunday.
And that would be the 23rd over here.
I could put notes in here.
Pick up whatever and we can go back to list just by clicking here.
Now I'm thinking pop that out here before I start thinking I'm thinking that task is more of a personal
thing than it is really in my working.
Andy Anderson's list.
So I want to make another list and you can do that of course if I come down to this button right here
and click I can make a new list.
I can delete.
I can rename.
I can refresh Now what's refresh.
You have to understand something here.
We're not working on our computer.
We're working through the Google servers.
People say well you know I do things like I move folders and files around my computers all the time.
And it's like instantaneous.
Why sometimes does it take a second or two or even a minute to see the results inside of Google Apps.
It's because you're running it through the Google servers Refresh will push it for you.
Well we want a new list and I'll call it family matters.
Really that was a TV show click OK.
Now there's nothing in it yet.
If we come back down to this button we can go now into Andy Anderson's list.
Now I want to move this one so I'm going to get into my details again over here.
End down here I can now move it into family matters go back to list.
I can come over here now and change to the family matters but sometimes it might take a second or two.
That's when you refresh if you need to do it again if we go over to actions we have things like in Denton
and then up down and edit details which we've already talked about.
You got help and tips.
Another one I like is e-mail e-mail task.
I can now if I want to e-mail this task back to James or anybody else that I want.
So if I come up here and say e-mail Pask list it will be more than glad to open up an email for me.
Now it's not assuming I want to send it to James and that's fine with me but I can come up here now
and begin typing in James and others to James is my down arrow key because that's easier and then press
the return key anti-Mac the enter key in Windows.
Love the different names I can see see I can be see if I want to but I can also add more information.
Now think about this in a business situation instead of you just typing in a task which is fine I do
that all the time.
You relate the task to an e-mail and now you've got one more link in the chain.
Keep the communication open.
I'll go ahead and get out of this one down here and it'll pop this back over here.
I've noticed that sometimes when I do a relational e-mail and I've got this top out which we did have
we headed over here I noticed that sometimes it will put it back over and pop it back in and sometimes
it won't.
I'm not sure.
To be honest with you if it's something that I'm doing I'm just not realizing it or if it's doing it
on its own whim whatever it's still there that's fine.
You want to pop it out you can't.
Let's go ahead and close this for now.
Let's go and I'm going to come up here and go in to count.
Now in calendar if I want to change into a different task list I can come down here and there's family
matters.
Now eventually things come to an end task are completed.
So you take them off.
Now I could very easily just delete this one right here using that little trash can icon right there
if I want to do it that way.
But maybe you've got several couple of them pass are completed and what you want to do is just get rid
of those tasks.
You can go into actions right here.
And one of your options is to clear completed tasks.
You can also view completed task sort by DO day or print them and that one will be gone.
You can switch back over into our other list and we do the same thing if we want to task do one thing
and they do it very well.
They help us with our workflow.
But as you're going to see as we move through these chapters G-mail contacts tasks all work together
to produce a workflow for us.
That just makes us more efficient.
That's what it's all about isn't getting more efficient.