We have our drive install Let's go back into it.
I'm going to go drive.
And again it remembers what I did.
You might have to sign in if you do go ahead.
Now I only have one thing right now.
We're going to start totally from scratch.
And that was the meeting notes that I attached to a document in a previous chapter.
Let's take a look around the interface right here.
Over here you have a drive button.
If you click it knows how.
Kind of just refreshed itself.
So remember what we're doing here.
I think you know this but we are running off of the Google servers on a cloud and it's raining down
on us.
This is not local this is cloud.
And every once in awhile things can take a few seconds.
So if you're not sure you've got the latest you could click that button and refresh you have a search
area up here which is point powerful.
And if I click this little button you can see a lot of the things that we can look for.
We'll talk more about this later.
Over here you have an info button info and details in activity.
We don't have any yet.
We can change the view from a list like this into a grid in the grid will show you a small kind of like
icon of what you're looking at.
So we're talking about all kinds of things here.
We have our options under the gear.
We can go from comfortable to compact settings on upload settings.
Notice some of the options here convert.
There were two types of documents that you can have inside the Google Drive or I should say two types
of files.
One is native to the application that you use like Microsoft Word and the other one would be a Google
doc.
You can convert them if you want to which means you can use the Google apps to the cloud to work on
them or you can just keep them as they were as say on or PowerPoint presentations whatever and then
work with them outside of google up to you.
We can manage our apps keyboard shortcuts and help let's close out here.
Here's the only thing I have uploaded that one thing I did in the previous chapter if we come over here
and click the create button.
This is where you start organizing this thing.
Think of it just like any other hard drive with folders but with things like documents presentation
spreadsheets forms drawings and you can connect to more apps over here.
As a matter of fact if you remember in an earlier chapter I downloaded from Gmail apps the lab mind
map.
I love doing mind mapping and now it's over there for me.
You might not see this one if you didn't download it but we can connect over here and even get more
if we want to.
If we click this button we can start making files and folders and start creating our organization over
here.
You can say what's been shared by me.
What's been starred.
You do have a star over here if you want to use it.
What's recent.
What's trash.
You click on more.
You can work off line.
We will talk about that too.
All items right down there.
Now as we start working and we start uploading or downloading stuff you will eventually see a little
icon come down over here in the lower right and it will say Show all.
And when you say show all it will show you all of what you have done in terms of downloads Well there
you go.
In a nutshell the heart of the system.