We've got Dr. setup the beating heart of Google Apps for business and we're ready to do some stuff.
Now you'll notice I already have some stuff over here on the right where I was experimenting around.
Don't worry about that stuff.
We'll talk about that in a minute.
I still only have one document meeting notes and it's not even in a folder.
So what I'm going to do here is go to the word Croma and go on to quit.
I'm going to get out of krump.
Now what I have here let me start from the beginning.
Whether you're on a Windows system or a Mac system you will have the option of creating a shortcut to
get into your Google Drive.
And remember I'm not in google drive now.
I'm on my computer and I'm going to come up here if I'm on a Mac and I'm going to open the Google Drive
for you know what I need organization.
How do we organize the computer folders.
That's how we do it.
We create folders maybe additional drives maybe like I have over here but folders this Google Drive
that I just opened up is the cloud.
And it's waiting for me to do something so we can attack the problem of organizing our Google Drive
in two different ways.
We can attack it directly from our computer locally or we can attack it from Google Drive and let's
do both.
I don't want that sticking out there all by itself.
I need a folder I need at least a folder for PDA.
If not PDA for business ideas for personal we'll handle that in a second.
So Mac or Windows it doesn't matter just right click your mouse.
What are your options will be new folder.
I see that that means it's sinking with the cloud and eventually it will come to a checkmark like this
one.
Meaning it has successfully sunk XEDIT word sun is in sync.
I'm going to change the name to
and I'm going to move this one inside there.
Again it's going to try to think again not try it will.
And when you get that check mark it's done.
Let's close this now I'm going to reopen chrome or explorer safari.
Doesn't matter it right back in come up here and when type in drive it will remember what I did so drive.
Google dot com.
And I should already be signed in again and take me back.
I've got a folder I don't have as many folders as I want.
That folder is basically holding my PTF dock.
And there it is.
And you can see PTF docks over here.
How do we do this.
If we're in Google although I will admit to being very comfortable working with an operating system
I do a lot of my basic setup the basic setup just right in that folder.
And then I come back here and then I fine tune it.
So we've got PTF docks right here let's say in PTF docks.
We want a subfolder for business and one for personal so we can click here and make sure you have the
selected we can click here and we can go into new folder and let's call this one business.
We create
and if we open this up right here you can see it.
Stay selected here because if we slot business it'll put the folder inside of business.
So stay on this make it read and we can do that again.
This is not the only place we can do this and we can send you folder again.
And this one will be family.
So now we have business and we have family and we can drag and drop.
That's one of the things I like and that's part of the Crome experience.
We can drag and drop stuff in there from our computer.
I work off multiple drives and a lot of you might.
But I've also got chrome completely expanded in my window.
I could shrink that down just a little bit and just start dragging in a drop in.
Let's go back to PTF docs because this one is kind of left hanging isn't it.
If I grab it here I can move it into business.
I mean this is just like any other computer.
We're just doing it through the cloud through Google Apps drive.
Now let's go further with this and say well you know what my business.
I probably need to share with a couple of people on notice the icon right now is just as kind of a gray
folder looking thing.
What that means is it isn't shared.
But I do want to share that folder.
The business one not the family I want to leave that alone or maybe I want to share that with specific
family members.
So let's get to business first.
Make it read Come over here and click this little button again and you do have an option to share now
we can get that another way.
I actually can get it about three or four ways but this one is kind of convenient.
We're going to share.
There it is.
That's the link.
Who has access.
Me Who do I want to invite.
Now remember we haven't gotten too far into groups yet although we did create one group in a previous
chapter you could type in the group name and everybody in the group would have access.
Or you could type in individual names like maybe that's what Mike they have access to this.
So come down like Mike now can edit or can he just view.
Of course that's up to you.
And you can add more than one person up here just separate them by a comma Mike.
He's management and he would have or should have the ability to edit some leave that as can edit.
I do want to notify him you know actually put a message in here it's optional because it'll give him
information
here is access to the folder.
Do I want to send a copy to myself.
I usually do for record purposes.
Some would say yes.
Now you have one more option down here on editors.
And if you click Change you can say editors are allowed to add people and change the permissions or
only the owner can change the permissions.
And I think on that one I'm going to leave it on.
Editors are a lock and click save.
Now there is no further action required by Mike.
In other words to confirm it because he already has access.
Any time I want to I can come back into sharing I can select here.
I can say no he can only view or I can take him out completely right here.
I don't know if you want to do that to your manager.
Click on now you will notice something that's changed.
Looks like a little tiny person doesn't it.
That means that that particular folder is shared.
And now something else happens if you add another folder to that folder.
So we have it selected its read them over your come down into new folder
if you have a shared folder and you put another folder inside the shared folder it takes on the properties
of the parent.
It is a shared folder by default so we'll call this one
create and share not just create.
You can see now that one has a little tiny icon there too.
Let's get out of here if we come back in an open up our drive folder on our drive and go into theirs.
You have docks the old one we have so far this one has a little tiny people icon on it indicating it's
a share.
Of course if we open that one up we have another one in there that's a share.
When you're creating the drive or after you've created it I should say it's then up to you to begin
organizing your information which takes me back to something that I harp on a lot in harping means pushing
it organization.
You now have your drive put the folders together for your business.
Put the folders together for family and personal begin the organizational process drop into those folders
the things that you want on the cloud and whether you want to give people access or not.
That's what Google Drive does or at least that's the beginnings that Google Drive.
We're not done.
Let's go ahead and close out here and move on.