We've got our drive home and away Mac or Windows notwithstanding we have created some folders for organization
which to me that's the bottom line.
You don't have folders you don't have organization and all this stuff is sitting right on the cloud
ready for me to access when ever I want it.
But we're not done.
How about adding files that we started with one PTF called meeting notes.
How about getting more stuff before we do let's add another folder.
But I don't want this folder is part of PTF docs.
I want it as a separate folder.
So make sure you have my drive selected here it's in red.
Go to the word create this time you do from over here to use the word create and say folder.
The only thing in here you might not see is mind map.
And if you remember from a previous chapter I pulled that off of G-mail lap and basically that's why
that's there.
I love mind mapping.
I could teach a whole course on mind mapping.
I think mind mapping really helps keep you organized in understand what you're trying to do but I need
to shut up and make a folder.
So click right here.
Now what that guarantees because we clicked on my drive.
It guarantees it's not going to go into the PTF Docs folder and I'm going to call this one.
Cooking a lot of you know if you have listened to some of my other lessons or been to my classes I use
a lot of cooking analogies because I did.
I am actually still a chef.
I did study at school.
I run a small catering business when I have time I write cookbooks.
I want this part of my business and why not use Google Apps for that.
The folders called Cooking will create now inside of cooking's on make sure I like cooking here.
I can go click Create again and Creedon of the folder.
This one will be recipe.
Capitalization is not important but if you want to you can.
And again inside of cooking I want one more and it will be tips tricks that create here it is over here.
If we click on it we can drag and drop stuff in.
We select the one over here we want to do that too.
But what if we don't want to drag and drop.
I work on multiple monitors so I do have a lot of fun doing that.
I just grab it and drag it over.
We could go back out on to our desktop and drag it over from there.
Now I want to do it right here because I don't want to drag and drop and these recipes are somewhere
else and I want to get them.
So with the recipes folder selected right here I can come up to this button right here and upload files
or folder.
When you go to files now on my desktop now they will be alphabetized unfortunately.
But I do have some recipes and let me go ahead and pull this out so I can see this here.
I want this one right here.
Creamy turkey soup.
I'm going to hold down and this would be true on a Mac or Windows system.
I want to hold down the command key on a Mac.
The control key in Windows to select different recipes without selecting everything in between them.
Buttermilk biscuits recipes.
Now it would have been more efficient for me obviously if I put all the recipes in a folder maybe and
just actually selected that fold and that's fine.
But that's not how I'm doing it.
And that's the way you know you live with what you have.
OK.
Let's stop right about there and say open.
Here it is.
It's uploading them
upload complete.
We can close this down.
And if I go into recipes they're there.
Now notice the big blue W that is Microsoft Word.
We'll talk about how we deal with that a little bit later.
But all we have to remember is we make folders we can then populate the folders with just about anything
we want.
Building up the drive builds us up as an organized company.
Let's go ahead and get out of here for a sec.
Notice there is no saving or anything it's just there.
If we go in here now and open up Google Drive folders I think you know what you're going to see you're
going to see cooking and if I open that up and get into recipes there they are.
I also have one called tips and tricks.
What I did was I wrote an article for cooking magazine on the conversion in European as opposed to how
we measure things in American and here it is right down here.
So since I'm here who's dragged over
we've now created a cooking folder at least I have the information is there and if we go back into Google
Chrome or Explorer or whatever and go back into Dr. and open up cooking there it is.
And again remember these are all Microsoft Word documents.
We'll talk about that later.
Think carefully as you build your system up.
Matter of fact I'll put this in my mind map it so you get right.