In this lesson I want to show you something that we are going to talk about in more detail when we get
into the docks chapter and the presentation chapter.
But we've got stuff don't we.
We get into cooking right here.
We've got recipes and I can select one of these and I can share it with somebody.
But sharing isn't sending it is it.
It's just giving permission to access it.
They're not necessarily getting this as an attachment as an e-mail.
They're just getting permission to share at home send it somebody.
Let's do one thing first.
We had one Google app that we deleted didn't with pineapple express.
I want to bring that one back.
I love being able to do this as long as I haven't deleted it out of my trash.
Take out the trash Naki.
Click here to go back to Google Dr..
We're back in the cooking and our she is going select.
There are a couple of ways that we can do this we don't have to do it from here but I've got it I'm
working on it.
Made some changes to it.
Whatever I come up to the Word file on the pull down menu here and one of my options is to e-mail as
an attachment.
Now this will work with presentations and all the other parts of the Google app for business family.
If you come up here what you're going to see is going to be based on what particular thing you're trying
to move.
So if you're using presentation you would have the ability to change it back into a PowerPoint presentation
you say amen.
I wish I hadn't taken this out of Microsoft Word.
The guy that needs it needs it.
In Microsoft Word change back here.
No big deal.
Plain Text.
Now the two most going to search through my personal and through my business users I to send this to
Bonnie at her real India account.
The subject will be the name of the document and that's fine I guess and I could send her a small message.
This is brilliant.
I usually do send the copy to myself because that gives me a record and clicks on whether it's a presentation
document or a form doesn't matter if you need to send it to somebody as an email you can sharing just
gives them permission to share it sending it to them actually gives it to them.