Let's go into cooking recipes and I'm going to come down here obviously you've got your own stuff in.
I'm going to go into this one right here but I'm going to cook a little tick right here.
Now when I do I can go up to the word more for example and I can go down to share.
And this is another place where you can do e-mail attachments or just plain old share or if you've got
a ticked off right here you can come up to the spot right here and share.
There are probably a dozen ways to do anything in these programs.
And really that's not confusing.
That gives you the ability to choose which one of them is the most convenient for you.
I'm going to invite some people to this particular document.
It could be a folder Don't be a document.
I'm going to use the group that we created in a previous chapter and we called it Starfire.
There are three contacts inside of Starfire and I'm giving them the ability to edit right over here.
It's got him right here.
Notify them the e-mail.
You can add a message if you want to.
I'm going to send a copy to myself.
I'm not going to paste the item itself into the e-mail Kwikset.
So they now all have access and can edit.
They are by definition collaborators and we're all working on the same recipe.
So I send it to them.
But I realized something I made a mistake in the recipe.
And if they actually make it the way I suggested they're not going to be very happy.
So I got to make a change here I go.
I send this to.
Did I send it to everybody in Starfighter not send but share.
What do we do.
Well if we come back up it's still to go to more and go down to share.
What share with collaborators or email I should say.
There they are.
Come in here and say
Send a copy to myself.
I usually don't paste the sun now you also had the ability I kind of quit that a little bit too fast.
You could unstick people if you didn't want to send it to them too.
So when you're sharing something with somebody they're called by definition by Google a collaborator.
You have the ability every time you make maybe some major change to let them know you've made a major
change and don't let them just guess at it.
And you'll notice over here it also does say shared working with collaborators.
It's just one more way drive.
In this case Google Apps for business keeps you organized.