Greetings everyone and welcome to Google Apps for business.
Google apps in my opinion is really changing.
They've been around since about 1997 I believe changing how businesses interact through the cloud.
In this lesson I want to talk about how we're going to use this course and why you might want to be
here.
But don't forget technical information is about to be disseminated so please stay alert at all times.
Google Apps for business is divided up into these individual Cloud Access business apps.
For example you have something called G-mail which is a big one and we'll talk about these in more detail
as we go along.
You've got something called tasks the Google calendar.
Your organizational tool Google Drive which involves things like documents presentation also call slides
spreadsheets forms groups which are very important.
And finally we're going to wind up this whole thing by talking about the ad men Council and how we control
everything through the council.
The next question I want to answer is who uses Google Apps.
Actually quite a few people use Google apps including you.
Now you might or might not be a part of any one of the definitions that you see that makes no difference
whatsoever.
Google apps is for anybody who wants to use it.
We're going to approach this course at the beginning.
So we're going to start with the beginning a journey of a thousand miles or kilometers.
Begins with what the first step.
With me it's filling the car with fuel because I'm not going to take a journey that long and walk it.
I'm going to drive it.
But we're going to start at the beginning by doing what.
Setting up a Google Apps for business account and you may already have done this but you're not really
sure where to go from this point forward.
So we're going to take this thing from the very basics we're going to start out by setting up the account
setting up users and groups.
And there is one thing that I think is really important here because I harp on this in just about every
class that I do and that's organization in planning in knowing where you're going begin with the end
in mind.
We're going to build a good solid foundation here so the building doesn't fall over.
We're going to look at this in terms of who we are and what we're doing and why we're using these applications.
Then we're going to get into the individual apps for example G-mail.
Now that's a big one to be honest with you but we're going to talk about how it's used how we send and
receive emails how we add attachments how we archive how we create rules filters do searching and control
our G-mail.
Now we're going to move into something called contacts and those are the people you want to maintain
contact with.
We'll talk about how we add contacts and contact groups and how we control access to those groups.
We're going to talk about calendar now.
In my opinion the calendar is the main organizational tool of Google Apps for business.
And with it we control all kinds of things.
We're going to talk about creating events even creating events through Gmail how we share our calendars
how they help keep us organized.
We're going to talk about Google Drive Now Google Drive is kind of like the main drive that you access
all your information from.
You have to install it differently on a Mac in a Windows system.
And we're going to talk about both.
We'll talk about creating folders performing searches sharing files working with things in history Google
Drive then divides up into different areas.
For example Google documents will talk about the creation of documents exporting documents inserting
images and objects into documents using things as simple as spellcheck about you but spellcheck has
ruined my ability to spell anything without using it.
Well then switch into Google presentation.
Also call slides pictures worth a thousand words.
We'll talk about how you make a presentation how we add and import slides using effects how we add things
into the presentations.
We'll talk about Google's spreadsheets.
We'll create them we'll create them with templates we'll make formulas.
We'll talk about formatting options.
We'll talk about Google Forms creating them editing them sharing them and exporting them.
We'll get into a very important area.
Google Groups now this is distribution team collaboration.
We'll talk about what groups are and how you set them up.
To me Groups is a very important chapter because it's going to change your workflow.
We will then wind up with something called the administration Council.
Now in my opinion he or she who controls the administration Council controls the world of their business
apps.
We're going to talk about adjusting settings in G-mail calendars contacts in business.
We'll talk about resetting passwords.
He who controls the administration Council controls their world.
I can safely say though by the time we're finished you will have a fairly good understanding of what
Google Apps for business is and what they are used for.