In this lesson let's look at exactly how Google apps work.
Now I tell people this all the time but nobody ever believes me.
Technical Information is going to be disseminated.
Please stay alert at all times.
We are talking about cloud computing cloud computing starts with the Google server.
Now that's where all our stuff is and we will talk about backing up our own stuff.
But Google's got my stuff any where I am on almost any kind of device.
All I need is a connection to the Internet.
Now could be hard wired into a business system.
It could be a laptop it could be a smartphone.
It doesn't matter if I have that connection.
I can do my G-mail I can chat I can video chat if I want to.
I can organize my personal and business information.
I can create information in a variety of forms and then share it with others all while sitting down
with an espresso and a piece of chocolate pie in my favorite coffee bistro which is kind of how I hang.
If you've got a connection you've got it made.
But that leads me to another question and that's a question of security how safe is my stuff.
Now the answer to that question is it's not your problem.
Not really I mean there are things we can do.
We'll talk about that.
But it's Google's problem.
So let's talk a little bit more about that.
What does Google do.
Well there are cloud based.
They discover a problem.
Let's say they discover a hole in their programming that a potential hacker could get through and they
close the hole they put that out onto the cloud in like rain.
It all comes down to US security updates are automatic.
But that's also true of your applications.
They come up with a better way to do something.
They put it on the cloud.
It rains down on top of us and that allows me to relax and conduct business with an espresso and a piece
of chocolate pie in my favorite coffee bistro.
So now that you know with Google Apps for business is all about it's time to get serious.
And they do say a journey of a thousand kilometers or miles begins with the first step.
And our first step is setting up an account to tell you what I'll see you in the next chapter.