Greetings everyone it's time to talk about my 10 Reasons Why You Should you must.
You just got to be using Google Apps for business.
Now I understand.
Any time I'm involved with doing a presentation technical information will be disseminated so please
attempt to stay alert at all times.
Let's talk about ten reasons just 10 things that are in Google Apps that we are going to cover in this
title.
Among others that I really think make this a deal breaker number 10 cloud storage.
I call this in a sense my anytime anyplace anywhere I want my stuff I can get it on my computer.
And when the cloud comes in you know what and he says Let it rain.
I don't care where you are.
I don't care if you're on the International Space Station.
If you're working with Google and you've got drive setup which we're going to do you can get your stuff
any where you want.
That's my number 10 my number 9 is just plain old organization.
I'm talking about the cloud and keeping it together.
Google works with users and you have an admin that is the person we are in a sense we're setting this
all up all your users can communicate with each other.
Any place that they are on the planet any time day or night and the admin kind of keeps everything together
if you know anything about me I'm a big believer in organization.
This program does it.
I want to tell you.
Number eight calendar in a little piece of calendar called resources.
Now you run a business you've got stuff in your business you know meeting rooms maybe microphones projectors
computers chairs tables everything you go into a calendar and as admin you will set this up.
Let's say you have six wireless microphones so each one is a resource.
I go into calendar and I want to set up a meeting and I want it in a particular room.
I'm going to need this projector I'm going to need this computer this microphone whatever.
And so I set all that up and we're going to do that when you decide the date if the date is conflicting
that's what I love about this.
If it conflicts with somebody else using that room or that microphone you'll know so you can either
strike a deal with that person to get the stuff you need or change your meeting calendar and resources.
That's my number eight my number seven is Google Labs.
Now we have an expression in the cooking industry that all chefs are mad scientists and I kind of agree
with that.
What are labs.
Well it's just crazy good stuff.
Like for example in calendar or even in drive what happens is you open up calendar.
Now let's say you run the type of business where you're working with people all over the planet in time
zones is important to you.
There is a lab you can install in calendar that will give you a world map of times.
Google Labs adds functionality to the pieces of Google Apps for business.
That's my number seven number six.
Well it's a free for here chats video and phone calls but I like the way that it's done and conducted
in Google Apps for business.
It's not just like Skype ing or using messages inside of Apple's program because of the user interface
and how it's all put together.
It creates an organized set and I do like the fact that I not only can do text in video chats but I
can actually make phone calls on landlines directly from Google Apps for business and that's my number
six number five groups they get all kinds of groups that you can work in.
You have e-mail you have web forums you have Q&amp;A forms you have collaborative inboxes.
The whole process through the cloud allows you to get together with selected people and discuss just
about anything you want to.
And we've all been involved with things like blogs.
Google doesn't really good.
That's my number five.
Number four is collaborators like the French resistance I suppose this is sharing taking to its limits
documents presentations spreadsheets whatever you're working on something but you need some information
from somebody else maybe even another opinion.
You set it up and you begin collaborating in the person that you're collaborating with could be on the
other side of the planet.
You not only can work together through chat but you can work on the document together through chat collaborators.
I like that.
That's my number for number three reports.
Businesses run on the reports and Google Apps really gives you what you need here.
G-mail reports calendar reports drive even something called alerts.
It tells you what you need to know about your business and how it's running and the alerts are really
cool.
For example you can set an alert to warn you if somebody is trying too many passwords on a user account.
Reports is my number three.
Number two going off line.
Unplugging if you will I call it total productivity.
You download what you need from the Google Cloud you work where ever you want to send it back to the
cloud when you get re-access.
So you're on an airplane and you don't want to pay the 10 bucks to get that Internet service.
And basically you've got three hours on the plane what are you going to do now before you get on the
plane.
You download what you need you can work on it on the plane off line and when you get back on line boom
plug it back in.
That's my number two my number one is templates.
You say that your number one.
They're not in any order but I do like templates.
Templates can extend your creativity to it's limits documents and forms and spreadsheets whatever.
Let's say you're doing a form and it's a typical form where you want name address city state zip that
kind of stuff.
Why reinvent the wheel.
There are not only hundreds and hundreds of google forms out there but there are thousands if not tens
of thousands of forms from people like us documents spreadsheets all of that stuff directly inside of
Google Apps for business.
It will increase your productivity and take your creativity.
In my opinion to its limits Well there you go.
To me 10 very good reasons why you need to be using Google Apps for business.
But we've talked enough about it.
Tell you what let's get started.