All right now that we're done with the pleasantries in this chapter we need to set up shop.
Now in my opinion this is the most difficult chapter in the entire series because there are some things
either you or your I.T. people are going to have to do to coordinate Google Apps with business with
your host server.
That's going to be different for every host server that's out there.
But I think I've got a good idea on how I'm going to teach this.
Once you get over this hurdle and believe me it's not really that big of a hurdle.
Once you get over it I would say it's not necessarily down hill but you get into the fun of setting
things up because now it's going to work for you.
So this chapter is the most crucial chapter in getting Google Apps for business up and running.
You're ready.