What is it Google for business account without workers users.
So let's go back into our admin Council and let's come down here to users.
Now there's only one which is Me of course.
Go and click over on the left shows my name last signed in and my email usage which I haven't done anything
yet.
Over here we have controls like number one this one right here adding more users.
So let's do that.
Now do you want to add them manually or using a CFE file upload.
In other words you're putting them all into a document and it just takes them and just puts them all
in for you.
I'm going to do it manually.
We'll just do one you do one you can do 100.
I want to say manually continue.
So let's set up an account here for Bonnie Lloyd.
Now her primary email address for me will be Bonnie real Andy dotcom.
It will allow you to set up a temporary password.
So let's go ahead and click here and give her a temporary password.
Now we can choose to require her to change it at the next sign in which I think is a pretty smart thing
to do.
Let her make her own password create new user give the user name is Bonnie Bonnie a real Andy dotcom.
What I want to do basically is e-mail the instructions to her which I could do by clicking right here.
I could print them if I want it to which I usually do and I put them in a folder.
But if we want to create another user we go here if we are finished as we build our organization we
build our users.
No we're not done.
This is the easy part obviously.
But we will talk about permissions and what they can and can't do but start setting up it's one of the
first things that you're going to do.
Start setting up your users.