Before we get started in this chapter let me ask you a question Are we a going to create a form in this
chapter B are we not going to create a form in this chapter.
Or C take a nap.
What I just did was a multi-part question wasn't it.
Forms do that.
Now you have a choice.
You can call up everybody that you need information from and get the information from them or you can
create a form.
Now I'm in crome.
I'm not trying to push Google Chrome on you obviously but I do have a Google account.
I'm not talking about my Google Apps for business account.
I have a Google account.
It's FREE.
Over here I don't have to type up here the word drive.
Google.com.
I can come over here and click and get it right here.
Is this a great planet or what.
Go into your drive.
However you get there.
Go there on Explorer go there on safari go there and Firefox for that matter.
I do have a folder that I created for forms.
So what I want to do first I suppose is select that folder go up to the word create and go down to form
now forms are a brilliant way.
They really are to get information from people and they are embarrassingly easy to make in Google Apps
for business.
So let's go ahead and select form here we go.
The first thing is the title.
Now let's call this say something like Starfire I suppose choose a theme you can look through these
There's quite a few.
Let's do something relatively professional in terms of I guess that means maybe boring.
I'm going to go Hetter Gray the color gray is actually an absence of color but it's considered a serious
kind of lot.
I'm trying to be serious here so we're going to click OK down here and that brings us right in to the
first question.
So what do you want to do here.
Well first off let's change the form description to vital information needed for the Starfire project
meeting.
First question are you going to attend.
Now you can put help text in here if you want to.
It's not necessary.
Here is where we decide with the question type is going to be text paragraph text multiple choice checkboxes
choose from a list scale grid date time.
I'm going multiple choice because one of the options on multiple choice is go to a particular page based
on an answer.
So here option 1 would be yes.
Now you can use the tab key if you want that's easier and good on the next field and type in I suppose.
No positive and negative.
I suppose you could add a third one saying I'm not sure yet but I don't want indecision.
You're either going to tell me you're coming or you're not going to tell me you're coming.
So this is a required question just like that's what we've done.
Our first question now I'm not ready to do the.
Where did they go.
Based on yes or no we're in talk about that in a second.
Let's come down here and talk about add another item.
Now we do also have this confirmation page and that will be sent when they click the submit button.
Let's add another item that we can add all kinds of things here.
If you add another question it will stay on the same page as the first question.
I want this on another page.
So I'm going to go page break right here.
And incidentally I have to tell you something in working in Google Apps every once in a while I will
when I do something go to the second question.
It will tell me something went wrong and you need to start all over again.
And if this happens again please contact Google Maps.
So if you see that you're probably not doing anything necessarily wrong.
Now I'm just going to put for the page title y description is optional.
I'm going to come down the ad item again on this page.
OK.
Actually let me click done first.
That might help.
Let's come in here and I'm going to put in a text field.
Now the title is Why are you not attending.
They can put help text in if you want to question type is text.
This is where their answer is going to go.
And it is again a required question click done on this case.
You will notice that.
Are you going to attend.
We'll continue to the next page.
We'll talk about how we change these in a second.
Let's add one more thing so far.
Let's come back in here and do a page break.
Let's talk about transportation
a done here and add an item here and this one is going to be choose from a list you know a lot of different
options.
This is really cool.
How will you arrive help text if you want it.
Now here's the list.
Now we can again go to a page based on their answer.
But an option one let's say playing a press the tab key train auto alien craft submarine goes as far
as you want.
I know I'm being silly.
I apologize for that but sometimes I get into these moods.
It is a required question.
A Let's stop there for a second if we come up here again what I want is are you going to attend if they
say no I want them to come here and say why.
But if they are attending Obviously I don't want to know why they're not attending.
I want them to go to the next question down here.
So we're going to get back up in this one and edit.
Now you can click in it to edit it or you can click the button over here either way it's fine.
OK.
Go to page based on answer click here.
We don't want them to continue to the next page.
We want them to go to the Y page or the transportation page depending on what they do.
So this one is yes go to transportation.
This one is good.
Why.
Go and click on on this one.
So that's the second page.
If they do go to this page and they say no and it comes to this one and it says why are you attending.
It's still going to go down to the next page here.
But they're done.
I want to know why they're not attending.
And that's over.
So after page 2
let's see what we've got so far.
Let's come up here and say View live form says really like I said very easy required field are you going
to attend.
If you say yes and say continue how will you arrive.
You can choose that and then click submit.
Let's go back again.
Are you going to attend.
No continue.
Why are you not attending and then go to submit.
You can have as many questions here as you want to.
You can have checks tick marks if you will.
You can have multiple choice.
You can have text fields doesn't matter you are.
Let's go ahead and close this right here or come over here and say edit the forum up to you let's just
click right here because it is saved.
We're going to show you one more thing here before we end this lesson.
If we go into my drive and I go into forms we now have two things we have Starfire which is our form.
We're now done with it.
But we have it.
But we also have responses.
And as people start coming in with their responses as you're going to see we will have a list of those
responses and not only a list we will be able to do statistics based on the information in that list.