We've created a form in we like it but we want to do more to it.
We've made some mistakes maybe we decide we want to add or take something out.
Obviously anything on a computer can be modified if it couldn't it would be useless.
So let's go into forms.
Then go into Starfire.
Let's start with the form settings that you see right up there.
One is require one of a kind of Productions Inc.
Log in to view the form that makes it very specific and I'm going to use that one automatically collect
respondents one of a kind productions username and show progress bar at the bottom of foreign pages.
Now we have all either seen or participated in online surveys and there's a progress bar at the bottom
of the screen.
Just one note about that.
This is in a survey.
They have to fill this out but surveys people don't take them according to studies.
If they last longer than 12 to 14 minutes they just don't want to sit there for a quarter of an hour
filling out a form.
I'm going to come up to the Word file on the pull down menu to show you something else up here.
I'm not really sure about the design.
I don't know that Gray.
I need another set of eyes on this so I can add collaborators now and adding collaborators what you're
doing is you're giving that person the ability to edit even to add more people to the list.
You're doing all of that is going on that Bonnie right here.
Click send.
And she can add it.
Now what that means is if she's online we could have a dialogue going back and forth right now.
We could both be working on the same document collaboration we've talked about that before and other
chapters is really a nice feature of Google lots for business if at any time now that she's a collaborator
that you feel like you want to give her an email all you have to do is go up here and go down to e-mail
collaborators and you could send an e-mail to everybody that's involved in this project that you will
want to share it so we can do that now under Edit.
You only have two things really undo and redo.
And those are my two favorite keys in the whole world.
I wish life had an undo button and make it real nice but I need to make some changes down here.
Number one if we go all the way down to our confirmation page I can change this text if I want to.
That's what they see when they submit your response has been recorded.
Thank you show a link to submit another response.
That was a mistake.
I need to turn that off.
They get one response.
Publish and show a link to the results that allow responders to edit responses after submitting.
And I'm not going to let him do that either.
I don't like that over here or coming up a little bit.
Why are you not attending.
Click here.
That box doesn't really give him a lot for explanations so I'm going to change it from a question type
text into paragraph text so they get a longer answer there.
So that gives him more room to tell me why they are not coming.
Another thing the theme itself I'm not sure about that theme.
Gray is OK but we're going on a trip and we're going to be in a hotel or whatever going a little bit
of fun to maybe making this a little bit too serious so we can come back over here again and change
into a different theme.
Now you've got some pretty wonky ones in here like birthday balloons.
How about Argo.
Let's see what that looks like.
Now we come up here in view live form that's not too bad.
I like that.
It changed the font change the background color change the background itself and there is no longer
when they submit.
Going to be a button saying you want to do it all over again.
Let's go ahead and go in to edit this form go back again.
If we go to the word insert we can insert things such as if you want to do this an image or a video.
I'm not quite sure how that would work unless you had a video for example of the lobby of the hotel
that you're going to stay at in a lot of hotels under web sites do have videos that you could link to
if you wanted to do that under Tools right here.
We have something called a script manager an editor now that just takes you into another level of control.
We're not going to get there today but script manager and script editor allow you to manage scripts
and that is like I said another level of control.
But I think I like what I want I want to add one more page.
So I want to add one more page down here.
Maybe right after transportation we can say add item page break.
How about guest's description optional.
Come down here and add an item.
And on this one let's go ahead and do choose from a list question title will be how many additional
guests will you be bringing.
Over here.
Option 1
2 3 4 and we'll leave it at that required question
and let's see how it works.
Let's come back up here one more time.
Are you coming.
Yeah I'm coming.
Can't wait.
Will you arrive.
Submarine this time.
How many additional guests will you be bringing.
And then submit it works.
Let's go back to edit and I'm not submitting because if I do it will add it to my results and we're
going to talk about those later.