Let's go back into our forum and let's assume we're ready to do something with it and send it.
There are a couple of things that you can do here and let's explore the three different ways that we
can kind of do something with this forum.
One if we go up to the Word file on the pulled on menu and go down to download as you have an option
to download and this would be the responses we don't have any yet.
Comma separated values.
So if you download it this way it would be very easy to bring that into a program say like Microsoft
Excel and then use all the power of Excel to generate charts and graphs and all kinds of things.
Another way is to in bed right here.
Now when you in bed it your pasting that text which creates a live link to google.com and the account
and allows it to display.
So if you're a Web kind of guy or gal and basically you want to put this onto a page that you have created.
There you go and you can even customize the size.
The third way is what we want to do.
We want to send it out.
So we're going to click send form right here it's ready.
You can share it on Google Plus Facebook or my personal favorite Twitter.
We don't want to do any of these.
We want to bring it down here and we want to start typing it.
Now if you remember we created a group Starfire and Starfire had three members in it.
Those are the ones that are coming to the Starfire meeting to type in instead of their names Starfire.
And there it is right there makes it a whole lot easier.
Groups can really help you out.
Now you want to include the form in the e-mail.
No I want them to have a link to click to get to it.
But either way would be fine that's up to you.
I usually say send me a copy that gives me a record of it being sent.
I can customize the message and the subject Starfire meeting custom message.
Let me know on this by Friday everything else is ready.
Click send.
And there you go off through the Internet.
Our three people are now getting an e-mail.
And it's up to them to respond.