We've got our form we're sending it out.
But we want to be involved in terms of when people send back to us maybe make changes in other words
I want a notification.
So let's do this.
I'm going to go and it forms I'm going to go into the responses now in responses go up to the word tools
and go down to notification rules.
This is pretty cool.
When do you want to be notified any changes are made.
Anything on this sheet is changed any of these particular cells or changed collaborators or added or
removed or a user submits the form.
Now I do want to know when they submit it but I also want to know if they change this up here.
Let's say we give them permission to change it later on.
And somebody says yes and then they say no or vice versa.
Well that's going to impact the hotels and how I get everything set up.
So I'm going to go into right here and then I'll click this button here.
And those are cells BE2 through before.
So BE2 colon which has come through B for before and after.
Click OK if a user submits the form or that cell changes email me a daily digest or right away click
safe.
Now there it is.
You can have as many of these as you want.
You can add another one right here.
But if you're done click down here now any time somebody submits the form I'll get an e-mail or if anybody
changes that one field.
Are you going to attend.
I'll get an e-mail notifications that can really help you stay on top of stuff.