Let me begin with a question Does anybody remember the group Huey Lewis and the news.
A very popular group years ago in the United States.
They did a song called The Heart of Rock and Roll is the beat.
So what's your point.
Well to me the real heart of Google Apps for business is Google Drive.
And that's what this chapter is all about.
Now it installs differently on a Mac or Windows system.
So we're going to cover both.
I want you to get this.
We're going to talk about its interface.
We're going to talk about adding and sharing folders.
We're talking about adding files.
We're going to convert documents for Google Apps so we can use them when we talk about additional drive
settings to control it the way you want it.
We're talking about sending email with Google Drive.
Working with collaborators I love collaborators.
And then we'll search inside of Google Drive.
So if the heart of rock and roll is the beat the heart of Google Apps is Google right.
Let's go.