I've been told that hard drives can get like addicts they get so cluttered you just can't find what
you need.
This is kind of true in a way.
But believe me we have some pretty awful searching abilities in Google Drive.
So I've got a lot more than what you see.
I mean we've got cooking and PTF FDX big deal.
I've got hundreds of folders and that's not unusual.
And I'm looking for something.
So I come up here and begin typing the word port he o r k as we say in the United States.
The other white meat.
It tells me saucy pork chops and Pineapple Express pork chops.
If I want one of those I can select it right now if I click this button over here it will show me three
things and you say what is European conversions got anything to do with the word poor.
Understand it's not just searching the title it's searching the text in the document and I find that
tremendously valuable.
But what if you want to refine the search.
What if you're getting too many results.
Well remember any time you get into any of the apps in Google besides the X which means clear it in
this button here which means search this button right here will give you options but they'll be based
on where you are and where on the drive check it out.
All Documents folders drawings images private not shared owned by me not owned by me opened by me created
with I can search for poor and then refine it by using these options.
So once you get this thing organized it's not helped or skelter you've got a very organized system of
folders and sub folders.
It's going to get pretty big.
That's just part of life.
But as it gets bigger and you're looking for something if you can think of anything about what you're
searching for in terms of a word you'll probably eventually be able to find it.
That searching in Dr..