We've got our PTF docs over here and that has two folders and that one that we can share and one that
is an.
Although I might change the share on that one to family which would make sense.
We come back over here to my dr.
Cooking has two folders recipes and tips and tricks and we do have some recipes don't we.
You know what I think I want to work on one of these recipes maybe make some changes to edit it.
So I come over here and I say Sasi pork chops and what kind of where is my editing stuff.
We don't have editing stuff.
This is a Microsoft Word document.
Now I love Microsoft Word.
I really do it's a great program but you're defeating the purpose of the efficiency of using Google
Apps for business if you're not using Google and say well I didn't make this in the Google Apps I made
this in Microsoft Word but I can't really change it.
I can view it like print it make it bigger make it small.
I can share what if they don't have Microsoft Word.
So let me show you something here.
Let's get out of here.
Click the little X close that take us right back I'm going to bring in another recipe.
But before I do go up to Little year and go into upload settings we have convert it convert uploaded
files to the Google Docs format convert text from upload a PDA it's confirmed settings before each upload.
I'm going to do this I'm going to select this one.
Let me come back over there again.
And select confirm.
I want to make sure I know what I'm doing here and sometimes I might not want it taken out of the word
format.
One question you might ask them.
You say OK I open it here and it's not opening it in Word but I have word why can't I open it here.
Well actually you can if you go back into Google Drive Let me show you this real quick.
That's the folder.
If I go into cooking and Gosain the recipes now I'll show you that I won't open it but I'll show you
this.
It will allow me to open it in Microsoft Word that's the default.
So on a Mac or Windows system if you had word and you clicked on it from here it would open it up in
Microsoft Word.
You could make your changes save it.
It would save it back to the cloud.
But that's kind of like having an extra middleman in there.
You don't really need to do that so let's do this.
Let's get back out of here.
Fun stuff.
Let's go into recipe's because I want to upload it into recipes.
Let's click this button right here and say upload a file.
Now this one I believe it's got pineapple and it's going to be in the piece there it is.
Pineapple Express pork chops with yams.
Yum.
Quick open upload settings convert documents.
Yes that's exactly what I want to do because I want to work on this in Google Apps confirm settings
before each upload.
See those are the settings I made.
That's fine.
Start up.
Don't take long at all but it takes it a second to get it back to me from the Google Cloud and sometimes
days are you know more busy than others.
Let's go and close this.
Now watch what happens when I select this one.
We are in the Google Apps word processor.
We're going to a whole chapter on word processing and I know most of you are probably more than familiar
with doing word processing but I have the ability now to modify this document because it's in the Google
Apps word processor.
I can add comments notifications I can share it if I want to and when I click this button over here
if I had made any changes they would be part of the document.
Now we're moving away on computers from forcing people to constantly stop and say save documents or
save the lot of times as we work on them especially in the cloud.
Let me do one more thing here.
Let's go to cooking recipes and we decide for whatever reason that we just don't want this one anymore.
If I click on it over here and click right here remove it now it will tell me one item was moved and
here's my undo.
It'll be up there for about 20 seconds.
But understand something.
If you do anything else that goes away.
So make sure you don't want to undo it before you do something else.
So we've moved documents in that were Microsoft Word and we've converted them into the Google Docs word
processor so we can work on them as cloud based applications.