Let's take a look at a couple of the things that you can do to make life easier inside of drives.
Well number one we've done this before but I want to mention it again.
And that is if you click the word drive up here it basically does this refresh it goes up to the cloud
and make sure you've got everything.
Remember you've got that this area over here of course is your activity.
Now the last thing that I did was drop Pineapple Express.
Pork chops with the yams in the trash.
Check this out.
I haven't pulled it out of the trash yet or deleted it from the trash permanently.
If I click on it right here it brings it back and asks me if I want to take it out of the trash now.
Yes.
When we delete something we get 20 seconds to undo it.
But as long as you haven't thrown it out of your trash yet you can still get it back if you want it.
Let me go ahead and go back to Dr.
now if I come over here and click the magnifying glass right there you will open up basically and show
it to me in the trash but it will show me everything else that I have put into the trash and I have
a button up here to restore it based on the tick mark or delete it for ever.
That's up to you.
If you want more room and you don't really care about the activity going on over here you can click
this button right here and you get more room.
Click it again to bring it back.
Don't forget you've got this button here to switch into a grid view.
I do like that because it does give you a little bit of a kind of like a visual of what you're working
on.
Over here of course we can get to other stuff under settings.
We know that we can go here for our upload settings we can go comfortable cozy compact.
It's up to you.
I'm going comfortable.
I want to come back up here again.
I want to show you two more things.
Number one keyboard shortcuts if you know anything about me you know I am crazy about keyboard shortcuts
keyboard shortcuts Cordone University study save you one hour out of every eight if you work on a computer
all day long.
One hour out of every eight as opposed to pulling menu items down or thinking and trying to figure it
out.
Learn shortcut keys.
Learn shortcut keys they are excellent.
Let's come back up here again.
Let's go into settings.
Now in here obviously you do want to set your language and you want to set your time zone.
You have an option here bold.
Any updated items which makes sense to me.
My storage.
I'm using one megabyte out of 30 but here's the cool thing.
And this is another incentive for converting images documents PowerPoint presentations into the apps
for Google only the stored items that are not converted count toward your storage limit.
Google doc formats don't use up your storage space.
We have an editing option here.
Basically we have one from right to left controls instead of left to right right to left click save
and it takes us right back here.
Now there is one more option let me show you this.
Go into manage apps now in Manage apps you have the apps that you're working with.
You can connect and try to get more apps if you want to.
This is all the apps that we have and we can get into the options on these.
If you're a product page which will give us more information on Google slides and other options used
by default if you don't want one of these used by default just go ahead and take it right here.
If you've made any changes click OK.
And we're back here again.