Talk about adding contacts and even removing them if necessary understand something about removing when
you remove a contact from Google contacts you're not really leading that person.
OK.
You don't have administrator capability to do that.
You're just taking him out of your context.
And I've got just one because I'm just setting this thing up.
I want more.
Let's talk about a couple of ways that we can accomplish this.
Now I know somebody I want to add.
That's not part of this Google domain but I still want to add them.
I know their name and I know their e-mail address.
So one way I could add this is what I call down and dirty.
It's come up here and put this button add to my contacts.
I know your name.
I know their e-mail.
How do we format that so that Google knows this is a name and this is an e-mail.
We'll start with an open quote and type in their name.
Close quote.
Use the less than sign in typing their email.
Now make up one here.
He does live in the Washington D.C. area in the United States so called D.C. dot com which I'm sure
there probably is a domain like that.
Let's go ahead and use the greater than sign.
So in quotes.
His name in less than and greater than signs is the map.
Down and Dirty look at.
So that's one way we can add a new contact the other way.
Or the second way I should say there's several ways is click new contact over here.
Of course now I could have done the exact same thing and added Graig this way and gotten more information
if I wanted to use it.
But how do I do that now with Greg since I already added them.
Let's come back here.
Well there you go.
You can add more information as she get down and dirty way to kind of add a contact scroll back here.
Another way in the way I do use a lot is by importing from a C S V.
Comma separated value file.
So if I come down here there is import contact's.
I need a c s v v card file.
I'm going to choose it.
And here it is.
Click open and go ahead and click the import button.
Now I did something sneaky.
Why you have all these imported things over here.
What I wanted to do is bring in a duplicate when you first bring in a CSP file.
It will ask you I'm going to check for duplicates now but if you re-import some that you're deleting
it doesn't do that because it assumes you know what you were doing.
I don't know what I'm doing.
I got a derk block twice don't I.
Well it would be so easy for me to click here and just simply go over to more and say remove it delete
it.
OK that's easy.
But what if you get hundreds and hundreds of contacts.
Do I have any duplicates.
I guess I could sort them by name and I'd be able to see them but I just don't want to do that.
So I have an option under more right here which is fine in merge duplicates.
Now what's the merge part.
Well what if you have a duplicate of somebody that has more contact information than the other duplicate
it will merge the information together to produce one.
There it is.
Do I want to merge it or is there something different.
Maybe it just happens to have the same name and I need to change that manually.
Now I know what it is.
I'm going to merge.
There you go.
Now the other thing which I've already mentioned to you.
If you want to remove somebody you can come over and select that person and then just go up to the word
more right here and say delete them adding is very easy.
You have several different ways you can do it from down and dirty to detail.
You can do it from C S V or v card files if you want to get rid of one or more than one.
Just check them over on the left here and basically come up here and say delete.
But these are your contacts not anybody else's.
It can be anybody you want them to be.