It's time to start getting a little bit practical here I would think contacts are there but what do
we do with them.
Well there are a lot of things.
How about sending somebody an email.
You can do that here you don't have to go back to G-mail.
So if I come up say to Dirk and hover under the click just hover I can do contact info emails recent
emails and he's never sent me any.
He's a brand new addition but I can do a chat or I can send an e-mail if I want to right from here.
So I click and I think well wait a minute wait a minute.
It's not just Dirk is it.
It's three other people or two other people or 10 other people.
So you come up here you click and you start typing.
So how about James but notice it gives me to me James Marley and James Lloyd James Lloyd is a part of
our domain but he's not part of my contacts yet.
Doesn't matter it's going to give it to me.
If he's there now you can use your up and down arrow keys to choose the one you want and just go ahead
and press the return key.
Speaking of keys the return key is the name of the key on a Macintosh keyboard and the enter key is
the name of the very same key on a Windows keyboard.
Same keys different frustrating names.
I need also my camera.
Am I.
There is.
This is not a big deal.
But what if it's 30 people.
What if it's 50 people you want to type in 50 names.
I don't.
We're here to talk about groups groups this is our first introduction to them.
The groups that we set up in contexts are different than some of the other types of groups.
We're going to do because these are not shared.
They're yours.
I'm going to get out of here.
We're working on a project and Dirk and James and Mike are all part of this group.
I want to create.
You can tick off as many as you want a new kind of peer's up here with the three headed monster on its
called group.
So go into it and go down to create new enter the group name the three of us are working on a project
for the company.
It's kind of a top secret kind of thing so I called it code named Starfox.
I just made that up actually.
Click OK.
We now have a group called Starfire.
Now let's go ahead and do another group let's say Dirk is part of management.
And Sam is part of management.
Dirk is already in one group doesn't matter.
He can be in as many groups as you want him to be.
If we come over here and do another new group here or up here come down create new We'll call this one
exec's click OK I want you to notice something over here.
It's telling me what groups they are in Starfire and exact Starfire Staffa exec OK and you get the idea
you can create as many and you can put as many people and duplicate them in there.
No big deal if we go back now say into male and we want to compose an email.
G-mail actually.
Sorry about that and start typing in Starfire.
There it is.
With one click you have added all of those people.
Now three is not a big number but 20 or 30.
That's a big number.
If you've got a lot of e-mails to do if you're working with a lot of different kind of people you go
in your contacts.
You make these groups.
It can save you a ton of time.
And I measured it and I weighed it and it's actually one physical pun.