Contacts are really important because they help us organize.
We've got all our friends in one place we can work it out.
Another area that is really good for workflow is something called tasks a task to me are kind of like
oh sticky notes.
They're kind of like sticky notes the sticky notes.
KING I've got sticky notes on my monitors I've got sticky notes in my desk.
I've got sticky notes in the lavatory.
I got them everywhere but I've got so many I don't look at them anymore which is a problem.
This might not be the best analogy but I think tasks are very similar to having a sticky note it reminds
you of something.
So in this lesson let's do like an overview of tasks and then we'll get a little bit more detailed in
the next let's go into Google and go into your mail and up here if you click mail you will notice you
have a third option tasks like that.
Tasks are pop up.
Now we can come over here and pop it out if we want to kind of like doing that to add a task.
Just start typing.
They're all say work on google training.
If I press the return key and again return key on a Macintosh keyboard the Enter key on a Windows keyboard.
And it gives me a new one.
I don't have to use it but it gives me a new one going to put in there koi pond.
Now part of koi pond to me is I need to clean the filters and I need to purchase some food for the koi
pond.
So if I come down again like this I can go into action in action.
You've got all kinds of things move it up move it down and you can do that manually in the system itself.
But you've got these shortcuts for added details help show tips email me to indent.
This one because it's part of a pod.
Let's come back up here and say purchase fish food and it will keep me on that indent and clean filters.
You can have as many of these tasks as you want to.
You can format them using the actions right here if you feel like you need to do that.
But where are task going.
Well number one a task is completed.
You can tick it off just like that and you can take it by clicking it again.
So they help us in reminding us of what to do.
But that's not all they do.
Let's go ahead and pop this back in.
Let's go in close for now and this is Andy Anderson Teslas come up to this button right here and when
you click it you get your other apps go into calendar.
We haven't been there yet.
Let's check it out.
In Calendar they appear over here.
They're interconnected.
So we've worked.
If you're following along in a sense chapter by chapter we've done a up but we worked in G-mail we've
worked in contacts and now we're working with tasks.
All this stuff is interrelated.
Everything works with everything else to produce really good work flow.
Now in the next lesson.
Let's actually get a little bit more detail on what we can do with tasks and how they can help us with
our workflow.