In this chapter we're going to talk about spreadsheets.
Now I have a confession to make.
This is a true confession.
I actually like spreadsheets.
Why.
Because I don't really love math.
Now I remember the days when everything was done with a calculator and thank goodness for solar power
calculators but all calculations were done spreadsheets were done on paper.
Not a fun time to live if you know how to create spreadsheets.
You can do very complicated mathematical stuff.
And once you put it together it will do it for you.
Over and over again.
Let's do this let's go into Dr. Google dot or Dr. got googled outcome and this time let's use a different
account.
Why on in August because we can.
So I'm going to sign into.
How about Bonnies account as an account and we'll use Bonnie at real Andy.
Let me see if I can remember her password.
We're in now.
This is a fictitious account because I'll be honest with you if I actually access my wife's account
and begin adding things to it this would be the last lesson I would ever teach for infinite skills.
This is a fictitious account.
There's nothing in it yet.
So let's do something real quick.
Let's create two folders.
This one will be spreadsheets.
And let's do one more and we'll call this one.
Sharing with Andy let's click that little button right there next to sharing with Andy and go into sharing.
And let's type in my new address down here can edit send.
All right click done.
So now if I create a spreadsheet under Bonnie's name and I want to share it with me I can just make
sure it's in there too.
Let's go in spreadsheets here.
Let's go up to the word create and go down to spreadsheet our first spreadsheet.
Let's give it a name.
How about us for infinite's skills demo.
Click OK.
We now can start it if we want to.
That's important.
Let's click on this button here.
Move to.
Now it's going into spreadsheets.
But click organize hold on the control key that's the control key in Windows command key and a Mac same
Kieta for name and click that now gives me the ability to share from my account her spreadsheet.
Anytime she doesn't want me as a part of it anymore she can and check me right here.
Quick move get ready to go home.
Let's start out at the top right up here and go down one.
Let's talk about maneuvering.
Use your arrow keys to go left right up and down or click in a cell.
Use your return key.
And if you click it once actually as you can see you go into the cell you can begin typing.
Another way to do that would be to double click if you press the tab key you can go left or right.
But if you hold the shift key down you can go backwards.
Now if you don't have access to the interior of the cell and you type something inside of it you can
use the return enter key to go down or the shift return energy to go back up again.
So it's a lot of different ways we can maneuver.
Let's get into this one right here.
You don't have to double click just start typing and type in date.
Now use the tab key and put in Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday.
Weekends are ours.
Again no if I use the return or enter key as you can see I can go down and every time I do that it allows
me to go in the cell and then I can then go on to the next cell.
So it's a nice tool to know you have a button that you know you can push.
Let's go back up to here again and let's type in one date.
I'm going to type in 0 3 that would be March and use the forward slash 15th.
Let's say for its last 20 14 Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday what are we going to do here.
Well let's just type in some numbers to start with just in that first rule.
So Type in $342 and 25 cents and making these numbers up let me put in a couple of more on Friday for
you.
OK.
So we've got some numbers we're beginning to populate this thing out.
Let's start making it look a little bit nicer.
For example click and drag go up to the word view on the pull down menu and turn off grid lines.
Now it doesn't look too good.
I agree but don't worry about it.
We're working on it.
It clears off all the other cells.
Now come over here.
See this button for borders and click this one right here we want borders.
But just in that one area it helps kind of control what we see up here.
I want to title someone do this.
I'm going to select all those cells up here it's like that.
See this button right here.
That's merge them all together.
Go ahead and click inside of it and type in the money chart.
Now we haven't done any actual text formatting or number formatting yet.
We will get to that.
We just kind of building the bones of our spreadsheet right now.
Let's go ahead and select this entire column right like that.
Now come up here this is the fill color.
Let's change that to maybe a light gray like this one right here.
Let's do the same thing to this one and same thing to the last one
up here.
Select those are all kind of grouped together in our merged.
Go in and go up there and let's give them a little bit of a dark color.
So it's beginning to come together as a chart it's saved automatically.
Don't forget that.
But there is another place if you don't want to design this.
Don't forget if we go up to the word file and go down to New from template just like in documents and
just like in presentation we can get really good pre-made templates.
Now let's go into public select spreadsheets and you can choose from any one of a number of these templates.
There are quite a few preview that you all you have to do is repopulate those areas with your numbers.
Let's go ahead and close this out and get out of templates by clicking the tab.
And let's stop here.
We've done enough.
Let's go ahead and go back into Google Dr..
So we have it now here.
And we also have it here.