In this lesson let's talk about the dreaded function calculations.
But that's where spreadsheets really shine.
So let's go back into our demo right here.
We've done so much to this.
We have columns of figures and you know what I really don't want to have to add those up with a calculator.
Do we have to do it.
No of course not.
So let's look at several different ways that we can sum up these columns.
Number one get into this one right here.
Type in an equal sign.
Now just like in Microsoft Excel that means you're about to enter a function.
The function is going to be some sort going to type in s u m Gnosis trying to help you out here.
Go ahead and put in a left right like that.
Now stop.
Pick up cursor.
Come up here and click on this cell.
Now that's b three in drag down because I don't want to have to type in B-3 through B 11 now press your
return key and that's the enter key in Windows return on a Mac.
There you go.
You now have a calculation now.
Obviously if I change a number it'll change the calculation.
That's what I love about spreadsheets.
They're so much better than a calculator.
Now we've got to do it for the next five columns.
Yes or no.
Well yes but there are ways that we can do this.
It's going to make it a whole lot easier for you.
Number one get into this area here.
Now you can see up here what we've done.
So that's not really a number it's a calculation result from this column and that's all we need to know.
If we come over and say EDID copy we are copying a formula.
If I get into this area right here and press control V which is the shortcut control V on Windows command
Viana Mac as you can see every time I do that it puts it in.
But it's smart enough to understand by default that I don't want the same calculation over and over
again change the numbers for the columns.
So if you look up here it's now ef 3 through F 11 D.
Well let's do this.
We have a button up here for undoing multiple undo.
I love Hindus.
It's my favorite key in the whole world.
Let's go ahead and take those back down to the first one.
Here's an even easier way to do it.
If I click right here you'll see a little tiny square come up right there you see it.
I talk low when I'm trying to get your attention right.
If you touch it you can turn it into a little plus sign.
That's what you want to see.
Now click and drag and you see that dotted line come up.
That's what you want but go all the way across did it again.
That one was a whole lot easier.
You say Well Andy I don't know about some I don't know a lot about calculations I saw when you typed
it in that kind of helped you out.
That was really kind of cool.
But some obviously is not the only one I want and can I find more information on doing this kind of
thing without buying a book.
And the answer to that is yes.
See this button up here for functions.
If you click it it will give you some average count max and min.
So we can do this.
Let me get rid of this one.
Just delete it so that one is not done yet but we want to summit but we don't really know how to put
it together.
So we click here.
And we come up here and we say some or average or count or max or min.
Now what do you do while you could type in.
But do the same thing just grab indirect back at square one.
We got it done.
Now I'm going to put the word totals over here because that's what they are.
And let's go ahead and put that on the right hand side I suppose.
And I think totals deserve probably at least being bold and maybe even having a darker color in here.
So let's go across and select all of the cells like that come up to bold and let's give them a different
color.
Blue color of trust.
Do you trust my figures.
I'll tell you what is doing a whole lot better job than I could do with a calculator.
So when you're doing functions Incidentally if you come back up here again and you go to more functions
it will list them all for you.
In my opinion the most difficult thing yet the most beneficial thing about spreadsheets is functions
and once you get them figured out well you can do just about anything you want.