Formulas when you work with them on spreadsheets can really make the spreadsheet useful for you because
it's doing the calculations.
Another thing that we can get into for a lot of people is a wonderful thing.
It's charts of some people can look at numbers and go and they're just numbers and some people can look
at them and go Wow those are really cool.
My brother in law is an accountant believe it or not and he loves numbers.
But when I look at a chart I get a better idea of what's going on.
So let's look at how we can make a chart.
Pretty easy.
Let's go back into our demo.
Now when you're preparing a chart you want to select the information first that you want the chart to
be say for example we want the dates and the information on Monday let's just do a simple chart here.
So I'm going to select this information right here so I have the dates and I have the amounts not the
total come up to this button right here and click it.
Now the cool thing about what I just did when I click that button is that Google Apps now begins recommending
charts based on the data that it saw.
You say oh I want more data.
You can click here and come right back out and change those numbers to reflect more information if you
want to do that.
We can do things like switch from rows to columns.
We don't have a third row is ahead or so we're not going to do that.
Here are the recommended ones.
No I don't know exactly what's going on by the numbers but I can vary instantaneously.
Look at March 17th and realize we spent a lot of money on March 17th.
Those are the recommended charts.
Now you can click more right here.
We could spend weeks here.
There's all kinds of fun stuff.
I like pie charts.
My mother used to make really good apple pies and I could always tell when my sister got a bigger piece
than I did so I know pie charts.
If I come over to one of these I can look at it this way or I can look at it today or I can do a donut
up to you.
Let's go to 3-D I like 3-D.
Once we decided on our chart we can customize it.
So if we come over to customize right here based on what we're doing we can give it a title the money
game and we can change the Bold Italic size color stuff like that.
This over here is the lechon.
K we put on the right left bottom top up to you change the color font size cetra is fonts down here.
The background if you want to change that slices are measuring in percentage right now but you can change
that if you want to we can put a border around it.
Now we don't have one with the donut hole.
That's why that's great out features are 3D you can maximize it if you want to slice as well you can
go into any one of these here and then change its color over here.
Again that's something you want to do.
Now I like pie charts because most people can understand a pie chart.
Most studies show about eight to ten pieces on a pie chart.
And people when they look at a pie chart read it like a clock.
They start at noon and go round clockwise from noon to noon.
And so I like this I'm happy with it.
I can come over here and say insert if we come over here we have a button here and you can click on
an area of the chart that you want to edit this button right here is the view mode.
It's kind of in the way isn't it.
I go down to a corner here and I can resize it if I want it or what I want it is I want it on its own
separate page its own sheet.
So I want to come down here.
We've got sheet want I can click this button right here and add a sheet but that's not how you do it.
Come back up here again come over here and click on the chart and you get editing.
If you click on it and we don't want to add it we've already done that.
Click here now advanced deaded is where we work.
It's not anything more than what we did delete.
I don't want this anymore I want to start all over again save it as an image publish it copy it or.
I love this one.
Move it to its own sheet.
So if I click here it literally puts it on its own sheet and gets it out of the way.
But it is still connected to this information.
And if I change the information over here and go back to the chart it will reflect those changes charts
to me are really important because for people who are not just into figures in numbers it's a great
way to display your information.
And with all the charts that you have available you can spend a lot of time working on these things
keep your charts for most people unless their account and simple pie charts line charts bar charts.
Those are the easiest ones for anybody to recognize if you've got accountants or doctors or lawyers
or somebody else.
They get more complicated but don't use a complicated chart just because you can use it because it fits
your audience.