One of the beauties of working with spreadsheets presentations documents in Google Apps for business
is the ability to share obviously and the ability to add comments that can be disseminated across anybody
you're sharing this with.
Now remember if I come up here we are sharing this with me.
I'm pretending to be Bonnie.
Bonnie wants to leave me a comment.
Now could be a presentation.
It could be a document.
Works the same way.
In this case select maybe a cell that you want to attach the comment to which I just did.
You can click this button right here.
You can click this button right here you go up the word insert and good on the comments over here doesn't
matter where you do it you're going to get the same thing.
So we have that cell selected and we come up here and we click say here insert it.
Now notice what happened down here first.
It's telling me the sheet now will have a comment on it.
Any sheet that has a comment will have that icon.
Let's get back over here and type in.
What do you think of this format.
Go and click that.
So she now has that comment right there.
Notice the little tiny dog ear right in that corner which shows you where that comment is.
Now let's do maybe another one up here is blue the right color.
If at any time she wants to see her comments then she can do it just by touching them hovering.
But if you click up here on comments they will appear.
But don't forget she's sharing this with me.
So let's go ahead and do this.
Let's come back out of here.
Let's go ahead and log out of Bonnie.
Sign up.
Let's go in to meet.
Let's come over here and go into shared with me.
And there it is sharing in the I can come into it and open it up and you can see I can come over to
these right here and see them.
I can also respond.
Send it back in when the Google server saves my comments.
If she's online she can actually work with it back and forth comments are a great way to collaborate
on things as complex as spreadsheets.
Make sure everything is right.
But as long as it's being shared and I can share this or she can share this with as many people as she
wants.
That's where the power of Google Apps for business really begins to shine.
Doesn't matter if it's a spreadsheet a presentation a document doesn't matter.
Being able to communicate from any point on the planet back and forth in real time is a tremendous asset.