Greetings My name is Andy Anderson and I'm going to share with you the secret to my success.
Now if you've taken any of my courses with infinite skills you might know me is like the Photoshop dude
or Illustrator graphics art design animation things like that.
That's what I do.
But the secret to my success to keep me organized is a series and set of programs that we're going to
talk about called Google Apps for business.
Now my wife Bonny is just convinced that she keeps me organized and she's probably right about that.
But another side of my organization is Google Apps for business so what are we going to do.
Well we're going to start from scratch.
Tell you how to set it up but what are they.
Well you have things like presentations documents spreadsheets forms all kinds of things.
Now let me throw another name into the mix here if you'll let me.
Microsoft Word PowerPoint Excel if you know those programs you have a leg up on learning Google Apps
for business and your response might be well OK and then why do I need Google Apps for business.
I've got Excel.
I don't need to learn another spreadsheet program.
Google Apps for business is amazing.
Now we are going to handle it as if we are the administrators.
In other words setting up users and accounts and all that kind of stuff.
I want to tell you something.
Any time any place anywhere.
I have a problem I'm working on a spreadsheet is going I don't know spreadsheets I'm not a spreadsheet
guy but Bonnies a spreadsheet gal.
So I tell you what she's in London and I'm in Wichita Kansas.
Doesn't matter.
We share the document.
We're both looking at the same document.
I see changes she makes.
She sees the changes that I make.
Total organization.
That's with Google Apps for business is and I'm about out of breath.
So let's go ahead and get started.
What do you say.