Data transfer over networks.
So when we transfer data over networks,
we have to have a way to tell it where it's going to go.
Now we use IP addresses to get you to the system,
but how does it know what
application is listening on that system?
Well, that's where a port comes in,
and ports are going to be numbered
from zero all the way up to 65,536.
That's a lot of ports,
so even though you only have one IP on our machine,
you can have over 65,000 different openings
for you to be able to run services on.
Now, we break these up into two buckets.
The first is called the well-known and reserved ports.
These are ports from zero through 1024.
These might be things like file transfer protocol
on port 21, web browsing on port 80, and things like that.
Ephemeral ports, on the other hand,
are short-lived temporary ports
that are open for a short time from this predefined range,
and these ports can be things
from 1025 all the way up to 65,536.
For example, as I'm recording this lecture,
I record the audio on my iPad.
The iPad then acts as a file server
and picks a random port around 60,000ish,
and my web browser on my laptop
can then access that and download the audio file.
That is opened just as long as I download the file
and then it closes again, just that quickly.
Now, data transfer occurs using
these IP addresses and these ports,
so what does this look like in the real world?
Well, as you can see here,
I have a client on the left and a website on the right.
The client is at the address 192.168.1.24.
The website is at 64.82.46.21,
so from the client to make a request to the website,
it's going to come from the source IP,
that 192 address, and a port, just a random port
it's going to pick in those ephemeral ports.
In this case, it chose 49,163.
It's going to send it to the destination of the website,
which is that 64 dot-dot-dot address
on the web server which is at Destination IP.
What port does it go to?
The default one for websites, which is port 80.
Now, the website on the other hand, is going to reverse that
and go from its source, and its port 80,
back to the client on its random high port, 49,163.
So you can see how this communication will happen
to establish the session and communicate over that port.
Whenever we're done transmitting this website,
that random high port that was opened on your client,
it's closed and another random one will be opened,
but port 80 will always be sitting there on that web server
ready to serve requests from
anybody else who wants a website.
Now IP version four packets are going to consist of
the source address, that IP of the sender,
a destination address, the IP of the receiver,
the IP flags, which will allow
packet fragmentation and other special things,
and the protocol, is it going to be using TCP or UDP.
All of those things will go to make up this packet header,
and you can see it here shown on the screen in blue.
Do you have to memorize this packet header?
No, no, no, no, no, don't worry about it,
but do understand that your header is what's going to contain
your source and destination, as well as the port,
the protocol, and things of that nature,
so your packets know where to be routed to.
Now back when we talked about TCP and UDP,
we talked about the fact that TCP had a lot more overhead.
Now, what does that really look like?
Well, that's what I have here on the screen.
Up top, we have the TCP header, which is 20 bytes in length,
and you can see it contains things like the source port,
the destination port, the sequence number,
the acknowledgement number, and then a bunch of other flags.
All of that with the checksum and the pointers,
it all adds to this overall length,
making it a pretty bulky protocol.
Now compare that with UDP at the bottom.
It only has four pieces of information,
the source port, the destination port,
the length of the packet, and the checksum.
That's it, and it's only eight bytes long,
so you can see that there's less of the data there in UDP
because there's less that needs to be contained,
and so it allows us to have
a faster, more efficient protocol.