The TCP/IP model.
Now, if you remember all the way back
when we did the OSI model overview,
I mentioned that the OSI model was a reference model.
But it wasn't the only reference model out there.
The other big one that we're going to talk about here
for Network Plus is the TCP/IP model.
This is also known as the TCP/IP stack or the DoD model.
Now, this is an alternative to the OSI model,
and the nice thing is, it's only four layers.
So it's a little bit easier for
most people to understand and learn.
It is actually more relevant than the OSI model
because today's networks are all TCP/IP based,
and the TCP/IP model refers to it specifically
in its four layers, where the OSI model,
sometimes things get a little bit more blurred.
So how does the OSI model compare to the TCP/IP model?
Well, it's actually pretty simple.
If I take layers five, six, and seven,
the top three layers, and merge them all together,
I get the application layer.
So application, presentation, and session,
all of those functions occur under application
in the TCP/IP model.
Transport gets carried right over.
Network gets carried right over,
but we call it Internet instead of network
because it is really all about routing
to external networks, or Internets.
And then the final two is the bottom two layers,
which is data link and physical,
which is all about your internal network.
And so we call that network interface,
which is how you, the user, interfaces with the network.
So that's how it is.
It's pretty simple when you start looking at it that way.
Take the top three, squish 'em together.
Take the bottom two, squish them together.
And that's how you get the four layers of your TCP/IP model.
Now for the exam, you do need to understand the TCP/IP model
and so, if you can draw this diagram,
you're going to be covered there as you go through the test.
The network interface layer, layer one,
is all about physical and electrical characteristics,
just like in the OSI model.
It's going to describe how to transmit
bits across the networks, those ones and zeros
that we had in the physical layer,
and it's going to determine how the network medium
is going to be used, whether it's going to be coax,
optical fiber, or twisted-pair copper cabling.
This would be things like ethernet,
token ring, fiber distribution networks, or RS-232.
All of that gets put together inside of network interface.
Now layer two here is the Internet layer.
This is where we take data and package it into IP datagrams,
like we did at layer three of the OSI model.
It's going to contain your source and destination IPs and
forward those datagrams between hosts across the network.
These datagrams are going to be pushed around the networks
through routing, and this connectivity
is going to occur externally.
This is where your Internet gets connected to your Internet,
internal versus external.
Examples of this are going to be IP, ICMP,
ARP, and reverse ARP.
And we will talk about all of those
as we go through switching and routing
in the next section of this course.
Layer three here is going to be the transport layer,
and it's exactly the same as transport in OSI.
It gives you communication session management
between hosts, and it's going to define the level of service
and the status of the connection used
using TCP, UDP or RTP, the real-time protocol,
which is used for voice and video.
Application, or layer four, is going to combine
the top three layers of the OSI model,
and it's going to define the application protocols being used.
It's going to tell you how the programs are going to interface
with the transport layer, and it's going to be the layer
where the user is going to interact with.
Now, examples of this come from layers five, six, and seven
of the OSI model again, right,
because we squished those down.
This would be things like hypertext transfer protocol
for web browsing, TELNET for remote control,
FTP, or file transfer protocol, for file-sharing,
SNMP for network management,
DNS for domain name resolution,
SMTP for sending mail,
SSL and TLS for secure web browsing and encryption.
All of these things are going to be found here
in layer four, the application layer.