Welcome back glad you're still with me because we're just getting started.
This chapter is about controlling your Gmail inbox.
So we're going to talk about creating and formatting a gmail account.
Got to start there.
We're going to work with G-mail conversations which are kind of interesting.
We'll add attachments if you've ever worked in an e-mail program I think you know how to do that.
We're going to organize with stars and labels.
You have to be able to find stuff will perform searches in G-mail and we'll work with filters and rules.
You've got to have rules around here or there is chaos all that.
And as they say more in this chapter.