Let's go ahead and sign back into G-mail if you're not already there we're going to be here for a while.
I want to talk about something called conversations.
Now you will notice up here I've got me and Bonnie in the number four.
That's actually what is called a conversation.
We went back and forth to test our MX records and see name connections into Network Solutions just to
make sure they were going to work.
So it's a conversation where I sent her a message she replied to the message back and forth we go.
This can be as many people as you want it to be.
If we click on it it will open it up.
So this is a test test shows fine.
One more check check with I-T all things or go back and forth conversation.
Now if she is in her office on an almost like real time chat now over here you have a button to expand.
All of them if you want to read them.
If not you can click on them one at a time and read them that way.
This button allows me to print conversation and this one allows me to view it within a new window.
Now if I come in here and reply that becomes a new part of this conversation and the reason I want to
show you this I think it is a good feature.
I do like it.
Let's go back to inbox right over here.
But not all people do like it.
So can you turn it off.
The answer to that is yes.
If we come over here to our gear which is for settings and go into settings right here now it probably
did default to the general settings up here if it didn't go ahead and click that tab.
If you don't like conversations which you can do is come down here and you'll see conversation view
and you can turn it off.
Now there is a lot of stuff here in settings but if you make any changes don't forget you have to come
all the way down here and click save changes and you will notice it's now split up.
If I do click on them just like any other system it will show me replies.
But it splits them apart.
When you get into the inbox itself I do prefer conversations.
I do like them.
But if you don't it's an easy matter just turn them off.
Conversations help organize.
That's all they do.