If you're not in your Gmail go ahead and get there we're going to be spending some time here.
What I want to talk about further is how we organize ourselves.
I agree that we only have a few things but e-mail Gmail whatever you want to call it can get away from
you very fast.
By Apple Mail System has tens of thousands of messages in it.
They're not all just stuck here like this.
I've labeled them.
I've started that I've given them certain priorities certain key words.
Let's talk a little bit about this now.
One of my items is important.
Just one right here.
If I click on any one of these I can market just with a click as important I can filter it by clicking
right over here very easy.
Let's go back to inbox.
We can control what goes on over here.
Go over to our settings button and click Settings go into labels.
Now you can see we've got all these different labels over here.
We have inbox star important.
Some are showing and some are hidden.
If we for example want spam we click right here and now it's over here.
And if we had any spam we could click that button over there and we'd see just our spam.
Let's go ahead hide that one again.
If we come further down we can create our very own labels if you will and then use them over on the
left to further filter out what we're doing.
So we can even create our own it's out here for many.
Another thing that we can do besides just putting these things over here so that we can filter and see
what we've got is actually changing what they are over here.
So if I come in and select Google Apps team right here I can then go on and you can choose as many as
you want.
I come over here and sign it a label or I can create a new one right now or I can manage labels which
will take us back to where we just were.
This one is labeled as a promotion and an update which is what they are exactly.
Now to get back out of here for a second.
You say well promotion and update aren't here.
So we can go back in and actually get those and you're correct.
But if you click more right here you'll notice promotions and updates are right here too.
And like a temporary pulled on menu system if you want to use it get back up here.
So we have labels we can create our own labels like he could have a label called business or one of
a kind productions or something like that.
Bonnie I don't have anything I want and then I could put them over here so I could get to them quickly.
We have another thing called a star.
This right here.
And if I click right there I've added a yellow star to that particular G-man.
What does that mean.
Well it can mean anything you want it to mean obviously a star could mean it needs to be worked up.
It's a work in progress.
But if we go over to our settings again and go into settings here and go into general come down here
and look at all the different kinds of stars that you can use.
Now right now we only have a yellow star.
We can do four stars.
Or we can say all you say well I don't want these for I don't want just one.
And I don't want all of that.
You can do this.
Let's go back to one star for a second.
I want this one right here which is called a red bang.
Interesting.
And I can drag it up now and put it in any order that I want and maybe I want the purple or the blue
star appear.
In other words not only can you drag them up here and if I could do that again but I can decide the
order that they're used in.
So if we've done this don't forget you got to come down here and you've got to say save changes.
If we now come in here and click on one of these it goes through the order of the way we place them
so we can cycle through them.
The cool thing here and we're going to do this in the next lesson is how we can then focus in in search
for this kind of thing.
Now let's do this to remember our conversation up here.
If I open that up I have the ability to come over here and say Well that particular part of the conversation
was important.
That's right bang this one over here is not a red bang it's going to be a Blue Star.
This one wasn't important at all.
So you can even put them together like this.
If we then come over here and say inbox and we click on start it will list not only the ones that we
started here but even the ones on the inside of the conversation that Bonnie and I had stars labels
important are always not the only ones for sure but always to help you organize a huge amount of mail.
Inside Google Apps.