In my opinion there are two hurdles you need to go through.
The first hurdle.
We've already done and that is the domain in waiting around patiently for the verification of the domain.
That's the first hurdle to jump.
The second one to me is setting up the G-mail account.
Once you do that you basically then begin reaping the benefits of working with Google Apps So let's
go ahead and set up a gmail account.
If you are in Crome that's fine.
If you're an explorer or Safari that's fine too but I've mentioned this before I'll just say one more
time quickly.
You should try out Google Chrome when you're working with Google maps because there are some advantages.
I'm going to come up here and type in Gmail.
I've already done it once or remembers it.
G mail dot com.
And go ahead and enter.
But this time don't sign into our account could.
But we're not going there.
Incidentally if you're using Safari or explorer this does look a little bit different but you will find
a button that says Create an account.
That's what we want.
Let's go ahead and create a Gmail account for my wife.
Do believe I remember her name.
Now here's the fun part.
This is a generic gmail account.
There's probably 50 billion of these things out there and if you think you've got a name that nobody
else has you might take a while getting one.
I want to tell you so if I type in Bonnie I know for sure.
Bonnie has been taken.
So I'm not even going to bother trying to test that one but I'm thinking OK how about if I add something
in here like maybe the first three digits of her phone number or maybe part of our address.
So I'm going to type in 4:58 not press tab key.
I don't believe it.
Somebody has that one.
Oh goody.
We got to try again.
Let me get in here and type in Bonnie Lloyd.
Now the problem with me about playing this game with all these people that already have all the good
names is finding one that you can live with and you can remember.
So parts of phone numbers and that to me really can help you out here.
Let's try this one.
Cross your fingers.
That one we got Bonnie Lloyd 2 5 9 created password confirmed her birthday.
It is the 20th
gender is female of course.
Mobile phone
current e-mail address.
Now prove that you're not a robot.
If I come in here I can skip the verification.
Now if I do I'm probably going to have to verify through the phone.
I think I can get this one.
I hate these things but I think I can get this one.
It says 5 8 3.
And when you use a space probably don't have to use that space.
And this one's pretty easy.
I've seen some that are pretty difficult.
Sixty three sixty nine 5 3 3 6.
If you can't read this one you can click here and get a different one.
I am in the United States.
I have to agree to a policy of course and then go next to.
Now depending on what you're doing you may have to do this part.
Now the phone number is where you are going to receive it and you want it as a text message.
Some phones don't do text messages but most do.
Or do you want it as a voice call and text message.
Now this could take a couple of minutes.
Hopefully it won't.
But we'll try this now tells me it can take up to 15 minutes.
So what we're going to do here is kind of pause it until I get it and then we'll come back OK.
That actually didn't take very long at all.
And I'm going to come up here and let's go ahead and type it in.
It's 8 4 1 6 3 9.
Of course the code is going to be different for you.
And if you try to enter it in a couple of times and it doesn't work it's going to invalidate it you're
going to have to do it all over again.
Let's click continue.
Welcome Bonnie.
Your new e-mail address is Bonnie Loide to 5:9 at gmail dot com.
Continue to G-mail.
Now you've got a little congratulations thing going on here.
You want to learn more.
Go to the help center must go ahead just close out of there.
No I don't want to take a tour again but thanks for asking.
OK.
You're going to have a couple of basic e-mails.
We're going to get more into this in this chapter but we've successfully set up a gmail account and
we now have access.