In this lesson and the next lesson we have to more kind of techie things we have to do that are very
important to setting up G-mail.
But the good news is once that's done we get to concentrate on doing email on doing spreadsheets on
doing presentations on working with our calendar.
So let's sign into our admin Council now you're going to notice something different about mine.
It now says Down here it's a set of billing.
It doesn't say set up G-mail does.
I've already done it.
And the reason I did is because it takes about five hours to kind of propagate it and get it working.
I'm going to show you how I did it.
But this way we can kind of move on.
So it's set up billing ignore that.
What I want to do is talk about two things.
One in this Lotzen And that's changing names to make access easier.
And then in the next lesson actually setting up the Gmail itself.
Now you can still get to the information to set up G-mail even if it's set up billing up here.
So even if it says set up Gmail ignore that one.
I want you to come over here to Google Apps.
Go into Gmail here and go into user settings.
Now you're going to notice here I can access Gmail and my users can at mail dot Google dot com forward
slash a forward slash real anti dot com and you go whoa I wish it was easier to change.
You are all right here.
Now over here you will notice.
There it is.
But we also have mail at real Andy dotcom.
That's a lot easier.
Problem is not problem does something you have to do if you select it what you are going to have to
do is go into the admin council or your host do you have that kind of access.
Now if you work in a large company I would suggest if you have an I.T. department that we know about
this kind of stuff you just tell them you need to do what they're going to do it for you but you need
to create a C name record right here.
So if we say save changes it's going to give us some general information on how to do that.
But the problem is there are hundreds and hundreds of service and hosting providers.
I've got three myself.
There's one in Australia and two in the United States.
I'm adding the same scene name record but to get to it it's going to be a little bit different now I'll
show it to you right here.
I do have my account manager set up and you can say I've gone in and I've drilled in to my host and
they're seen records.
I would add it here.
If you have an I.T. department like I mentioned before they can do this for you but I want to warn you
of something if you do it incorrectly.
If you make a mistake you run the chance of blowing out your entire e-mail system until it gets fixed
again.
So if you're not comfortable with this part.
I mean we're concentrating on Google Apps but I don't want to leave this out.
I wanted to show it to you if you're not sure if you don't really know how to do it.
See if you can get somebody to do it for you.
Call up your Hulst.
These people that you're paying a monthly fee to.
They know how to do it.
Say I've got to do this I'm working with Google Apps for business.
I need to change the name record.
How do I do that.
Chances are they'll do it for you.
Just remember if you've got to do that this is the way you have to do it.
It's not just in Google Apps.
I'm going to go well you know what I think I'll do this later.
And it takes it right back to the way it was.
But if you want to simplify the names you can you can do it for G-mail calendar drive and sites.