One more thing to set this up go into Google Apps even if it says Gmail over here.
Go into Google.
I want to show you something in Google Apps.
Go to G-mail and go and use acetic in order to set up Google Apps and Gmail.
We have to go back into the admin Council on our hosting server which is like a software program like
Microsoft Word or Word Perfect skin look different.
You're going to get to things differently.
And we need to add this stuff right down here.
Let me show you something about this stuff.
Notice at the end of each one of these is a full stop period.
You have to type this stuff in exactly the way you see it here.
So my suggestion would be this copy and paste it again you're going to have to get into the admin account
so on your system and it gives you instructions here.
Same way it did previously when we talked in the last lesson on how to get to that point.
Let me show you what it looks like at least in Network Solutions.
There it is.
Now if you look at the names here.
Those are the same names.
Copy paste it over here.
The priority is how it sorts through which one gets first what's up.
TTL stands for time to live.
Sounds like a James Bond movie doesn't it.
It's also called the hop limit.
It's a mechanism that limits the lifespan of the data not seconds.
Now what I did is cut it in half because the default at 72 72 is two hours.
Why did I do that.
Well for me it's a couple of things.
It's caching in holding the data longer than it's needed and it's also something for security without
a TTL telling it that the information expired.
It's possible your data could be floating around on the Internet and packets for eternity.
So we use the TTL feature to limit that.
You can go up to I think something like a day which is about 86000 seconds.
Up to you what you want to do here.
The default will take you to 72.
I decided based on some research I did with Google about this is that I could take it down to 36.
It helps with caching the data and I think it also helps with security.
So you're going to have to one more time or get somebody else to do it for you.
Take this information it's right there for you and yours will be different.
It'll look different and put it into something that in a sense has nothing to do with Google Apps for
business.
You're hosting or service provider continue in say that basically when you come back when you go to
here and then we go back into our council you will see a little spinning globe right up here and mine
spun for like about five hours before it finally stopped.
Now we can set up billing next if you want to do that that's fine.
It's setting up it last for your credit card et cetera et cetera.
We're not going to do that.
I'm still on a free business trial so I'm not going to worry about Bill.
And you can ignore that up until the very last minute.
But understand something.
If on the last day when it expires if you don't have billing set up they will suspend your account until
you do set it up.
That's about it for setting up G-mail.
But don't forget if you don't do it correctly it can mess up your entire site and your e-mail system
until it's corrected.
So make sure you kind of know what you're doing here.
And let's move on.