To start out this chapter and let's go into our admin console we can do it up here type in a and it
will remember the last thing I did.
So admin that Google doc come in if it asks you to sign in please do.
I've already signed in once and it remembers me.
Want to talk about some of the things that we can do to kind of control the overall settings and permissions
and things like that that go on inside of Google Apps for business.
Let's start out here by going into Google Apps now in Google Apps.
Here's all our services and we can come over here for example and click on one tic that Mark come up
here in either turn down or turn it off.
Let's just do this let's go into G-mail.
Let's start there in G-mail we can see we have eight people active users in the last seven days.
If I come over here I can also turn it off.
It is possible that you might want to because of security reasons do something like turn it off.
So you do have an option for that.
Let's look at a couple of things inside of here.
We have all these different settings in areas that we can go into we can get into authentication default
routing hosting the labs you go in here and turn off the labs if you don't want people to have access
to them.
You can even get into advanced lab management where you manage the labs individually.
Let's go into email addresses for a second.
Now here are all your e-mail addresses that you have set up the user accounts.
We've been here before.
We can also get in here and start creating groups like our Star Fire group that we talked about earlier.
If I come over to one of these say for example and click on it it does give me access to money I can
come over here at a photograph.
I can actually suspend or delete her but I don't think I want to do that to my wife.
She has six Google Apps enabled.
And here they are.
She is a member of one group family.
She has one license user assigned and you can come down here and say show more security settings she
has no admin role but I could give them to her.
No device is assigned like mobile devices and she does have 65 Google services enabled all this fun
stuff right here.
And one market place app that we got earlier in the story called mind meister.
Let's go ahead and go back over to users and click this little button right here.
Let's go back into Google Apps and go back into G-mail.
The one area I want to talk about here because it has most of the settings is right here.
And as the administrator it is well it's your responsibility to set this up.
First thing we can change the you are well if we want to current one is kind of complicated.
We could do something as easy as mail real Andy dot if we wanted to this area down here is showing you
your MX records.
We talked about this earlier.
In my opinion the hardest part about using Google Apps for business is not creating spreadsheet.
It's not making a presentation or a document.
It's setting up Google Apps with all of this kind of stuff.
If you're not used to doing it so you can get started doing all that.
So it's got all the stuff here for you.
Shows you your Google and MX records if you haven't done this yet.
Down here we have user e-mail uploads.
You can allow users to upload mail using email migration.
And if you turn that on you can also allow them to import from things like Yahoo Hotmail AOL.
The one thing about this I would say is now we're talking security issues in a sense because the more
access you give people the more potential there is for something happening that you don't want to happen.
You can totally uninstalled the service right here.
You can let the users choose their own themes which studies show that if you allow a user even things
as simple as choosing a background color they are going to be more efficient because they feel like
they're more controlled There's nothing wrong with that.
I leave that on unless I'm a dictator.
Do you not want e-mail read receipts sent or allow them as well as if you want to the following email
addresses separate them by a comma it's go down a little bit further here you've got name format I like
first to last but I also allow my users to customize their own settings.
Now you've got an app search right here that's a locally applied option and that extends the capabilities
of Google Docs and searching down here you can disable pop and I met you can get into BlackBerry support.
These are pretty straightforward kind of questions.
In a sense what do you want to allow and what don't you want to allow.
On a global basis.
This one I like online Gmail it allows my users to be productive even if they don't have access to the
cloud.
And we've got information on gateways here and it's good on a little bit further and get into spam.
Now you have something called the white list and those are trusted sites.
They should not be marked to spam.
If you are using some gateways for your e-mail if you enter them in here it will improve spam handling.
Now here on spam it's not configured yet.
I can configure over here create approved senders list.
Now this bypasses the spam filter so you want to be very careful about who you put in the approved list.
You can always come back later and take them out.
You do have a blocked one here.
If we go a little bit further down automatically delete e-mails for all users when Now right now nothing
is deleted.
It's up to you to decide if you want this to happen.
And if some messages have a particular label don't delete them.
Another one here I like is a pen footer and what that does if we selected it allows me to put together
a footer like maybe a legal notice that will appear on all of the e-mails and once you do it here it
spread and populated throughout the system.
Now you can also restrict the domains that your users are allowed to exchange email with.
You can also configure content filters based on words phrases or patterns and objectionable content.
Particular word lists.
Now we all know certain words I won't say them that I think we would all find objectionable.
And you can actually create a list.
Let me show you.
You can decide which messages to effect.
You can add a word list right here and then decide what you want to do if those words are found.
Coming down a little bit more.
We have routeing we have something called a catch all address for particular routing but it's only used
if you really need it because spammers do this.
They will try real Andy dotcom and they have programs that just put in all kinds of names.
So if it's not there if that account isn't there route them to a catchall address.
But the problem with that is is if you get a lot of those it could block up your system.
The best thing to do would be just discard them.
In my opinion you do have the ability to work with Microsoft Exchange even outlook for that matter and
you can configure that information right here if you've made changes and you want to save those changes.
Click here if you don't want to start all over again.
You can say discard but working with G-mail settings just fine tunes the experience for all of your
users.
That's what it's designed to do but it is up to you to set it up.