In the previous two chapters we've been playing around with G-mail.
I mean we got our POP or IMAP server set up.
We've got all this stuff ready to go.
We've got e-mails coming in to our inbox.
Now what I don't want my inbox to be is something that's clogged with like 20000 e-mails.
Oh yeah I can come over here and I can say important or I can store them and click over here and say
oh there they are.
What I need is a way to organize it.
Now we've already done this but let's go over it again.
I've got two new messages from Bonnie right over here these two.
Now I've got one from James and that's on a Sunday fishing trip.
Now if you remember we created a rule that said any time I get something from James it goes into family
and it goes into James right there.
So that's already been moved over here.
But if you don't have a rule for everything.
Well then you have to kind of do some of this stuff manually and that's not that bad.
Let's do this let's go back to settings for a second.
Actually more than a second and go into labels.
Go down the labels here and create a new label.
We'll call this one Bonnie and we're going to nest one of them underneath family.
And the reason being is she does occasionally send me emails that are not business related and I'm going
to create.
Let's do another right here.
Great new label.
This one's going to be business.
We're not nesting it re new label again.
This one will be Bonnie.
This one we're nesting under business.
Let's do one more infinite skills.
The people that are bringing you this training in I will mess that one underneath.
Yes what business.
What I'm doing is setting up a structure here that I can work with to organize my stuff so I don't have
10000 messages sitting there in my inbox.
So let's do this let's come out of here.
Go back to our inbox now since I don't have rules set up.
I only have one for James.
I want to move these two I've read them you're on office supplies and equipment testing.
But I want to keep them I don't want to delete them.
I could I could delete them but if I come over here and select both of them.
I can then go to this auction right here and move to what business Bonnie and I could create one for
this G-mail if I wanted to I can have as many of those as I want if at any time I want to get back to
those messages.
All I have to do is come over here and Salon.
This is organization and this is something you really really really have to do.
Otherwise your inbox is going to become totally unmanageable.
Now we're not done with G-mail but we're done just talking about G-mail.
Let's move on.