Open up your G-mail and take a good look at what you have I'm talking about the interface are OK.
What we see how it translates to us if you don't like it you can change it.
Now here is my take on going too crazy with the interface.
This to me is primarily a business tool.
It is called Google Apps for business.
If I make it too much like fun I don't think I want to work anymore and I want something else.
But with that said Go up to your gear right here and go into settings in settings go into themes.
You've got all kinds of things here.
Mr. McCann like wasabi.
You can get a little bit more crazy as you go down the thing.
Now notice some of them have that dog ear down here.
This one for example has a clock.
Now check this out.
If I click it it's going to ask where I live in the city that I live in and believe it or not the image
will change based on the time of day.
We'll give you a sunset image in the evenings and a nice bright sunny one during the day.
It changes based on time and location.
It's kind of interesting.
We can customize our themes.
Bring in your own photos if you want to.
And we do have some classic themes down here.
The one I would use might be high contrast that one does make it look a little bit easier to work with.
But I'm going to go back to default over here not just because I'm boring which I think I am is so we're
all kind of on the same page.
But please feel free to change this if you want to go back to my inbox.
That's going to say I changed things because I did move around.
I would say OK we're back to the same old boring look.
Now here's another thing that I want to show you these buttons up here the way they look.
They're icons.
And it might be easier to tell what they are if they were words and not icons.
So if we come over here let's go into here and go into settings again.
If we scroll down in general make sure you're in general in default you usually are
button labels.
Do you want icons or do you want text.
It's up to you.
Let's go and change that to text.
And while we're here we've got time for this.
How about putting in a photograph.
And if you didn't do that well you can do it right here.
Select a picture that everyone will see when you e-mail that.
Sounds exciting.
Is it on your computer or you don't want any.
I'm going to choose a file.
I've got to over here that I might use.
One is me in the Test Kitchen and one is probably better for what I'm doing looks a little bit more
like I'm studious.
I'm going to use that one.
Now you can use Peggs and piano keys and just they don't want you using anything that has nudity in
it.
And I think I'm fully clothed there and I'm going to go ahead and bring that out.
And you could say something about like that and apply the changes.
Now I have my own little photograph.
Don't forget to come down here and save the changes.
Now check this out.
If I select this they're all words.
Now not icons though it changes fundamentally how we look at the buttons.
We can change the background if we just happen to be bored.
And I have my own little photograph right here every time I e-mail somebody.
Not too bad for a day's work.