Anytime you compose a G-mail basically there's a subject who you're sending it to CCCC the body and
then a signature isn't it.
We're talking about signatures.
A signature could be.
Regards Cheerz whatever your name.
Maybe some information about company maybe even a phone number or something down at the bottom.
Even an image.
But I don't really want to do that every time I compose a message.
So Google gives us the ability in Gmail to create our own permanent signature if you will.
Let's do that.
Let's go up to this button right here and go down to settings.
Now you should be on General.
Go down down down down and eventually you will see signature right here.
Now of course by default there is no let's go ahead and click here and let's make a signature.
Come back up again and do this
whatever you want to put down the that's a good phone number.
Now you of course have the ability here to reformat it.
You can add a link if you want to maybe to your Web site you can add an image if you want to it's up
to you.
You can insert this signature before quoted text in replies.
That's in reply and remove that line that precedes it.
That's an option if you want to choose.
I like what I've got here I think I'm OK.
So let's go ahead and come down here.
Don't forget you have to save the changes if we now go over to compose something.
Well there it is.
Now it's not really that big of a deal I understand that but it's something that can save you some time
when you're composing your messages to have one standardized signature.
And don't forget you can add links and you can add images if you want.