If you ever had the occasion to set up an email client or app you probably have come across the term
POP and IMAP.
If you are not quite sure what those terms stand for and how each one affects your email account let's
talk about that.
I map stands for Internet messages Access Protocol and pop stands for Post Office protocol.
In other words both our e-mail protocols they allow you to do things like read emails locally using
third party applications like Outlook Thunderbird Fedora Mac mail that kind of thing to set them up
in Gmail is very easy.
Let's go up to our settings button right here.
Go into forwarding and pop I'm at but besides pop in IMAP setup you can also if you want to set up a
forwarding address but I go by what kind of Google recommends here.
And I actually create a filter to make that happen.
Let's talk about pop First we can enable it by default it is disabled and we can enable it for all mail
or all mail that arise from this point forward to you but once you do you get the ability to decide
what happens to the message after it's been accessed with pop.
I love this part because it's very powerful.
I can come in here and say for example Mark one production's mail copy is read.
So if I'm here and I'm reading it in I've got myself set up on my Apple client.
I've got it on my iPhone whatever.
It will market read on all those devices.
That's what it's designed to do.
Keep everything in order.
Now I map is the one I prefer to be honest with you.
You do have configuration instructions here based on which particular app you're using but I'm disable
Let's turn that on.
Now when I mark a message in IMAP is deleted do you want to expunge it immediately or do you want to
wait for the client to update the server.
Now if you click here it activates this area down here.
Do you want to archive the message that's the default.
You want to move to the trash or immediately delete the message for ever your folder size limits.
Don't limit the number or limit the number.
And basically you can choose how many are in each one of those folders.
And again based on the e-mail client that you're using you have configuration instructions here on exactly
how to set that up setting up IMAP or pop allows you to bring all of your e-mail into more of an organized
sphere.
Regardless of what device you're viewing it on.