Well here we are in the admin Council.
One of the questions that gets asked a lot to me is how do you change password a user that forgot the
password and they need a new one.
So how do I get them a new password.
Actually it's pretty simple but you do have to be admin to do it.
So we're in the admin Council go over users here and you will see your users.
So let's say Bonnie forgot her password.
One of the things that we could do is just hover right there for a second.
And as you can see there's reset password.
But if you click you get more stuff tells me a little bit about what she's been up to.
There's your profile down here.
Here is her photo.
Now she doesn't have one and she can do this herself.
But if you want to add a photo Let's go out and do that.
I don't think we've done this.
Click here and select a photo.
Let's use this one right there click open.
Now I want to tell you one thing about these photos Google is very picky about them.
If it's not the right size if it's too big it's going to reject it.
But you'll see that down here and say it rejects it.
If we upload that's when you cross your fingers and there it goes.
It actually happened pretty fast.
Now this button right here means.
Get rid of the photo.
But like I said she can do this herself.
Now as to the password again that's right here you would type in the new password and retype it you'd
see the strength down there.
And I always require my users to change their password the next time they sign in for security.
She would be sent the e-mail.
There you go.
But we're not done.
Let's get out here.
Let's go back.
To our console and go down to more controls right here.
Just click that and go into security.
Password monitoring.
Now if I select that it shows me all my users and their password strength green is good.
It's down to red.
It's bad.
It gives me their password length.
And if Google considers it a good password.
So after they've redone their password I can come here and go where they do type in one two three four
five.
That's not a good password.
I don't see the password but I know it's strength.
Now if you go into basic settings here you can assign a minimum and maximum length.
Now those are the defaults 8 to 100.
And I'd just love to see somebody who typed in a 100 character password I'd be kind of fun.
So you can control that right here in security inside the admin Council.
So if somebody forgets their passwords.
Not really that big of a deal.
It's very easy to reset and you move on.
And here you can even control what kind of passwords they can put in.