Here we are in the admin Council.
Go ahead get there if you're not.
Let's look at some of the options we have for our company profile right over here.
Now in profile Let's start actually with personalization if you want to you can have your own custom
logo as you can see.
I do have one real Andy and there's fearless leader.
The defaults are up here.
Now how did I get this one.
Well I selected here obviously and then I came down to choose the file here and chose it.
And then I uploaded it understand Google is like really picky about this thing.
It has to be a P G which I prefer or a jiff and it needs to be scaled to 143 pixels by 59.
If it isn't it's going to look really bad and don't include any google trademarks.
So if you want to customize Google Apps for business this would be one thing that you could do and show
this logo in all sites that users create of course save our changes here.
Close this out.
If we come to communication preferences what do you want do you want performance suggestions and updates
feature announcements offers from Google feedback and testing.
These are all on by default you can turn them off in profile.
We have things like the organization name which you can change contact information things like that.
And finally down here in Kustom you ourselves and I do like this feature we did talk about this before
to get to G-mail it's Melgar Google dot com forward slash a Ford slash real energy dot com that's the
default.
You can change that to make that real.
Andy dotcom makes life a whole lot easier doesn't it.
Let's go ahead and get out of here.
When you're working in the admin console when you're setting up Google Apps for business every single
one of your apps and services is going to have preferences and most of them are pretty straightforward
things to answer.
But in order to customize business to your particular organization and the needs of your users you're
going to need to go through these things and sort them out.
Not really a bad thing but that's why they pay you the big bucks.
You're the administrator.