I've been told that organizations and companies live on reports I think you can overreport something
and just strangle everything to death by too many reports.
However if you don't see reports right here go down to more controls and you'll see it down here.
Quick reports.
It's actually pretty cool.
Number one G-mail.
It's telling me total mail usage by six months down to one week if I want to use it.
Average male usage is going down user activity.
If we go into calendar how people are using calendar based on time and notice if you go along this thing
it will give you precise details as you move along.
I would like that feature if we go into drs and docs how drivers are being used and we can go down then
we can do this and look at the exact results on collaboration on total docs created by average number
of users that Doc is shared with Doc creator reports.
We have mobile devices if you have them set up you have an audit long for the admin Council.
I remember I changed in the previous lesson my logo changed email settings its giving me a log of everything
that I did.
You have an email that you can actually email out that log additional reports all kinds of stuff and
alerts What do you want to be alerted to when suspicious logging activity happens turn it on user suspended.
All of these different things you can turn on to be alerted if one of them occurs.
Companies may or may not live by reports but having the ability to see these reports gives you a really
good kind of like overall look at the health of your company.
Don't forget you got reports.