Another lesson series done.
So what did we learn.
Well if you would allow me let me speak to that question personally.
I was looking for something I wasn't sure what it was but I didn't want to hire people to do it for
me that would allow me to keep my two businesses working without me constantly working at the business
and not doing what I want to do and that's photography graphics art design cooking.
Those are things I love to do.
I was looking for something that would allow me to do that.
And I found it in Google Apps for business.
I now have joy in my life again because I'm actually doing those things.
I'm still running my business but now basically my communication spreadsheets all that kind of stuff
is organized through Google Apps for business and I am one happy camper.
I want to tell you now we learned a lot but we still just scratch the surface.
But I tell you what we're up and running aren't we.
You might want to be better at spreadsheets and documents and things like that.
But the more you work with this program and the more you walk down this road I think I almost guarantee
that you will have the ability to conduct and work your businesses and at the same time enjoy more time
whether that's relaxing hour by the pond or having more fun doing what you want to do.
Google apps is going to do it for you.
I promise you that.
So I'll tell you what this is Andy Anderson saying.
Keep the faith keep learning.