IT guys in this chapter we're going to continue our exploration of G-mail features.
We're going to start with working with chat and even making landline phone calls if you want to.
We're going to talk about doing video chats when you talk about what a people widget is and know what
you know what it is when we get into the chapter we're going to adjust our G-mail theme.
Think of it this way.
Studies show that if you can have an environment that you work in that you're happy you're going to
be more efficient.
So we're going to adjust our theme.
We're going to create a signature reading going to show you how you announce you're out of the office
if you want to we'll talk about setting a pop and I'm map accounts you don't have to but there we're
going to work in something called the experimental lab which allows you to add additional functionality
to G-mail based on what you do.
And then we're going to just wrap it up and talk about what we've learned in these last three chapters
all about G-mail.
We go.