Let's talk about another function of what we do here in G-mail that we know we can send emails emails
if you will to other people.
No big deal may lapse have been doing that for the last 300 years but we also have the ability to initiate
a chat of video chat and even believe it or not a phone call using a cell phone or a landline or connect
to them.
Let's talk about that.
If I click over here this is my chatting area right in here.
If I click this button right here you can see I can say I'm available.
Busy.
Invisible.
You can put in a custom message.
Today's a great day.
I'm having a lot of fun.
Let people know about it.
We can show in the chat list the most popular or all contacts we can add.
Change your picture and chat settings.
Let's talk about chat settings but let's get to it a different way.
Let's go up to our settings icon the gear and come down the settings.
This is just another way to do the same thing and go into chat.
For example is it on or off.
You can turn it off.
Do you want to automatically allow people you communicate with often chat with you in see when you're
online or only allow people you're explicitly approving enabling outbound calls disabling them.
Now I have display I sight video camera so I use that for my camera.
My microphone is the scarlet microphone and headset unit that I'm using right now and my speakers are
my display audio.
Couple of other options like echo cancellation things like that sounds on or off.
Do you want your emotional little characters like your happy faces in that to actually animate when
you use them.
If you make any changes click here.
We didn't make any.
So we're going to click Cancel.
You will notice I have Bonnie Lloyd right over here.
She is one of the users that I created.
Now how did she get down there.
If I want to add somebody to my chat I can come up here and start searching for the and I'll type in
James there is James.
Now he's never been invited.
So I have the option of inviting him to chat which he will get through his G-mail and either accept
it or reject it if he decides to accept it.
His name will then appear down here and make it easier for me to contact him.
I will see if I can get in touch with Bob.
If I click here and let's pop this out and make it easier to look at.
Not too long ago actually I did send her a message testing out the system and I said where are you.
And she said I'm in my office Sillett.
I don't know if that means she's in her office being silly or if I'm silly for asking a dumb question
but let's see if she's still there.
So you come down here does this look familiar to you Macintosh.
Windows has messaging systems.
You have skype.
Basically the same thing.
And it is free.
So how about where are you now.
Just press the enter key.
Now let's see if she responds.
Well what we can do here.
I can come up here now and I can say go off the record.
What does that mean.
None of these conversations are safe.
I can block her which might not be actually a very good thing to do to your wife.
And I can start a video chat which she refused to do.
So let's just get out of this area right here and pop this right back in well like I said before if
you've ever used Google or some of the other messaging services this is no big deal but it is all bundled
inside of G-mail in Google Apps for business.
Now there's another thing I want to show you really quick.
Let's close this out before she sends me another one of those chats.
You can make phone calls directly here with this option right here.
Again if you've ever use Skype or some of the other IP systems same idea you might have to when you
click that button load some software.
If you do it will guide you through the process.
But understand if I click this button right here I can dial a number right in here and it will call
a landline or a cell phone.
You'll notice I have a zero balance account.
Was that mean well what it means basically is I have no money in the account for the calling service.
That also means I can call the United States and Canada as that's kind of where I'm from and do it for
free.
But if I go overseas there is a charge.
It's not that much.
But there is a charge.
So you would need to set up an account to do that all inside of Gmail.
This is not just for sending GI or e-mails.
This is a whole lot more powerful than that.