We can do a text chat.
We can even make the phone call.
We know how to do that.
How about a video chat.
Don't forget one thing that if you are working on phone calls text or video chats you will have to install
some software but it runs through the process.
Painless no big deal.
Let's say I want to do a video chat with Bonnie.
Now that's not really that practical because she's about 100 feet away from me in another room.
But let's say she's in another part of the country.
I want to get together with her and maybe even some other people.
You can have more than one person on a video chat.
There's a couple of ways we could maybe pull this off.
If I come over here I've got a write down here.
Now if you don't see the person you're on here just click up here and search.
I come over here and I hover over and get Barney Lloyd and I can chat right now.
But you know what this conference is going to be tomorrow.
And so I click here to send her an e-mail.
And then the e-mail subject might be something like video conference video chat and the body would say
we need to meet video chat.
9:00 a.m. tomorrow.
The cool thing about this when we get a calendar if you get a message that basically has a date and
or time in it and you click on the date or time it actually automatically puts it into your calendar
and will alert you.
I love that feature.
I don't have to do that.
I know she's waiting for this.
So let's go ahead and do this.
Let's come back over again.
Come over and click this little button right ear.
You're going to see me over in the lower right.
This is me and I have to now invite her.
That's kind of like making a phone call.
So let me go ahead and do the invite.
Now I hope she really is there.
That's calling her.
Now you can even do things up here like turn off your camera.
So there she is.
Let me go ahead and turn my camera back on again.
You know what the thing is here.
My wife is the only person I know that has a dryer sense of humor than I do and that's scary.
I didn't think she actually would be there trying to figure out what she was going to do.
That's a ceramic rabbit playing a French horn.
I see why she put the candle in front of it so you can really tell this is a video in that photograph
if the big if she was really there we could now be carrying on a conversation.
Also look up here get besides turning off my video if I don't want that I can mute my microphone if
I want to say something maybe to somebody else.
I don't want that person to hear it.
You have a button right over here for adjusting bandwidth usage.
Now you could have problems hopefully it won't but you could even disable HD if you have to get the
video working the way you want it to.
You have settings here of course it's for your display your microphone and your applet and you can play
Tests sound if you want to if you're having a problem.
And finally over here because I feel like I think I need to do this now I'm going to hang up on her
just like that.
Video chats are nice.
Course you have to be well-dressed I guess for a video chat.
Video chats are nice because you can actually when you get to see the person and sometimes it's a little
bit more personal than just a text message.