What I want to talk about in this lesson is something I think is really kind of neat.
It's called The People which it it's kind of a way to get know somebody before you take the relationship
to the next level of the people which can be found in a couple of places for example if I open up this
conversation with Don her people which it appears over here now if I don't have anything necessarily
open let's go back.
Inbox Your But I do have Bonnie down here and I could have other people down there too if I hover.
I get people which are down there.
Now she does it a photograph I'm going to show you how you do add those.
It's got some information that tells me who she is.
It's got her gmail address number one.
Now if I click either here or here I get into an area that allows me to add her if I want to do this
and something in Google Plus called circles.
Let me go ahead and get out there.
If I come back down again.
Down here you have contact information.
And if I click and select that I get contact information about Bonnie Lloyd.
But the cool thing about this is this is information I can change because it's my people which is in
my Gmail account.
I mean I can come over here she is my spouse or actually I'm her spouse I guess work all these things
I can change add notes over here.
This is my information about Bonnie Lloyd.
Let's go ahead and go back over here.
I'm back down here again at the bottom.
We also have e-mails now this to me is going to be more important to you when you have G-mail just populated
with all kinds of stuff.
And you say where are my active e-mails with Bonnie.
If I click here it will find them for me.
Well there they are.
Let's go back over here again.
You also have the choice of doing a video chat or a regular chat or sending an e-mail.
Now if you click this button right here you have the ability in the chat list to always show auto.
Never show or block the people which is basically a way.
Like I said for you to get to know somebody better add information into the contact info to help you
better understand who this person is.