Believe it or not there are people according to studies that are so hung up on things like email that
they literally check to see if somebody has sent them a message every five to eight minutes.
I would call that obsessive compulsive.
There are times when I don't want to check e-mail but if I'm in my business I'm kind of obligated to
do that.
But what if you're taking a week off to do something maybe it's a business trip and you want to be courteous
to the people that are sending you e-mails who think you're ignoring them by giving them something.
We have all seen.
Hi I'm out of the office I'll be back on.
And when I get back I'll respond to your e-mail kind of message.
Very easy to set up.
Go into G-mail of course go up to our gear and go into settings.
We've been spending a lot of time in settings and that's fine.
It should default to the general down down down until you get to vacation responder It doesn't necessarily
have to be a vacation.
It could be a business trip but we'll go ahead and turn that on.
Now it defaults to the first day today's day and so on going on holiday.
OK when's the last day.
I'm going to put in say the 21st a short hop kind of vacation come in here.
Now the message can be obviously anything you want.
I'll be out of the office until the 21st when I return.
I will respond to your e-mail so leave me alone.
Maybe something like this.
Why would you want to put this in the plain text.
Would it be better if it was on olds and had maybe an image and even a link or something.
Not everybody has the ability to see that stuff.
If I only send the response to people in my contacts or the people in my company one of a kind I know
the browsers they have I know their capabilities but if I'm sending it to anybody that I'm the one off
might send me an e-mail I might want to put that in plain text that's up to you.
I am going to send it to everybody so I'll leave these on check.
And I'll click save changes.
You'll notice a nice bright yellow bar up here which lets me know I'm on vacation settings.
Anybody that e-mails me I will get the e-mail but they will get that response.
Now let's say I get home early.
I can end it now just by clicking here or I can reset it in vacation's settings up to you.
I'm done.
Vacation's over.
So if you need to put an out of office responding messaging it's actually pretty easy and you've got
that big yellow bar at the top reminding you that it's active.