We've been spending a lot of time inside of Google's Gmail and of course it's a very important part
of the whole business app kind of thing.
But when you look at G-mail we can change the themes.
Couple of things like that but how about adding functionality in a really crazy kind of way.
And I'm serious in a crazy kind of way go up to your gear again and go down to settings and move over
to something called labs some crazy experimental stuff.
What is all of this.
Well what they are are features that we can add functionality to G-mail and basically use them or maybe
not use them different things to work with.
Let me show you one or two that I really like.
I'm going to get up here and type in undo and there is an undo sent.
So I'm going to enable that one.
What was it.
Do you ever send an e-mail.
And just as you're clicking the send button realize you forgot to put the attachment on there.
I hate it when that happens.
This allows you to undo the sending of an e-mail.
So I like that one.
Let's come back up here again.
And I'm going to type in keyboard until I see custom keyboard shortcuts.
I'm going to enable that one.
I am a big believer in shortcuts.
I don't use them as much when I'm teaching mainly because if I did you'd never see what I was doing.
You just see the screen changing.
I have to talk about things I have to use pulled on menus but shortcuts.
According to studies can save you one hour out of every eight in a normal workday an organization can
save you 20 percent of development so that's not too bad.
Let me go ahead and clear this out up here for a second.
There are all kinds of things in here.
You can send them feedback on one if you liked it or didn't.
And the lab is actually a place where if enough people use it if enough people like it it might eventually
be incorporated into Gmail on a permanent basis.
Labs crazy wacky stuff.
Now let's come down here.
And save our changes.
Check those out there's a lot of cool ones.
And by the time you get this lesson they'll probably be other ones.
Now let's start with that good old undo.
I'm going to send an e-mail
and we'll use this one right here.
Neat video
but I forgot to put the attachment I hate it when that happens.
Undo and it comes back.
Now there is a default time I believe it's 10 seconds but you can change that.
Let's get out of here.
Let's go into settings.
In general settings if we scroll down we have undo send right here.
So it's on it's enabled and you can choose 10 20 30 or if you're really brave five.
Now there is in my opinion one disadvantage to an undo that's really long like 30 seconds or something
you're sending a lot of e-mails and that's always popped up up there 30 seconds 29 28.
There is that disadvantage but I leave it at 10:00.
I think that's enough time for me to decide.
I made a mistake and you bring it back so it doesn't send it for 10 seconds.
Over here we have a new feature keyboard shortcuts.
And there they are.
We now have the ability to re map the keys that we used as shortcuts and look at all the shortcuts in
Gmail.
Change the shortcuts to keys that make more sense to you maybe adding new features using Labs is really
kind of a fun way to customize the Gmail experience for you.