In this chapter we're going to talk about the Google calendar love calendar.
We're going to talk about what it is how it works when it create events which are kind of the heart
and soul of the calendar I guess.
Can talk about how we use them.
We're going to create additional calendars maybe personal calendars will add events even through G-mail.
You don't have to do it just in calendar.
We'll talk about sharing with we share with and who you don't.
We're going to wind up in the calendar lab which allows you to add crazy fun things additional enhancements
into your calendar.
All that in a little bit more in the chapter.
Let's go.