We're one step closer to business Nirvana and that's what I call communication.
We have only been using the one calendar and that's not really that big of a deal but you can organize
better if you have more than one calendar for example if you have family.
It's like my father in law invited me on to a fishing trip.
Would you like other people to see that.
How about creating for your business something like a holiday calendar where everybody has access to
put their holiday time down so people don't conflict.
A lot of good reasons why you might want to do this and it's very easy to do too.
Let's come over here to my calendars right there click this button go into create new calendar.
Now name it my family which is actually the name of a very funny British sitcom My organizations already
their description my family stuff.
Where am I.
Well I happened to be in Wichita Kansas.
You as a country united states I can change that obviously I am in the Central Time Zone.
You want to share this calendar as a public calendar.
No.
You want to share it with everyone in the organization.
No actually I don't.
So I'm going to turn these off.
I want to share it with specific people about my family.
My wife and my father in law.
So let's put them in James Lloyd over here.
See all events make changes to events make changes and manage Sherritt.
Now I don't mind if he changes things so we go ahead and say make changes to events he has that control.
I want to add somebody else.
And we're going to go into Bonnie and we're going to use her real Andy account right there.
Now her.
She's my wife.
I trust her.
I'm going to say go ahead and make changes and manage it.
Now that's my default anyway because I own the account.
Now if somebody falls out of favor with me.
Do you ever have anybody in your family fall out of favor.
You can always delete them over here or change what they can or cannot do here.
You always come back to this area.
Go ahead and click Create calendar.
And once you create it it'll take second over here to get to us.
There it is.
I can turn off or on by clicking the calendars.
So right now the only thing I'm seeing is my family.
So I remember that James invited me into a fishing party kind of thing on Sunday so I'm going to come
over here.
Let's do a quick note for am fishing with James.
Understand that now that we have more than one calendar we can choose the calendar.
It goes into so you want to make sure you got the calendar here and click Create event for I am fishing
with James.
Here's another interesting way to use those quick events.
Let's go into April and here Friday and type in this is kind of fun dinner Bonnie.
Now watch this every Friday for three weeks in my family.
Great event in that cool.
Now it started with the Friday that I was on and that's why I added three more even though I said the
next three weeks because it included this one too.
Using these quick tips and you can get more of these shortcuts by going out to the Google site can allow
you to create these events in a very quick way.
And we're putting them into one calendar.
We go back to March.
But what if we put say fishing with James into the wrong calendar.
If we selected and go to Edit events all we'd have to do is change it right here.
All you have to do is remember if you make a mistake you can edit it and change it any way we want to.
And we can change the colors Let's go ahead and say what we have.
Let's go back into April.
Do the same thing here if we click on it we can edit the event change the color.
Now since this is a recurring event it's saying do you want to do only this one or all of them.
You can create as many calendars as you want.
You can if I turn this one on actually show all the events let's take it back so you can see this on
both.
But you can turn them off or on to determine which one you want to use at any one time.
Now what if you want to say for the sake of argument get rid of this calendar.
If we go up here to this button and go down to settings and then go into calendars if we come back down
here again you have the option by clicking on the calendar here to come down and delete it.
Now if you do that it does permanently do it and it will say OK you got a check here because I'm not
going to let you do this unless you know what's going to happen.
So you select there and you can delete it if you want to.
We will making new calendar to me as a part of organization in business.
But in addition we can be family or just about anything you want.