I call this lesson.
Killing two birds with one stone which I assume means you're getting efficient because you've got two
birds and you only use one stone to get it.
What I'm talking about is creating an event without using calendar.
So we're going to go into this little button right here and go into GMH.
I'm thinking about having a luncheon meeting because then the business pays for the lunch and I get
a free lunch and we're going to talk about stuff.
So I think well I think I'll invite Mike and maybe Sam so I can post in Gmail Everything starts with
the compose experience.
I'm going to hold down the Shift key and click the button right here to pop it out.
You don't have to do that.
I just like doing that.
So I'm going to go in here and type in Mike and it will give me his name.
And Sam
guys let's get together for lunch and talk about stuff.
My signature is already there and I don't type that and then I think I should have done this three calendar
because it would have sent them the invitations and it would put it on my calendar for me.
Get onto the attachment button little paperclip and go all the way over here and there it is insert
invitation based on my e-mail.
Now the cool thing about this is it's showing me again their calendars.
Now you can see they're clear but if there were any conflicts I might say well I better change that
to a different day and maybe we could back up a little bit.
You know maybe take it out 12:30 or something and actually push it ahead.
And it's up to you to decide that based on the calendar.
Now you might get some people that don't have a calendar.
Not everybody that you send the e-mail to has to be a part of real anti-cop or at least in my case it
could be my wife and maybe I'm using her personal e-mail address.
In that case she'll be here but it will know that she does not have any calendar.
If the calendars are there I've got control where
I'm making that up as I go.
We only have one calendar so far so no big deal.
And you could add more description down here.
I'm going to insert the invitation.
This is what they're going to get.
Click Send All right.
Let's go ahead and go back into
and there it is.
So you don't just have to do it in calendar if you're creating an e-mail and go.
I would have been a good idea to put it on the calendar.
You can.