I learn something new at school today I learned how to share.
Although my experience with my young nephews and nieces is when they're very young they don't like to
share anything do they like to keep to themselves.
I need to share a calendar or somebody need to share a calendar with me.
How do we do that.
Actually very easy.
Now we've already gotten a taste of that because when I set up the events in this chapter we could check
other people's calendars and make sure there was not a conflict.
But what if I just want to see somebody's calendar.
Let's do this.
Let me start the process off from the beginning for quick because sometimes on a journey we lose sight
of where we came from.
So if I go into Admin
and I go in and sign in with my super top secret password we can go into users and we set up users don't
we.
We've done this.
The user will get notified through an email and we choose the email we're sending it to.
They come into Gmail.
They activate their account.
They have a calendar.
Now before they log in like Bonnie shouldn't have a calendar yet because she's never logged in and confirmed
that she's part of the group.
So we know this process do this let me log out of here first and let's go into G-mail.
I don't want to log in as me.
So let me come down here and let's say we just created the account from Mike.
So we're going to add Mike here so we get him and there he is type in his password if I remember.
If it were brand new you wouldn't have a lot of stuff here.
He'd have the introduction e-mails things like that.
But he is now in a sense activated the account if he goes into his calendar he can begin populating
whatever he wants that's going the month.
He's got some stuff going on.
It's got a lunch meeting over here a group meeting down here in April.
He's got a holiday set up and a spa day.
This guy's brand new and he's already setting up holidays and spas.
It's kind of interesting what if he needs to see somebody else's calendar.
Can he do that.
Actually it's very easy if you look down here you've got Sam Spade already there.
Now how did that get there.
I requested it by typing in.
Co-worker up here about mine.
Doesn't sound too secure.
I can check somebody else's calendar.
You're part of the business.
That's what it's all about.
If I come up here and go into settings a couple of places you can do this actually and go into calendar's.
And here is Mike's calendar shared edit settings.
The default is to share with everyone in the organization.
Now if you have a second calendar that's personal you can turn that off.
Your business calendar unless you change this is accessible to anybody.
But we can take that up one more level.
Let's say you not only want somebody to see what you want them for whatever reason to manage your calendar.
So you come in here and you add a person well how about me is going to add me and he's going to allow
me actually he can't stop me from doing this because I'm the administrator.
But he's going to allow me to make changes managed Sherrick and let me come back over here and finish
that on or we're not going to get any or I now have the ability to make change and manage his calendar.
Let's get out of here.
And go back to calendar now it doesn't change anything here.
But notice there are two areas Mike is up here under my calendars along with tasks other calendars down
here.
All these other ones.
Now what's the difference between the two and why didn't Andy in Sam come up here let's do this let's
get out of here and let me sign in and you will notice he's up here under my calendars not down here.
Why.
Because Mike gave me the ability to manage his calendar and he will appear up here if he hadn't to actually
he can't stop me because I'm the administrator.
But if he gives the permission to somebody else they're going to peer down here.
That's the difference.
As long as the calendar is public and you're allowing people in the company to actually access it you
cannot stop them from accessing it.
But it's no big deal.
You could have a second calendar and you would turn that off if you need to share your calendars.
There's no really big deal about it because there are already shareable.
If you don't want them to be shared you have to turn that off.