This lesson we're going to talk about creating events.
But you can start see now how all of these apps as we go through these chapter begin linking together
to produce a result of efficiency in communication in any business.
So I'll tell you what I'm going to get into my area up here and type in calendar and it will assume
I want that which is what I want and I'm going to activate that if you need to put in your password.
Please do events are things that go on a calendar that let me and everybody else know something's going
to happen.
It could be a fishing trip with my father in law.
It could be a very important production meeting for my business.
Doesn't really matter when you show you three different ways to create an event.
If we come up here and click the work create we get this big area to fill in the event so let's start
doing a production meeting.
I want a production meeting and not today but on Monday that would be a good day before the week has
a chance to get complicated.
And I think I wanted to start at say about 11 o'clock and I wanted to go actually to 12:45 but I don't
see a 12:45 up there.
That's fine go ahead and type it in.
PM And it will be on Monday.
Now here's the first interesting little feature time zone when you're working with Google Apps for business.
You could have people all over the globe time zones.
It might be 11:00 a.m. in Central Time Zone.
Wichita Kansas USA where I live.
But it might not be someplace else.
So if we click here you can do event time zones for different parts of the planet if you want to.
Let's go ahead and cancel that.
Is it all day.
No it's from 11 to 12:45.
Repeat is a very powerful feature.
Number one I think I do want to do this every month should be a monthly thing but it could be weekdays
Monday Wednesday Friday Tuesday Thursday.
Monthly.
Yearly de-link monthly on this guy.
Now repeat every x number of months.
Repeat by the day of the month and the day of the week we'll talk about that in a second.
Starts on the 24th.
Yes ends never or after so many occurrences.
Or on a particular day notice because I chose day of the month.
It says it will be monthly on day 24 of the month.
That could be a Sunday for all I know.
I thought well no that's not right.
I need to put that into say day of the week which means every month on the fourth Monday so repeats
a very powerful feature to cancel out of it to the location.
Well the location is I love this about Google 2 1 1 1 and it starts finding the addresses for me.
I love that.
And it found the one I wanted.
This one right here.
Now that actually happens to be we have a big box store here in the States I think it's in other places
it's best buy electronic equipment.
So what we're going to do is spend some time at Best Buy looking at equipment that we might need for
a business that's the whole idea calendar.
We only have one so far.
We'll make another one.
But you can have personal calendars whatever description go to Best Buy and look at cool stuff.
Sounds good to me.
Do you want to add an attachment.
That could be maybe some notes for the meeting.
PTF documents something like that I usually do PDA because everybody can open a PDA.
If you want to add one you can do you want to change the color.
Let's go like a red or blue.
You can make up whatever you want obviously for what these are.
And you know what I'm notorious for missing meetings.
Oh that was today at 6:00.
Oh man I forgot that.
So I want a pop up bang pops up and says Hey ten minutes before.
No.
I'm going to go 20 because I have to get in my car and drive to Best Buy.
But that might not be enough you know.
So I'm going to add another reminder right here and this one is going to be an e mail and it's going
to be 60 minutes before or it could be hours days or weeks up to you click here if you don't want it.
Close it.
Now show me as busy which is default during the meeting time which makes sense.
You want your privacy as default public or private up to you.
Here's where we enter in guests.
Now if you have a group you could enter in the group name like Star fight.
Let's just do this.
I'm going to invite Mike and just go ahead and press the return key and I'm going to bring in Sam.
So I've got two guests and myself the executives of the company right now this up here because I haven't
sent anything to them.
There's no yeses maybes nose or waiting's because the e-mail hasn't gone out yet.
I can click here if I don't want somebody to be a part of the group.
I changed my mind.
I can click here if that person is optional.
Now in suggested times it's basically saying these are the times that I can use and all participants
can attend.
How does it know that.
Let me show you something that's kind of cool.
Come over here and select find a type Notice how it's over that area and look at what Sam Spade's calendar
has on it.
It's got a group meeting.
I can move this around to find an area that best fits all the people that are involved.
See the beauty of this.
Mike's got a calendar.
I got a calendar.
Sam's got a calendar.
They're putting their meetings on their calendars.
I have access to that information and I can choose a time when everybody can come.
You know what that is.
That's organization that's efficiency.
We can come back over here again if we want to change it and notice it change to it but when I moved
it over here changed it from 1:00 p.m. to 2:45.
I'm thinking well yeah I can do that.
And obviously Sam can do that.
And Mike can do it so we're good to go.
I love that feature.
Let's go back into Event details down here.
Last thing you want guest to have the ability to modify an event.
No no modification.
And I don't want any other people.
This is just for execs.
And yes I do want them to see the guest list.
Up here click save.
You want to send the invitations of course send them to the event.
Let me go ahead and go into month mode right here is now right here.
If I selected I can delete it if I want to change my mind if you will.
I can go into edit event right here see the word map that will give me a Google map telling me exactly
how to get to the best buy.
If we go back to EDID event here you will notice over here I have one yes that's me.
I made this of course and come.
There are no maybes no nos to a waiting's because I just sent the e-mails.
They haven't had time to get back to me yet.
Total organization.
But I tell you what I decide because I really didn't think this through.
That it's not going to work.
I need to change it to the point of not just changing the time I need to start all over again I'm going
to go up and say delete now when you delete and I would suggest you do this.
You actually have the ability to send and notify the guests that you're deleting it.
That's exactly what I'm going to do.
OK so it's gone.
That's the first way to enter in an event.
And it gives you a lot of details.
Come over here and click this little button right here.
This is called a quick chat.
I love this when you type in next Monday production meeting you can capitalize if you want to obviously
with say cell just put one in here to save time.
Might get real Andy dotcom you could add more if you want it to.
10 a.m. for one hour.
What Google does is kind of cool it looks it then interprets it.
If I go ahead and click the ad button over here.
There you go.
Now we can go into EDID event and we can edit more of it if we want to.
But we've added the event down and dirty in quick.
Here's another way.
Let's come over to the 26 and click that we can do somewhat the same thing.
Notice the example is 7 p.m. dinner at ponchos.
How about something like I'm going to say dinner with Bonnie
for one hour.
And there you go.
Obviously if you create the event using this button over here you get a whole lot more stuff that you
can put in.
But these two other ways are very down and dirty.
They're very easy to use and you can always go back into the event itself and add more details.
Organization involves communication.
Calendar allows us to communicate and reminds us of things to.