In another chapter we talked about G-mail labs and some of the functionality you can add.
Well there's a calendar labs too if you want to use it.
Let me go in to see A-L calendar dot Google dot com.
That's just one more way to get to it.
And I'm already signed in so here we go.
Go up to your settings right here and go down to lamp's Reiner.
Now in labs you have these different things.
Hide morning and night.
What is that.
If you get a lot of people that are basically asking you and inviting you to things you can kind of
disable areas that you would never go to a meeting in gentle reminders.
Here's another one for automatically declining events.
And how many people invite you to an event at 3:00 o'clock in the morning so you could block off areas
and some people do get 20 or 30 invites a day.
They're very popular people and they say you know well if it's this time if it's in the middle of the
night Sunday whatever it is they should time.
I would never go to a meeting just declined the event.
For me this one is enabled by default because that's a lab feature that's part of Callendar now that
allows us to do things like attach spreadsheets and presentations.
This one is kind of interesting let's enable one or two of these.
This one allows you to create all those little crazy characters if you want to use them.
Who's my one on one with.
You've got a year view background image free or busy jump today.
Let's do that one too.
And this one tells you kind of like a countdown clock when your next meeting is.
I like that one.
Then we do one more World Clock.
Now you've got to do is click Save notice what happened over here.
We now have some new things.
Now we can also add tasks if we want to that would push that stuff down.
I'm going to turn taps off so you can see this.
Here's the event flare if you want to use it.
There you go.
Just click on one of those and it will add one of those to your event.
It's not do that please.
Next meeting is in 21 hours and 48 minutes.
It's a production meeting this one right here jumped today.
I need to see what I'm doing one year from today.
And then jump right here.
Nothing.
Isn't that amazing.
Oh incidentally if you do want to go back to today just click here and then you have a will clock just
like that.
I do business in the U.K. So that's a good one for me.
I do business on the West Coast of the United States which is a couple of hours difference than me.
So I can set these up just by going into settings right here and get just about anything you want and
any time you want to get rid of them you say what was I thinking.
You can go right back in the lab and turn them off if you want to.
Or you can click right there just like with G-mail.
This lab adds functionality to your calendar and since it's your calendar what you have here is personal
to you.