Welcome back everyone.
Now for the last chapter or two we've been doing the technical stuff to get everything happy to make
it all work.
To be honest with you if you already have that done your I.T. department did it for you whatever and
you're taking these lessons basically to learn how to use the programs you could actually start at this
chapter.
But I did want to.
I felt it was important to add that information in just in case you don't have some big I.T. department
and you need to know how to make it all work.
Now let's start I've got chrome open Explorer Safari doesn't matter and what I'm going to do is I'm
going to go up into my area here I'm going to type in Gmail.
I've already done it once so it knows what I've done.
Gmail dot com enter now needs to know my password obviously.
But in this case since I've been signing in it already has who I am.
If yours doesn't.
Just type in who you want and I will sign in.
Here we go.
We are in Gmail now.
In this first lesson I want to do is take us through the production of an email how it works.
And like I said before everything is set up.
You are not obligated to send email only to people who have a G-mail account with Google.
It'll go anywhere just like any other email system but like Microsoft Word is supposed to Word Perfect
sometimes although you're doing the same thing you're doing it a little bit differently now up here
let's take a little spin around here.
Up here we've got my emails that I have and I don't have very many because I just set the system up.
I wanted to kind of start the whole thing from scratch for you.
Over here it says I've got three emails.
Now those are the three that aren't read.
And just like most systems don't be bold.
If you click on one.
We're now down to two and I can well if I want to read this email they're all from Google.
Except for this one up here we'll talk about that later if I click this button right here it does refresh.
Over here you have a more button and it will allow you to mark all is read.
But we have to select messages Seymore actions.
So if I come on here and select this one again by clicking it right here.
Now here's the thing.
If you want to see more stuff up here you can select messages down here.
More than one if you want to and then you can control what they do.
So let's look at what we have now up here.
We have a button that allows us to archive put it in the archive I don't want to get rid of it but I
may want to come back to it someday.
This one allows me to report it as spam this is deleting this right here allows me to move it and I
can move it into some pre-set social promotions updates forum spam trash.
I can create new ones if I want to.
Over here are labels promotions update so I can put those labels on these particular selected emails
and the more button over here allows me to mark them as unread.
And why would you do that.
I have many times accidentally clicked on an email that I don't really want to read right now but I
don't want to think I've already read it.
Let me put it that way so I can market as unread or important at the task and talk about things like
tasks and contacts a little bit later.
I can use stars filter messages or mute them.
We over here we can scroll through them by clicking these buttons over here on settings.
You have a couple of things that are kind of interesting.
For example you have displayed density.
Now look at comfortable and look at compact puts them closer together.
I do work in a pretty large monitor so you're comfortable we can configure our inbox change settings
manage the domain change a theme or get help.
All that from here.
But how do you send an email if you are going to send one.
All you have to do is come over here and click the compose button and this is what's called the new
Google look.
We have a new message area.
We can say to say I want to send something to Bonnie now it remembers her email addresses because I've
already typed them in once so you can see I've got two options here.
If you've not done this before it's very likely you'll be typing in the whole thing but the next time
you won't have to.
So I'm going to go into this one right here.
Her G-mail account.
Now I can add another one if I want to by starting to type again.
We have CC's and B c C's B C C stands for blind carbon copy and what that means is if you send somebody
a c c they can see everybody.
The message was sent to.
If you send them a blind carbon copy they can only see them they can't see who else got the message.
The subject just simply a test of the system.
I come down here again and start typing.
Now once I have that done let's come back up here.
It now says a test to the system over here you have a button to collapse it.
That's down here right now.
However think of this I'm going to do another message.
I'm going to do it now before I send this one because there's things between both of them that are similar.
I can actually come over here now and compose another one if I want to.
Now let's go ahead and close this one out.
Let's click this button again to bring it back out.
Maximize it this button right here if you click it will allow you to go to full screen but it's still
locked to the screen.
In a sense if we click it again it'll take us back.
If you hold the shift key down and click on that button it will pop it out for you.
A lot of people like to work in a window that they can control and if we click here again it will pop
it right back in.
Now if we come down here obviously we have controls like any email system.
I can go in and say for example double click on the word test maybe and come over here and get into
my formatting options.
I think most of us know what this stuff does.
We have formatting alignment bullets and numbering indenting quotes or remove formatting.
Now we can turn that on or off just by clicking here.
We're going to get into attachments later but we can attach files we can insert files using Google Drive.
We can insert photos here is one of the advantages of using Google Chrome.
You can drag and drop this stuff right into the message if you want to.
Not all browsers will allow you to do that.
And this button over here obviously allows us to insert a link.
So if you have for example a Web site you want me to go to you'd insert it.
These guys right here let me click to the right of Andy and come back down here again.
These guys down here the emoticons.
If you click on this.
Understand these are animated.
If you want to use when you can.
I would suggest for business.
Probably not.
If you're just having fun go ahead and use one you just have to click on and there it is when you go
out and get rid of that come back down here again.
We have insert invitation and we'll talk about imitations later.
But understand how Google Apps for business works.
All this stuff is inner related.
If I click this button right here to send invitation it will give me my calendar.
It will allow me to insert these invitations in the calendar send people reminders.
It's a great system to work with.
Let's talk about that later though.
And then finally over here you do have a delete button.
If you don't want this one you can discard it.
And if you click this little button right here you have a couple of more options.
You can go into and change the label.
You can default to a full screen mode if you want that plain text mode.
Not all browsers support formatting.
And if you know that you can say plain text you can print it and you can check spelling.
Now check spelling is not a bad thing to do.
Printing actually pretty straightforward.
If we come up here like this it will give us a screen give us everything from the head or all the way
down click print.
It'll print it quick can so it still leaves it in its own tab.
And if we click here we go right back again.
If I click this button right here I'm saving it and closing it.
No it doesn't mean that means it's draft.
If I come over here into my drafts there it is right up here.
If you decide later.
Well you know what.
I don't need this.
I'm not going to send this one.
I'm going to change my mind.
I can click here.
And then tell the computer discard the ones I have selected.
Let's go back in inbox.
So as you can see there's not any rocket science involved in what we're doing now.
If you have ever sent an e-mail The only difference is probably the simple fact that it's slightly different
than maybe sending it through your normal e-mail application.
That's about it.
Now if we come over here and click on my name up here we can if we want to sign up
and I am now signed up sending Gmail.
Like I said it's very easy.