What I want to show you is kind of like a step above what we did in the previous lesson.
Let's start out by going into our gear and going into settings and going into labels now in labels.
I'm going to create a new label called family I'm not nesting it under anything and click Create.
Now I'm going to create another new label and I'm going to call it James as in my father in law.
This one I am going to nest under the new one I just made quickly so I could have Bonnie I could have
James I could have Joanne I could have family my sister down in Florida whatever family.
Why.
Because there's going to be so much going on with your mail.
It's not a bad idea to make your own little categories and labels and start isolating things.
So with that done let's go back in the inbox.
When my father in law e-mails me it's not about business it's always about family could be about a recipe
like it could be about I don't no new car but whatever.
Isolate him so it doesn't clog up my e-mail with family business.
So what I'm going to do is click here.
And say if a mess derives from James I've already done this once with him on another project.
So remember as I did that.
Now that's all I need.
I'm going to create a filter with this search when a message arrives that matches this search.
Apply the label family James create a filter.
That's it.
The next time I get a message from him I can come over here.
I can click James and all of his messages will be right there for me.
Say well what if I don't want that one anymore.
What if that was a mistake.
We'll go back into settings and go into filter's.
And there it is.
So I can edit it or I can delete it creating these rules and I have on my other system the one I use
in business.
I have hundreds of rules.
I have spam rules.
I've got family rules.
I got all kinds of rules.
I got more rules that I need.
But they can really help you and you can make the filter right here if you want to.
Making filters and creating rules organizes you.
Full stop.