I'm in Dr I'm going to go into presentations right here and I'm going to create new presentation.
I want to show you just a couple of more formatting tricks that are available.
Let's start with a simple light.
So we really don't have much going on here.
We go ahead and close this out.
For now we have one slide.
We do have click to add title click to that subtitle.
Let's come up here and click this button and go blank.
If we're starting with a blank slate we can make the most complicated cool looking background theme
that we want.
Starting right here we can go in here and pick up for example.
Oh how about a square.
And then go to the corner right here.
And draw out like that.
And once we have that of course we can come up here and change the fill color to something that fits
the mood of what we're doing.
We can custom color down here if you kind of know what you're looking for you can type it in right up
here.
You write like.
We can pick up a type or text box right here and draw ourselves the text box.
Select the text.
I did control a command and control in Windows to select all the text.
We can then begin massaging the text.
We know this maybe Center it.
That's right over here.
Now it goes outside the boundary of the box that I created because I made the text bigger.
The box doesn't expand but in animation and other things that can have an impact on how it works.
So you probably want to come down here and do this let it fit.
Let's go ahead and put another text box up here and we can start putting text in there put bullet points
to animate the points but I want to show you something here is kind of cool.
Let's say you want to make a link with this button right here.
Now you could click that button and put all the text in but I'm going to come down here first and type
something in.
I'm going to select that text.
Now check this out.
I think this is cool.
When I come to the link button now it's finding things related to the text that I wrote.
I've got a book on iTunes it's free on cooking.
I've got another one that you have to pay for.
You say well that's not what I was looking for.
Say find more got photos of me if I scroll down.
I do have videos on YouTube.
There's one right there.
I can actually insert a video.
But when you're inserting links that's kind of cool when you think about it if you're not sure where
the link is.
But you know the wording you can actually type that in and of course Google being the master of searching
in the universe is going to find related text.
That's pretty neat.
When you think about it now if we come back out of here for a second I didn't set that so it's not a
link right now.
Some of the other things that you can do up here for example you do have a tool that allows you to draw
a line and you have line wait you can do line dash.
So you come over here first and you select the line.
Give me an arrow a curve polyline and ARC a scribble.
You want a straight line.
Use this one.
Now that's really hard to see against that background.
I understand that but once you've got the line drawn we can come up here.
Let's make that bigger so we can see it and maybe change it into a dotted line.
Once you have it selected you can go to an end.
Wait for that arrow and you can redraw it if you want to just by moving it around or you can grab it
in the middle and move it someplace if that's what you want to do.
But we could keep this process up and actually with enough time design our very own theme maybe a company
theme with company colors in everything save it like we talked about and let anybody in our company
have access to it.
There are a lot of things that we can do two presentations in this program and it's not just about and
I know I harp on this but it's not just about learning buttons it's learning to use them in a way that's
going to be pleasing to me if I have to sit there and look at it.