Now I've taken the liberty to populate out the cells to save some time.
Same way I did this first row up here just added numbers put some decimals in etc..
What we need to begin some formatting and understand formatting of a document even a presentation a
lot of the stuff is pretty much the same.
Let's start at the top.
Let's go to a money chart right up here.
First thing I'd like to do is probably center that OK so I'm going to click inside that row and we come
over here and center it.
Now since we merged all those cells together it goes to the center of the merge.
So I like that but maybe I should make it.
Oh I don't know a different color.
And let's try that.
Let's get in here.
Let's start with the background itself.
I think I do want that a little bit darker.
It's going to get in here and get a darker color.
If we come over here we don't have to select the text to make a global change just be in the cell.
And if I get here I could build it first I suppose and maybe come over here and change the color maybe
we could reverse this by going white with maybe something like that.
Then we change the font you know do all those things.
Down here we've got date and Monday through Friday.
And those are titles and I'm going to do something here I'm going to forget to select this one on purpose
and I'm going to drag across all of these like that so we can center those that make sense.
Center them in the column we could try building them in maybe even a talis sizing them and let's give
them a different color like maybe a blue.
So we do all these things.
And what did we forget we forgot Friday.
I never forget Friday thank goodness sometimes it's Friday.
I've got to remember all the things that I did to get that right.
Now we didn't do a lot but think about if you did a very complicated type of formatting operation borders
all kinds of things.
Well watch this.
We have a button up here.
Looks like a paint roller that same paint roller is in documents and in presentations and it works the
same way it is a format painter.
It paints formats.
So what you do it's very simple is get into a cell.
In our case since we're working on a spreadsheet get into a cell that contains all the formatting that
you want to apply to Friday come up here and click it and come over here and click and that's what happens
all the formatting changes.
I love that feature.
So we've got that in.
We're ready.
Let's come over here and let's select all of our dates now come up to this button right here and go
into more formats.
Now we have numbered formats.
We have all kinds of different ones we have Date and Time right here.
When we have more here I'm thinking Well one of my favorite ways to do a date is this one right here
come over this way and back up and he this one right here the day the month the year.
Now I have him all selected over there and we change that.
Now these should be numbers shouldn't they.
And they should be reflecting the currency of in my case the United States.
So let's go and select those just like that and let's come back over here again.
I have a button for U.S. currency but if you would like to change that.
I don't I don't need to change that.
But I can get into here again for more formats and I have for example two decimals custom decimals.
Here's my currency.
Now if US is not what you want it will pop up in the currency that you put the settings for the country
you live in.
You have more currencies here if you want to change it.
I'm going to go to this one right here.
And now we've got that problem solved.
The formatting of the document itself is not really that difficult obviously.
And it's not any different than formatting a Word document a Excel spreadsheet PowerPoint presentation
or documents and presentations in Google Apps for business.