In this lesson I want to show you how you can have a collaborative discussion with somebody as if they're
in the same room with you and they might be on a different part of the planet.
Now this is what I did to set this up.
I went into documents and I shared employee noticed not so easy to do.
For right click here and go into SHARE SHARE over here.
And I shared it with Bonnie.
She can add it.
It's going to open it up.
Now watch what happens.
Look over in the upper right seat the letter B appear that not only means that Bonnie has shared access
to this document.
It means she's got it open right now and she's working on it.
See the cursor right here that's where her cursor is inside of this document.
So I'm not too sure I want to send this out with supreme leader or whatever.
And so I want to get her opinion as if she's in the room.
Like I said she could be anywhere on the planet and I know she's online and I know she's looking at
this document so I click this button right here.
I'll select the text
and send that by pressing the return key.
She changes it and then sends me a check back.
This sounds better.
It's as if she's in the room with me which is actually not very far away but she could as I've said
be on the other side of the planet sharing a document with someone means more than just sharing it.
You can go back and forth in real time no matter where you are and create a collaborative effort with
one two three four five ten people.
Doesn't matter and use chat to bring it all together.
That's pretty cool.