We've got a bunch of documents but what do we do with them.
Now we're still in our Google Drive.
Well we have a lot of options.
We can e-mail them to people we can share them with people we can download them now.
Downloading it would take it from the Google Cloud where word is now and give us physical access to
it.
So let's talk about downloading.
Let's go into my drive here and I'm going to go into my cooking.
We have a lot of documents in there in recipes and say I want to download this one right here so I selected
it will open it up of course if I go up to the Word file on the pull down menu I can go down to download
as.
Now here's the fun thing I can download it in a different format.
I can take it from the Google map into Microsoft Word into the ot t the open document format I can take
it into rich text PTF plain text web page even and it will zip it if I do a web page.
I think I'm going to try to.
I'm not sure which one is going to work the best.
How will this convert say into Microsoft Word.
Let's find out now if I come over here and click Microsoft Word say a little arrow come down over here
and here it is.
If you click here you can say where is it showed in the Finder.
It's going by default into my downloads folder.
There it is right there.
It's going to get out of here.
Now I want to try it also as a PTF and see which one I like better because I know everybody's got Acrobat
reader so I'm going to come back up again and go down into download as and this time PTF portable document
file on little arrow goes down moves this over.
If you want to see what it looks like click on it right here and it will open it in.
In this case Microsoft Word that did not work.
So the conversion of something this complicated back into Microsoft Word is not really going to work.
So I know that one won't work on me go ahead and get out of that one.
But let's see the PTF Actually that looks excellent.
So I now know that if I'm taking something this complicated that was made as a document using Google
Apps is not going to work too well if I use it as Microsoft Word.
But it seems to work as a PTF So I've made my decision I will use the PTF.
Let's go ahead and close these tabs for now.
There is another way to do this.
If I come over here and say select this one right here and select maybe this one right here.
I have both of those or as many as you want selected and I right click my mouse one of the things that
I can do is download from here.
It will show me the items I've got to Microsoft Word.
Now I can work PEF will work.
I can basically at this point download them and I'll have the same option.
But I've done two at the same time which made me more efficient hasn't it.
Now notice it says you can export up to two gigs at a time.
That's all you can do.
Text documents usually aren't that big so I wouldn't worry too much about it.
But you can use the same download technique for images and images have a tendency to be big and you
might want to watch that 2 gig limit.
Let's actually not do it.
Let's get out of here.
Once you create the documents spreadsheets presentations whatever they are you have the ability to pull
them off of the Google servers which are in the cloud and bring them to you or to somebody else with
a simple download.