In this lesson let's look at some of the common formatting options that we have to change our documents.
So I'm going to go into my drive in I'm going to go into cooking and go into tips and tricks.
Now I made a conversion of this one so we can work on it and we'll go ahead and open that up.
Now we've worked on this one before we put a header and footer and we've made the background kind of
a gray which makes it easier to read on a monitor but I don't like the font.
The font we're looking at as it says appears for DNA for DNA is a sensor font and it is good for subtitles
and headings but not necessarily doing a lot of body text reading.
So I'd rather have more of a sense of fun for a lot of this.
So the easiest way to do a generic cover your bases kind of change is just select in here somewhere
in press control.
Now that's control in Windows command on a Mac which is a shortcut for select all you'll notice and
this is very important.
That box just went blank.
Now that means something that means that of all of the text I've selected and notice it doesn't select
the header and footer which is good but if all the text I've selected it's not all Verdana.
There's another font in there somewhere.
So you might want to pause and say well maybe I don't want to do this.
Maybe I'd better check the other stuff but I do.
Someone come up here and click and we have a few fonts we can choose from.
Now of those funds which are mostly sans serif.
The one I would probably use would be Times New Roman.
That's a Serrefine.
It's a reading font if you want more fancy and come down here and there's all kinds of things we're
botto.
It's kind of interesting.
Droid sands you have a lot of fonts to choose from.
Stick with Times New Roman it's boring but it works.
So with everything selected I come up here.
Standard word processing stuff and change it.
Now that does make it easier to read and you'll notice the font size at least down here is 10.
That's a little bit small we might consider changing some of that.
But this being a heading I would not want in Times New Roman some actually select that text by dragging
across it.
Let's do both these.
I'll try both of those.
And let's take that to say trebuchets.
That is more of a subheading and heading type of font.
Let me go ahead and get rid of that space right there maybe even get rid of the space right here and
we could select this text again like this.
And then of course you know this we can build it italicize underline it to just about whatever we want
to it.
Now down here on these write in here let's come over here and let's select all of that stuff.
Now if we come over here we could bullet point these things if we wanted to.
It looks pretty good.
I like that.
Each one has its own bullet point.
Now what we're doing now is not universal or not pressing control.
So you're going to have to go through the document a bit at a time.
Go onto the next page make these changes.
What we also have here let me come down to one of the other pages.
We also have right here styles.
Now you've got normal text which is what we're operating with now.
You've got title subtitle heading one heading to and heading three.
Let's come down a little bit further.
See what we got here and let's just go to these.
This would be easy to work with.
I'm going to select this text right here if I come up here.
Now of course we are in normal text.
If I select it right here it will change it because I'm changing it to that style so normal text is
Cambria at 12.
Now let's say for the sake of argument that when you work on a document your normal text is 12 and it's
times new roman.
So every time you click that button it changes the text into Cambria at 12.
You want Times New Roman.
So here's something you can do.
If I select all of this again and go ahead and make my change say in the Times New Roman and let's actually
do this let's change that to 11.
Eleven actually is the new reading font 11 on paper.
And that's what you want.
Normal text to do every time you click it can save you a lot of time come back up here to normal text
and come over here and click this button right here and say apply or update update normal text to match
what what I have selected.
And that means the next time we use it it will apply the Texas times new roman at 11.
Let's just do a few of these.
There you go.
Keeping up with the styles can really help you out.
Now don't forget we have things like centering the text in left and right justify standard word processing
stuff.
Here's a button to actually number them as opposed to using bullets and you can get a lot of these options
underneath pulled on menu to.
You also have clear formatting if you want to do that.
Now let's say for the sake of argument on your normal text you wish it was back to the way it was because
you really don't like it anymore.
If you come down to options one of your options is to reset the styles and if you do it will reset the
stylus back to what Google thinks they're supposed to be.
Now another option you have if you choose to use it would be this right here and that doesn't make the
page bigger or smaller.
Obviously when you're actually printing it it's just when you're working on it here and you can change
the size formatting documents is pretty straightforward.
If you have ever in your life worked in a word processor and typed out a document there are no surprises
here.
Everything is pretty much straight forward.
Don't forget everything that we have done to this document has been saved automatically.
So if we come over here and click this button we're back into our Google Drive and all our changes on
formatting have been saved.