The advantage to using Google Apps for business sometimes can actually be a disadvantage.
Let me explain that.
We work on servers the Google servers the servers are in the cloud the cloud rains down on us anywhere
we are that has a wireless connection and we can work anywhere we want.
We can communicate with our coworkers.
We can send them stuff spreadsheets whatever.
That is the advantage.
The disadvantage is in my opinion what if you want to work on something but you don't have a connection
to the Google servers if you're on an airplane and you don't want to spend the extra money for the new
wireless service.
And I don't blame you.
Maybe you're going to be on the airplane for an hour or two.
You just want to catch up on a document if you're off line.
You can view stuff but you can't change it.
Let me show you something if we go into more right here.
Now this will be in any one of the Google Apps.
There is an option for off line.
Now we have already installed the drive but if I go to off line it'll tell me I already have the web
app.
Basically what this does is it puts editable copies of my documents on my computer and if I enable offline
that's what it will do.
So you have to be online now to get it done.
But the process then goes this way I can say get on the airplane or whatever I can do any work that
I want to and when I get back online the updates will be transferred to the Google servers.
So the advantage of having Google business which is good can also be a disadvantage but not if you enable
off line editing.
It's as easy as that.