In this chapter we're going wordprocessing with Google documents we're going to talk about how you create
them.
We're going to work with templates you've got thousands to choose from.
We can talk about how you download correctly a Google doc.
We'll talk about Page Options.
We'll talk about adding images and shapes it's something you want to do.
We'll talk about formatting options additional ones.
We'll talk about revision history which allows you to go back to revisions that you made in a document
even days ago.
We'll talk about a very powerful feature called working off line and then we'll actually revise documents
using chat in an interesting way to work.
We're going to do it all in this chapter.
Let's go.