Let's kick off this chapter by going into Google Drive.
So I've got chrome open I'm going to come up here and start typing and drive and it will put things
up there that I've done before in Google Drive is the one that I want.
I'm just going to press the return key.
You might have to type in your password.
If you do go ahead.
Here we are in Google right now since the last time we visited Google Drive I took the liberty of adding
a few more folders spreadsheets forms documents presentations and I gave them colors.
I'm not sure if I showed you how to do that but if we expand out my drive so we can see them over here
any anytime you touch one of these or hover chill button right over here.
Now you can achieve clicking the button by right clicking if you want to do it that way.
But if you click on one of these you have options like opening and creating new folder etc. sharing
at a star.
Come on here and change the color if you want to.
All that really does is change your visual perception of the folder.
But it could be a color that would attract you to the folder in a sea of folders and help you locate
it faster.
It's up to you.
And I did I changed the colors on those what we're here for in this particular lesson.
And in this particular chapter is talk about word processing and documents.
Google Apps has its very own word processor but unlike Microsoft Word which I love word perfect or just
any regular old text processor we are using the Google Apps for business processor which gives us control
sharing and email attachments and all the things that we can do.
Tell you what let's do one thing.
In this chapter Let's talk about creating a document.
Number one if you want to create the document in a particular folder like documents folder then have
that one selected.
And when you click here down create documents drawings forms mind map presentation spreadsheet.
We want to document and select here.
So this is kind of like what they call tabula rasa blank slate.
We're starting from scratch.
We have all the options.
We'll talk about some of these formatting options up here obviously in this chapter.
And you just really start typing.
But tell you what before we start typing it is as you can see up here in untitled document.
Click on the word untitled document and you can rename it in.
Well you notice.
Click OK.
Start typing.
Guys we need to up production.
We're getting a bit too slapdash around here supreme leader and we understand that as we actually write
the letter it's being saved all changes saved in drive.
We don't have to click a button to save it so that's cool.
Now we know it's being saved to the folder called document.
But what if for the sake of argument we either want to change the folder that it's saved in or get this
we want to put it into more than one folder.
So if you come up to this button right here and it says moved to folder and click that.
Now it's showing us the one that it's in it's in documents but if you're going to organize right here
you can see all of them.
You say well you know what this is designed for my employees for the company so documents it's kind
of like business.
But actually my cooking staff too is getting a bit slapdash and basically I want to send the letter
to them too or I want it in both places.
If I click up here it basically would just select that other document folder just like that.
But if I hold on the control key and that is the command key on a Mac control key in Windows and click
again I can actually add a folder.
Now again why am I doing that.
Well it's possible you might want to send it to two different divisions and you've got a folder for
each one.
Are you making a copy of it.
No you're just pointing to it.
So if I open it from the cooking folder which it now would be in.
Or I open it from the documents folder.
Basically it's the same document.
It's just being pointed to by the folder that it sent me going.
Turn that off.
I really don't want it in there so control or command click again or click Cancel.
Now you can also do things like even create a new folder right here.
Let's go ahead and cancel out of there and let's come back over here.
Open Google Drive if we expand it out here and go to the documents.
There it is.
So creating documents just like spreadsheets or presentations begins quite simply.
But one of the things that some people have asked me about is how do you put it into more than one folder.
And now you know.