Creating documents are actually pretty easy but you start with a blank canvas don't you.
There are a lot of things you can do in documents to document colors and fonts and all kinds of crazy
things and if you've ever worked in a word processor especially like Microsoft Word or Word Perfect
whatever you know you can do anything you want bring in images all kinds of crazy stuff but you're still
starting from a blank slate.
Let's talk about templates because there are a lot of them that you can choose from this time.
Let's just click my drive and then go to the word create in say document.
Don't give it a name.
Go up to the Word file right here go down to a new template.
This is kind of fun.
And when you first get here I have no templates.
I've not used any templates and I don't have any my templates.
I need a template so I can play around with it.
If you come over here you've got a really cool area.
People submit them.
You can submit your own templates.
See the button right over here you can basically pick from thousands because this is added to every
day.
And there are literally thousands and thousands of these things.
They're made by Google Docs a lot of them and see that right here.
And some of them are a lot of them are made by people like you and me.
If we come over here first off I've got time cards and all kinds of crazy things but all I want.
Number one is documents.
So if you click this button right here it will sort out through put all the presentations in that to
the side and just let you see documents and there are quite a few of them.
Now I'm looking for something in particular I'm looking for a new way to do a recipe card.
So I'm thinking maybe the word recipe is here's one recipe striped You got see these are resume's all
kinds of things going to come up here into search and type in recipe just like that.
Search the templates Wow there are quite a few.
Look at all those all kinds of different ways to make a recipe template.
Is kind of cute.
Tell you what I'm going to come back up here.
Kind of like this one before I decide I'm going to use it.
I can preview it right here.
I actually kind of like that one.
I like the color.
The color actually is a good color food.
And so I'm going to close this window.
I would say use it.
I like it.
It's now an editable document.
For example I'm thinking well it's actually a real recipe by Alice Waters but I think I'll make it carrot
bisque.
Now I did misspell that I did that on purpose because you'll see the line coming out here in saying
hey you misspelled it.
Let me help you if I right click on it.
There it is.
Now you have other options here.
But I have a love hate relationship with spellchecking.
Let me put it that way.
I love it because it helps me find the words in if I've got anywhere near the letters that it's supposed
to have in it it's probably going to find the right spelling.
I dislike it because I find it difficult when I'm writing without a computer to spell anything anymore
it's crazy.
Now this would actually have something besides chicken broth in it too.
How about two cups double cream.
Now please do not try this recipe because what I just did too it probably ruined it but I don't know.
I think I like that copy of recipe card is not the name I want I want carrot bisque.
So let's go ahead and click.
Where did I save this thing.
Let's come up here.
Didn't save it anywhere but on my drive.
That's not where I want it.
I want it in cooking.
And I want it in recipes.
Right there click move to.
Now you also have the ability since you gave it a name to add a star that might help you find it quicker.
If you want to do that.
But if we come back out again right here and we go into and open up my drive and go into cooking and
go into recipes there it is carrot bisque or let's say you like that template but either you don't remember
how to get to it again or it's like well I don't want to go through that process I want to use it again
right now.
So if we go back up to create Now this will put it in recipes since we have that selected if we're going
to create and go back to document go file and go into new from template.
But this time go into templates I've used it as templates to me are a great way to get a start.
Get your foot in the door so you're not looking at a white piece of paper and saying well what am I
supposed to do now.
And you saw they had resumes see these.
They have cover sheets just about anything that you want is in the template gallery it is pretty cool.
So you want to remember you have that.