Creating a plain document is not very difficult come up say to hear you say create document you start
typing.
But word processors do a whole lot more than that don't they.
Let's talk about some of the things that we can do to add some flair to our document add headers and
footers things like that.
So let's go into my drive here.
I'm going to go into cooking now I'm going to go into tips and tricks I want to show you something.
We have European conversions and that was a document I put together about how Europeans look at measuring
and how we look at measuring and terminology in cooking.
So it's about seven pages long I guess something like that but it's in Microsoft Word.
If I click on it it will show it to me in the viewer.
But here's a trick if we selected here and then come up here and go to more.
One of the options is open with now the default is the drive viewer which means we can see it but we
can't do anything to it.
But it also says Google Docs So what will that do.
If you choose it it will make a copy.
So we'll then have to over there one will be word and one will be a Google doc and that's exactly what
I want to do.
So don't despair.
You can always convert.
Right now let's start out by going up say for example to our file option.
And let's go down to page setup in page setup.
Even though the document has already been created I can go landscape with it.
I can change my paper size over here if I want to.
I can change the page color.
Let's do that.
Let's change the page color to something a little bit different.
Now most studies will show you that if you're reading something on a monitor and it's got a white background
with black text it creates eyestrain because of that projection of the color on paper.
If you're printing it that's excellent white and black is excellent because that's subtractive color
but an additive.
It actually causes eyestrain so I'm going to mute the background with just a little bit of color.
I think that'll be nice.
We can change our margins over here and we can even if we like this set it as a default the next time
we'll get in here.
I'm just going to click OK.
So I've given it a little bit of color.
It's well it's less eye strain.
OK.
So we got that done.
Next thing go up to the word insert on the pulldown menu and go down to say header headers appear on
every page.
So maybe I could put in something like revision 1.
Author Andy Anderson.
And if we come down into the other pages you will see there it is.
Now once we've got it up here we can select it we can change its color if we want to we can change its
size.
Typical word processing stuff we can put it say over on the right side as opposed to the left or we
can Center it.
Let's go back up to the word insert and go down to footer.
Now the thing I like about footer for example is I can come over here now and go back to the word insert
and go into page number and select bottom of page maybe put in a slash go back up to the word insert
again.
Page count 1 of four pages and let's stick that on the right hand side to let selected make it a little
bit smaller.
Maybe something like that.
Now that will be of course on all the pages.
There it is.
Last thing let's look at real quick is say we want to print this.
So we go up to the Word file on the pull down menu and go on to print or use the shortcut.
That's control P in Windows command key on a Mac.
And here we are.
Total sheets for I click the print button right here.
Now we're looking at the Google Chrome print engine.
So it's gonna look the same on a Mac or Windows basically depending on your printer.
I can change the printer here if I have another printer I can choose the number of pages that I want
to print.
How many copies change my margins.
I have a printer that does two sided.
That's why that's there.
And you can use background colors and images but I wouldn't recommend that on printing.
Do you really want to waste the whole cartridge of ink printing gray on the back of that piece of paper.
I doubt it.
Now you can also do this through your own print systems dialogue right here.
So this is going to look different for you than it would for me especially if you're on a Mac or Windows
system.
But I have the same options.
I can make some other changes up here say to paper number of pages I can convert it into a PTF if I
want to.
Whichever method I choose if I'm ready to print I just click the button and there you go.
So some simple formatting which is very wordprocessor ish combined with the ability to print it just
like any other word processor.