In this lesson tell you what let's spice up one of our documents by adding maybe some images maybe even
some drawings.
I'm going to go into documents and in documents we have an employee notice and open that up.
We need to up our production people get in slap dash around here.
Supreme leader I want an image that really shows me as supreme leader.
So let's talk about how you might do that now you could add a logo.
There's a lot of more practical ways to do things here.
But let's have some fun.
I'm going to move my cursor by clicking down here and pressing the return key once or twice.
Go up to the word insert.
I keep one come up here.
This is the pull down menu we're using go to insert and go into images links equations drawings tables
all kinds of things.
Let's concentrate on images now under images we can upload an image I can drag it in or I can choose
it right here.
Now I happened to have on my other monitor to the right an image I want to use.
Now I could get it this way but I could drag it in it's easy drag it in.
I'm talking here.
Fearless Leader.
Now once you select it we can resize it of course make it bigger or smaller.
But down here it's an inline graphic right now which means it's going to move with the text.
This one will wrap around in other words if the image is in the text the text will wrap around it.
This is the one I use a lot it's called break.
Just select it and what it does is allows you to move it anywhere you want.
If it's in line you can't do that.
So don't move it say write about over to here.
That is my fearless leader.
Let's go back to the word insert and go back to image.
That's not the only way that we can take an image from here and move it into a document.
We can take a snapshot.
Now this would be with your say Web camera.
So we have to allow it right here and if you've got it set up on here I am.
Is that a cute face or what.
I can take a snapshot if I wanted to.
I'm not going to.
We could do a u r l if you know the proper address if you have anything in your albums.
We're just getting started out.
Google Drive my drive and you go to search right down here you can search Google life or stock images.
So we're on Google right now maybe type in dogs.
I'm a dog guy.
Now they will tell you down here only select images that you have confirmed that you have the license
to use but I'm assuming since these are here in the Google search they are for public consumption.
However I wouldn't just necessarily take that for granted.
So if you want one of these you could select it click down here.
Let's not do that let's stick with what we have.
I like that Fearless Leader but I'm not done.
Go back up to the word insert.
And go into drawing right here.
You know a lot of fun here.
If you go into actions you can even do things as Word Art.
I haven't seen that in a while but it creates kind of like very descriptive and very artistic type of
text.
I'm going to come over here and start with this option shapes all kinds of different shapes I'm going
to do a call out like this one here.
That's a color.
Now let me go ahead and draw the color.
Pick up my text you let's put a text box in there.
I am the fearless leader.
Now we need to make that little bit bigger and maybe select the text come over to more.
We could move it around we could line it.
We could change the color of it bold it change the size you know just about anything that you want to
do here and let's move that over just a little like that.
Put it in the center.
I am the fearless leader.
Now I like that.
So what I'm going to do is say save and close.
And there it is down here.
But I can select it and go into break text and maybe move it up here.
Like I said have some fun with it.
Now notice what it's doing now because this text is here.
It's forcing it down and putting it in this one area.
So I'm going to do is I'm going to move this guy down a little bit like this and see if we can fix that
problem.
Here we go.
I think you have to move down just a little bit.
You have to play around with these things but that's all right.
Have some fun with it.
Now we know I am the fearless leader so we can add images of course if we don't like it we can delete
it just like that.
More practical or at least on a more practical approach.
We're talking logos here signatures.
A lot of things that you can use as images very easy to put in.
All you have to do is go up to the word insert.
And we went into images and drawings but you also have equations and links if you want to add those.