In the previous lesson what we did is we looked at some of the formatting options that we have and we
made some formatting changes to a document so let's do this let's go into tips and tricks right here
and there it is right here.
It's going to open that up.
So this is kind of how we left it.
So we have this up here we have the bullet points down there but down here as we go down further we
made some changes here playing around we changed the text over here playing around again.
And let's go ahead and say that we wish we hadn't done this.
Now this can be further compounded if the document is shared with somebody else and you're both doing
edits on it and somebody messed up and you say I'd like to take it back some.
But since I've closed it and reopened it how do I change things.
I actually check this out go up to the Word file and go down to see revision history right there.
Now what you've got here are the revisions that had been made to this document.
Now we can go into detailed revisions here and you can see just about everything that's been going on
with this document.
Now what I'm more concerned with is coming down here is kind of getting rid of this stuff that we did
but leaving the overall formatting alone.
What I need to do is just kind of back myself through these if I come to this one right here and I come
back down here it looks like I got it.
It's like unlimited undo.
And if more than one person were working on it you'd see their name up here too.
You decide you'd like it.
This is where we left off.
We're happy with it.
Didn't like the other changes we made.
Restore this revision.
That's actually pretty cool.
Now this works in presentations.
It works and forms.
It works and well anything in Google Apps for business being able to change history in a sense revision
history on any type of document is a very valuable tool to have.