A groups or similar to chats and blogs we've all done blogging you get out to a site they've got a blog
going on.
You give your opinion people give you their opinion.
So it's similar to that except with Google they're setting up all the work for you and the permissions
and everything else to make it work with the firewalls.
So we're going to create what we're going to set it up.
We're going to show how you as the owner can set up your own permissions on what can be done.
We're going to work within the group showing how it actually works.
Now we'll take a peek at something else.
One more thing I want to show you in this chapter is called Google sites.
Now sites is a new feature inside of Google Apps for business and it deals a lot with actually creating
and generating your own web site.
I feel it's a little bit beyond the scope of what we're doing in this lesson series.
But I don't want to leave it out.
I want to show it to you.
I think you still need a little bit of HGA now and a little bit of design experience to really exploit
it.
But the last thing we'll look at is a peek at something called Google sites.
So all of that in this chapter.
Let's go.