This chapter we're going to talk about groups.
Now to me groups are an excellent way to communicate.
Now Google Apps for business is all about communication but we're talking about almost like a blogging
kind of atmosphere where you can get people together certain groups of people to discuss certain things.
Groups are really cool.
Now I'm in Croma.
I could come up here in typing groups that Google dot com but since I am in Chrome and I am signed in
I can go right here if I want to and go into groups right there.
We're going to create a group in this lesson and so let's get started by looking at kind of what we
got here over here.
You have a create group button which we will be using.
Over here you have my groups we don't have any at home which is where we just were started.
So you have a lot of groups you can start to kind of emphasize them and put them into favorite's makes
it easier to get to them.
We over here we have a button for my settings.
You have for example my global settings and you have things in here like notifications for example to
allow group managers to direct add me to their groups or invite me to their groups notification settings.
Product help is a matter of fact is here too.
Down here you have something besides the language you want it to be in canned responses.
Let me talk about that for a second.
If you go back into May you set this up in mail now you go into your gear and go into settings and we've
been here before.
Go to labs in labs we're looking for one of the labs that has the word canned in it.
And well there it is e-mail for the truly lazy canned responses.
It's possible there are responses that you would use in a particular blogging or e-mail type of situation
that you can use over and over again if you enable this it will take you through the steps it's pretty
easy where you can create canned responses.
So I just wanted to show you that if you ever wondered were canned responses were let's go back into
Google Groups now over here you have some typical things like display density from comfortable to compact.
You can take a guided tour keyboard shortcuts to forget those.
I love keyboard shortcuts.
They save you one hour out of every eight.
If you learn them and then down here finally you have something called fiend's and you've got to count
them to at least so far you have light and you have soft gray.
So think about it.
Make a decision.
Choose one.
Let's go ahead and get out of here and let's create a group.
Click the button right here.
We need a name.
We have a group that we call Starfire and it's people that are working with us on this top secret project
that we don't want anyone else to know about.
So let's call this Starfire project now the group e-mail address will emulate what you put up here.
Start a Fire project if you want to change that.
Feel free to use that name has already been used it will say down here it's already in use so we're
fine with that group description.
Now how about this group will discuss the new Star Fire project my primary language is English United
States.
Here's the group type.
This is where it gets fun.
You have four different choices.
E-mail List is what you think it's a discussion group based on e-mail.
You have a web form.
Again just what you might think it is a web forum Q&amp;A and the newer one collaborative inbox.
So you have a lot of choices here and you might want to play around with these.
Let's do Q&amp;A Q&amp;A for now.
It will tell you a little bit about it right here if you want to learn more about it view topics.
Now these are basic permissions.
We'll talk more about permissions later on.
But the basic ones are who gets to view the topics managers and all members of the group know public.
If you go public it goes outside the group anybody can get in.
Don't want that.
This is a top secret project post no public but all members who gets to join the group only invited
users.
It's not public.
This is top secret stuff.
So we've got that set up.
Not really rocket science click Create now you'll probably get this on verification.
Make sure you are who you are and you're not some kind of robo machine.
If you can't really read that trouble with these things I think they're crazy sometimes you can click
the button over here to find one that you can actually work with and that I can do that on.
Let me get in here and type in upper lower case doesn't matter here.
I think that's t I guess we'll find out.
Click Continue Star Fire project group has been created.
The next step would be to invite people to join the group so go ahead and start to do that.
I have a group called Starfighter makes sense we use it.
There's three people in the Starfire group.
We can write if we want to.
An invitation message.
Please join me in this group to discuss the Starfire Project send invites invitations have been sent.
We can show them right here and we have just created our first of hopefully many groups.
If we go back into groups up here and go to my groups it can take sometimes a minute or two.
My longest wait was actually 11 minutes before the Google servers actually brought it to me.
That was a little bit disconcerting to be honest with you but usually it takes about 30 seconds or so
and you've got your group.
We've invited people to the group and we're ready to go to the next lesson.