We've got a group and we've invited some people let's go into my groups right here and there it is here's
the star if you want to add it to your favorites.
Now we only have one so that doesn't really make a whole lot of sense.
Let's go into it and see what we got clicking on it right up there.
Now since we haven't done anything yet we have a couple more questions.
Number one do you want to link your real Andy dot com profile and show your photo on posts.
It's up to you.
You can use your full name from real indie dot com.
Or would you like a nickname.
Again that's up to you.
This is how I'm going to look because I didn't choose this one up here.
It does also tell you other members of the group can find your e-mail address.
Let's come down here.
The group doesn't have a welcome message.
That said let's add a welcome message.
Glad you're here.
Let the discussion begin.
We can bold italic at an image if you want to.
Let me scroll down here and click save.
Hey let's come back over into my groups and go into manage right over here.
You'll notice first off that the only person that's a part of this group is me but that's because people
haven't responded to the e-mail yet.
Let's look at a couple of different ways that we can invite people.
One we've already used this one right here where it sends an e-mail message and they can actually decide
if they want to come into the group.
The other one is a little bit more direct called direct ad actually members.
It warns you that you should use this feature carefully.
If you force people without asking them into a group that can be construed by some people as spam they
complain to Google.
Your account gets deactivated.
Well my wife Bonnie is about 100 feet away in her office so I yell over at her.
You want to be a part of Starfire and she goes sure.
I always like top secret groups.
So I said OK I'm going to put you in there type in let's go to her real account.
That makes sense.
You will need to write a welcome message.
Welcome to the group.
Now your options.
No email.
Web only participation abridged digester all I work on some blogging sites on testing of software and
I can get hundreds of emails a day going back and forth that I don't care about.
So settings like this are kind of important.
I know Bonnie is not going to want to get a lot of e-mail.
She can come to the blog when she wants to participate so I'm going to leave that at no right up there.
And then we clicked the ad button her.
Now you might again get a verification
one member was at it show Bonnie.
So if we get to all members now we have to.
However as the other people respond positively hopefully to the email they also will be added so we
can come down here and say outstanding invites.
If you select one of these you have a choice to revoke their invitation or you can also get rid of them
later on too or rescind the invitation because maybe I don't know I got lost in the junk filter.
When you're working with groups you have several ways to invite people to those groups.
I would in most cases use the one that asked permission as opposed to the other one.
Unless you really know that person because I can get you into trouble and trouble is not something we
need.