Before we exit this chapter I do want to show you one more thing if we go up here I mean drive right
now there is an options relatively new call sites now in my opinion sites don't really fit in kind of
with what we're doing in this title but I don't want to leave it out.
I want to show it to you it's actually pretty interesting.
It allows you to create a fully functional site a Web site but in my opinion in order to get it done
correctly you still need a little bit of knowledge of web design and some of the coding.
With that said we're going to jump in with both feet.
I'm on sites I don't have one yet.
I can create it right over here if I come over here first go into user settings you want to set up obviously
your language.
Now if you have Hebrew or Arabic documents you can say show right left controls which time zone do you
want to be notified of your own changes.
No.
I want keyboard shortcuts though click save if you've made any changes.
Come over here and create.
Now the first thing is to browse the gallery or choose a blank template.
Let's browse the gallery.
There are some pretty cool things in here.
We can go into Insearch if you want to.
Let's go into business.
See what they got here.
You got all kinds of things that we can work through.
Clean and elegant sounds good to me.
We select it.
We see a little bit of what it looks like if we like it we say select If not we can cancel or go back
to the gallery.
Let's select
the address we'll emulate what you have up here.
You can change that if you want to select a theme by clicking here.
Now the themes don't change the overall look but just some of the colors and the fonts and things like
that it's the theme if you want one of these.
Let's go into simple come down a little bit further.
Lots of themes more options side categories and description will help people find you if you want to
be found.
We'll leave that out.
But you can use that click Create up here.
Now take a second or two for this to happen or a minute or two.
There you go.
Now the site itself is functional but we need to change things like for example what it says down here.
This thing can fit many purposes.
That's not what I want it to say Welcome might work but not that.
How do we change things on this.
Well what you can do is come up here and click this little button right here for edit the pages and
that loads the editor so we can now get into this and we'll come down here and change that text if we
want to make any changes that we need to add our own images.
We can go to the other pages too if we let's get out of here for a second.
We'd even be making changes.
This actually works.
It's a functional site.
It just doesn't have the stuff I want on it yet.
If we go into more up here we can do things like revision history so you can go back in time if you
made mistakes.
We can save this as template.
We can do site actions like edit the site layout manage the site.
Let's look at manage the site now in manage the site there's your categories again site notices a disposable
message site description site activity which we won't have any pages.
Those are the ones that are in it right now and we can add just by clicking there attachments those
were all the images.
It's using page templates so you can do a mini blog of announcements just by clicking here.
It's a very powerful editor but in my opinion in order to implement the site really good even though
it's doing a lot for you you still need a little bit of information on exactly how to put a site together.
But it is a great thing if this is something you want to do let me go ahead and get out of here.
And let's go back into site.
If it's the next day and I want to work on it again it's very easy you just click on it right here again.
If we go back up to the word more we have sharing and permissions.
They can also get that right up here.
Now that's the link to share.
But that also allows editing who has access.
You can invite people in put them in right down here.
This is an interesting feature and I do believe it's going to grow over time and even become more powerful.
But if you're interested in putting together a complex site without a lot of HVM now or ph or a lot
of those things that go along with doing web design this is actually a pretty good place to get started.