I am in and Google.
I'm going to go into my groups and I'm going to select manage again.
Writer.
Now we've got James in we've got my camera but we don't have Dirk yet do we.
So let's do this.
Let's answer for Dirk.
When mean come out of here and sign out real quick sign back in with a different account.
Let's go into his G-mail.
Do you want to accept or not.
Yes.
You've successfully joined.
You can now immediately go in.
But let's go into my account first.
So I have to get out of this one again.
Let's go back into groups
and there he is.
All the members are here we can start having fun.
Some of the things that we can do I can click say on Bonnie Lloyd and it opens up another area right
here says actions and I could choose more than one person if I want to.
If I come up to actions one is add to roll I can make one or more people owner and or managers if I
want to I own it I can do anything I want.
I could remove her from the group her ban her like I'm going to do that to my own wife.
I can change delivery settings and I can set posting permissions.
Now we know how to invite people we've talked about that but let me show you one other area here and
that's join requests.
You can only join this group if I ask you to come in.
But let's say it's more open.
Well you would have here we don't have any.
But you would have here join requests and you would make the decision saying OK this person can join
the group join requests down here.
I want to talk a little bit about permissions because this is where you kind of set it up to make it
work for you.
The basic ones we've already kind of talked about who gets to view topics.
Who gets to post who gets to join the group.
And you have a new member question you want to ask people posting permissions down here.
And basically these are pretty straightforward.
Who gets to do what this one none selected yet so select group or users managers who gets to assign
topics were all managers in a sense were all executives and say everybody who gets to attach files.
Now we don't have free form tags we can enable that if we want to but we don't have that option.
Mark favorites metoo topic that's like oh me too me too.
I like that topic.
I like that one.
So who gets to do that one.
And it tells you over here what it is all the different ones post announcements.
Who gets to do that.
Everybody replying to auto close topics we're all execs.
How about canned responses which I find kind of amusing sometimes.
Everybody want to click save.
If you don't it will warn you.
Come down to moderation permissions.
Now again all these are questions on who gets to do what and it's up to you to go through them edit
other posts.
Well I tell you what I think I'm going to leave that up to me.
Mark duplicate.
I'll let all members do that if they think it's a duplicate.
Like I said we're all executives.
Mark no response needed.
No I think I'll leave that to me.
Take topic all members on a sign.
I think I'll leave that to me.
And then click Save access permissions.
Who gets to contact the owner who gets to view members view member e-mail addresses and view topics
the defaults are pretty much what you're going to use in most cases.
But it is important as the owner of this particular group to go through them and make sure everything
is exactly the way it's supposed to be.
Now let me show you one more thing down here under information.
Go into advanced in advanced.
You can disable the group nobody can post to it but they can still see it you can delete the group.
It's over.
We don't want any record of it so we're going to delete it or you can reset it and even choose a different
type of group if you want to.
All under the Advanced Settings in information and I have had a lot of people ask me How do you get
rid of a group if you don't want it anymore.
Well that's how you do it.
Right down here in advance.
Right there it is permanent.
Let's go ahead and get back out of here and go back into our groups.
There you go.
We've created a group.
We've invited people to our group and we've looked at working through permissions.
The next step is to see how the thing actually works.
So let's do that.