We've got a group we've set the permissions up we got all our people there ready to go.
So let's see how this works.
We're going to go into my groups and go into Star Fire project now since I didn't make anybody else
an owner when they sign into their account.
Like Mike or Bonnie or Dirk or Jim when they sign in they'll see Starfire project but they won't see
the word manage.
So they would do the same thing that would click to open it up.
All right.
Here we go.
Our project is kind of barren right now.
I think we need to stir the pot and see what comes up.
The only person obviously that has to be online when you post is you.
I mean I can come back next week and turn it on and see if anything's happened.
But let's see if we can stir this up see if anybody else is on.
Let's post a question now.
Each one of the ways that we work depending on the type of group that you're using would be a little
bit different.
But it's me right up here.
Question is what about color.
Not a question or an announcement going to come down here and say what about the color of the star for
our device and I'm going to come up here and either say I wish I'd done that or post and there it is.
Now depending on how busy I suppose the Google servers are it might take a minute or less for them to
get it and then respond.
Let's see if anybody's out there.
You can always come up here and click the refresh button to see if anything's happened.
And we have two posts.
I'm partial to and I suppose he's saying blue by that it's the color of trust.
We can go back and forth and back and forth.
Other people can get into this conversation if they're online or maybe they come in tomorrow.
Doesn't matter this little button over here.
If you click it allows you to reply forward Edit link activity band Samman owner band added show original
delete the poster print so you can print these things too.
We can set this as that's already been done before that's a duplicate.
There's no action needed.
We can move it.
It's a typical conversation going back and forth.
We've done this a million times on a million different systems except we're doing it and we created
it working with groups is an excellent way to communicate with people a specific group of people on
a specific topic.