In this chapter we're going to communicate.
Let's go to our drive first and type in drive in Chrome.
It remembers what drive is drive Google dot com because it's one of the last things I did press the
return key if you're on a Macintosh the enter key in Windows and you might need to sign in that's fine
go ahead.
And we're back into our Dr. To me the one word that defines a presentation whether it's keynote Microsoft
PowerPoint or Google Apps presentation is communication.
We're trying to communicate something.
So let's talk about how we do that how we communicate inside of Google Apps for business.
Now before we get started in my drive I did something I created a new folder Bonnie Bell and its share.
And I remember how you do that.
I right click and go to share and share with here and I shared it with her so she can add it.
I remember we've done that.
And let's go into presentation.
I'm going to open up my drive.
I do want this one to go into the folder for presentations so I select it and come up here and say create
or I can do it from here.
I met her going to create and do presentation.
Here we go.
At the moment it's an untitled presentation.
Right now the first thing it's going to ask us is what type of theme do we want.
And it has some pretty cool ones in here.
Now you don't have to use one of these.
You can make your own.
Let's go ahead and benefit from these.
Let's do motter.
Now you can choose over here.
Wide screen 69 standard four by three and wide screen 16:10.
And if you don't want to see theme come up you just want to start with a blank presentation.
You can turn this off.
We got modern click OK if you have ever used Microsoft PowerPoint or say keynote you do have a leg up
on understanding how to do presentations in Google Apps it's very similar but to me and I mean this
very seriously this is not about learning Google Apps presentation.
This is about how you do a good presentation.
I teach classes on PowerPoint.
Most of the class is not on the mechanics of PowerPoint.
It's doing the right thing because you can really distract people if you go crazy with the stuff and
you've got transitions and all kinds of things that you can use.
But if you make it too much like a circus people won't remember what you're trying to say to them.
Let's do this let's make a real quick one here and go around the interface so we can see how this works.
Click to add a title and now we get into my wonderful typing skills.
Notice it jumped two lines because it's too big.
So I could leave it that way actually it's fun but I don't want to do that.
I wanted on one line so I'm going to select all the text by dragging and come up here.
Now I could change this and we get that right.
I can change this in one of a couple of ways.
I might choose a different font and that might help put it out one line or I might change the size might
do both.
Let's just see if we can get it with the size.
I'm going to get under about 16 or 72 if you print this and you can print these 72 as a linear inch
suffragan to 60.
That fits I'm happy with that.
Let's click in here and do a subtitle.
Anytime you do a presentation the first slide you get is a title slide.
You don't have to use it but that's what it gives you up front.
If we want other slides we can click this button right here and it will give us other slides.
Probably the most used one is this one.
And if we click here we can actually add a slide based on one of the others.
We have two columns.
Title only caption blank and title and bottom.
Which is the one it gave us.
All you got to do is click on one to get it coming over here.
You can select the slide you want to work on but if you decide on this when you go on and want that
one is blank you can come back up over here to lay out and you can change that one.
So say we want that one is Tideland body.
And it will change.
If you decide you don't like the theme you can come back up here to theme but understand if you are
in one of these text boxes that goes away the area up here is context sensitive.
It depends on where you are what you're going to see.
So if you want to change for example the background of the theme we need to click out here to get those
options.
Let's go into theme and maybe we decide we don't like modern.
So we come over here we look at some of the others and maybe sketched a little bit more casual.
That's OK.
Click down here.
OK.
That's kind of interesting.
Notice it not only changed the background but it also changed the font in the color of the font too.
That's what the theme is.
It's everything.
So let's get in here and let's click on this one and go second slide come down here blah blah blah which
is what I think of some presentations that I see to be honest with you let's go to this one and this
will be our farewell.
Always leave them wanting more so long so long and thanks for all the fish.
So we've created a presentation such as it is we can select the text any time we want to and override
the theme by going up here if that's something you want to do.
Change the size bold italics underline just about anything you want to do.
So long as you have it selected.
We have some other options over here.
We'll talk about later but these are all our formatting options.
Now down here we have an area for notes.
We can make that area bigger.
These are speakers who else notice this compensates by getting smaller obviously and we can click in
here to add notes.
One of the important things about a presentation is when you finish it.
The people need to know why they were there why did they spend six hours with you or write it they spend
an hour with you during this presentation.
Let them know.
Don't necessarily entertain them but you have to keep me happy.
Get him excited.
Why are they here.
The purpose of the presentation like I said is to communicate the notes are only seen by you as the
presenter unless somebody is looking over your shoulder.
But we'll talk more about the presentation part later.
Up here you do have a button to present from the beginning.
Present with the notes are present in a new window.
And like I said we'll talk about that later.
You have comments and you can share it.
Right now it's private only to me.
Let's get this in name by clicking up here.
Click OK.
Now let's go to this button that allows me to change the folder that I put it into.
Go and organize it in the right folder.
I'm going to hold on the control key and that's the command and control key in Windows.
Same key different name.
And here's Bonnie Elle's shared folder and I'm going to click right here when we talked about documents
in the chapter on documents I talked about adding it to another folder.
This way I understand what's going on here.
I want Bonnie to collaborate on this with me.
Now I could share the presentation with her but if I create folders for say Bonnie and Mike and and
all the different people that I have and occasionally I need their input on something that I'm doing
I can put it into her folder.
Now she now has direct access to it.
And if I don't want her to have access anymore I can come right back up and turn it off right here.
But right now I do want her to help me out.
Give me some advice even maybe do some changes.
So I'm going to move it into their Come back over here and it's now in here.
And it's in here.
But remember it's not a copy it's just pointing to it.
And she now has the ability to open it and edit it in if we're both on line at the same time we can
collaborate.
That's a good reason for putting a document presentation whatever it is into multiple folders.