Generating a presentation from scratch using one of the supply templates is actually a pretty good way
to start.
But of the ones we've looked at would if none of them really excite you they're just not what you want.
Let's explore that.
Let's go into presentations because we want it to be in that folder to create and go into presentation.
So you look at these and it's like you know none of these are really exciting me that much.
So I'm going to go to a simple light and click OK.
What I would like to do is maybe design my very own template that I can use over and over again and
give it to all the other members of my organization.
So I'm to start out here with background I going to change the image actually.
Let's do that.
Let's see if we can get a good image here.
Let's go in search and type in water.
Let's see what we get if we type in water on a Google search.
Now you can click these buttons up here to change the overall color that you see.
Kind of interesting.
I of like this one right here.
Let's use this one Clix like oh there it is.
Make sure it's applied to all.
If you had more and you know actually it's not that bad I guess.
But I don't like the color so I'm going to come down here and let's type in some test text and squint
at that text come up here and let's try maybe a white OK let's change this up here too.
And let's change that to maybe yellow.
If we're going to go crazy we might as well go crazy.
Now we can add other stuff here.
For example you have this button right here for shape's and say I take this one right here and I draw
myself a little decoration up here and I can use my arrow keys to nudge it exactly where I want it to
be.
Once I have it up there and selected I can come over here change its color like I said if we're going
to go crazy we might as well go crazy.
Now we can keep going here.
OK we can do a whole lot more.
But let's say we like what we have.
Let's go ahead and give this one a name.
This is our company.
Click OK.
I like it.
Go up to the Word file on the bold on menu go down to new and go in different template.
This is kind of a roundabout way to get there but it's fine.
Now you can go into public templates and find all kinds of things.
What I want to do is submit it.
Now I'm not submitting by using that button to the world I'm submitting to my organization.
So anybody in the organization will have access to this template so we're going to choose it from google
docs.
Remember we did save it with a name when the presentations.
And there it is.
So that company thing enter a description company theme select category.
How about business.
And we could do a secondary category if we want to like maybe presentation designs select the language
mynahs United States English and submit the template that's going to take it a minute to get there.
But basically what you've got in my templates is a template that anybody that comes here in your organization
will be able to use.
So it's a great way to basically create your very own templates and then standardize that through out
the organization creating your own templates.