Once you've created a presentation you have a lot of options.
I mean we could actually use it in a presentation mode where you would hook up your computer say for
example to a projector which is how I do it and then use your computer to control the projection on
to say screen.
You could have people watch it on a monitor if you want it to.
But you also have other options.
For example if we go into presentations here and let's go and open up our demo if you go up to the Word
file on the pulled on menu you can go into e-mail as an attachment or you can go to download the ads
and either one will give you the same options here.
Number one you actually do have the ability to save this as a Microsoft PowerPoint presentation.
The only problem you might have is if there is a transition or something that you're doing within the
presentation that doesn't work with PowerPoint and with powerpoint will try to do is updated to the
latest thing that it has.
You've got PTF documents scalable vector graphics PLG and other words give me images of my presentation
as pian geez.
Jay Pegg's or just give me the text of the document.
So it's not just about publishing these things.
For example if we go into Microsoft PowerPoint see the little arrow come down here.
So we now have it as a PowerPoint presentation and we can see what it looks like in PowerPoint just
by clicking on it right here.
And since we didn't really do a whole lot to this it looks pretty much the same.
We could try to PTF or like I said just as images once you've made it.
It's not just about presenting it.
It's about maybe even downloading it as a completely different animal as they say in a different format
up to you.