In this lesson I'm going to begin by going into my drive and going into presentations.
Now I have made a couple of extra presentations.
We'll talk about those in a second.
I'm going to open up demo presentation right here.
This is exciting isn't it.
Now I need more stuff.
I mean this is an excellent presentation.
I absolutely love it.
But I need more stuff.
Why reinvent the wheel.
Now what I'm saying here is what if you have another presentation and in that presentation is either
a foundational piece or exactly what you want.
Why reinvent the wheel.
So what we can do here is open up a presentation and we've got it.
We can then go up to the word insert on the pulled up menu and go down to now new slide.
That's the same as clicking this button over here.
Hey we're not going to do that.
We're going to import what do we get.
We get every single presentation that we have ever made in Google Apps that's here and any that people
have shared with us and maybe there's something in it that you could use.
Now you can also click here and get it into more of a grid kind of look.
And we can go back to this one you can actually see them.
Now I've got the demo.
That's the one we're using.
I've got the one we made earlier got the presentation points.
I'm doing a presentation for presenters on how to present which actually I do.
I train presenters on how to present.
So I've got slides that have points on them that would be good in this presentation like this one.
Points to Ponder.
I'm thinking yeah I can use that.
So I selected here and click Select here.
If there were more than one slide in most presentations do have more than one slide in them.
You could select the slides up here that you want to send over to your presentation.
You have a button down here or a tick box.
Keep the original theme.
Now that theme is the original thing so it doesn't matter.
It's the same one as we're using over here.
I'm going to select just the one and then import it.
This is not rocket science.
Now there it is.
Now once it's over here we can move it around and just click on it and drag it.
Well let's go ahead and bring in another one.
Let's go back up to the word insert and go down to import slides.
This one right here.
Color changes mood.
And it actually does.
Again we're doing a Google app presentation PowerPoint keynote whatever it is.
Anybody can learn how to use the program but not everybody can create good presentations.
That really is kind of important.
This one only has one slide too and that's all right.
I'm going to select it I'm going to come over here and say import slides.
This time I'm going to say keep a regional thing.
Now what did that do.
It kept the original theme.
If you're working on a presentation and you think you have other presentations which you eventually
are going to build a library of these things why reinvent the wheel.
Let's go ahead and click right over here.
It does save automatically remember and we now have our presentation with two additional slides importing
slides is very easy.