I'm going to begin this lesson by going into presentations and opening up demo presentation.
So we've done a few things to this.
We've actually added a couple of slides.
Let's talk about some of the basic formatting things that you can do.
Like Number one if I want to I can change the background color in an image we've done that.
And you can change the background.
We can change the layout of the one slide that you're looking at.
We can change the theme.
The overall theme of the entire thing if we select the text we get text options up here of course we
do we have the ability to change the font change the color change it bold it attacks underline it change
the font size all those things.
Now I'm looking at the color red right there and the color red is a very passionate color.
People exposed to Red actually their heart rates will increase and their blood pressure will go up it's
an interest in color I'm deciding I don't want them quite so excited with the first slide I need to
change that.
Something to come over here and select demo presentation and click right here of course and change maybe
to blue.
Blue is more of a color of trust.
Now we can dislike like this and decide if we like it.
So we're literally overriding the theme that we used which is fine the computer doesn't care so I can
blame you for that.
You work with your experience based on what you want to do here and you have the tools to make it happen.
Now my name is not capitalized.
It's just something I do.
I don't know why.
I just don't capitalize my name unless I'm doing something very formal.
So I'm happy with that.
I don't have to change that.
But you know we can if we want to but maybe change the font.
So I want to come over here and select the text.
Then you come up here just like wordprocessing and choose a different font if you want to just don't
use that one.
OK.
Comic Sans is overused.
We need to give that one a rest.
How about this one right here.
It looks very fancy doesn't it.
So we've made a couple of changes.
Big deal let's go into this slide right here.
I don't even need that slide anymore.
So what I'm going to do is press the delete key.
Now here we go Mac and Windows again.
If you've got a Macintosh keyboard it's the delete key if you've got a Windows keyboard it's the backspace
key.
I just love that.
Now we got points to ponder.
Kind of happy with the font.
I'm OK with that.
But my problem here is when we display this presentation this guy right here this area is going to completely
show at one time.
That's bad.
If you put all your points up while you're doing your lecture guess what people are going to do.
They're going to read ahead and when they read ahead they're going to get bored because they know what
you're going to talk about.
So what we need is to have one point come up at a time and this is cool animation.
There's all kinds of ways we can animate if we right click this just an easier way to get there.
Right clicking go on to animate.
And there you go.
Now it says the slide itself has no transition.
We'll talk about that too.
But this one right here we have what do you want the fade in fade out.
Fly in fly out zoom in zoom out or spin.
Let me give you a word of advice here.
Just because you can really animate something in a really wonky way doesn't mean you need to because
if your presentations look like a circus with things bouncing and dancing all over the place people
are not listening to you anymore they're thinking about what are you going to do to them next.
Fade in is very boring but it works.
It's really that a fade in now on a click.
Definitely because I don't know how long I'm really going to talk about each one of those points.
I want to control the process with a click but you can say after previous Now what would that do.
It would open the slide.
Points to Ponder would already be there and then would automatically start letting the other points
come up one at a time in a timed sequence.
I want to control what you say On Click now.
Also if you don't turn on by paragraph it's going to turn them all on at the same time.
Let's play it.
Now we're in a demo mode here.
Click slide or press enter to continue.
So I'm going to press my Enter key.
That's actually the return key on a Macintosh and I start talking start the presentation with excitement
face your audience.
The slide show does look at your audience and here's what I love.
Don't read the slides.
I've had presenters because I train presenters that will actually look at the presentation that means
their back is to the audience and read verbatim what's on the slides if that's all you're going to do.
Print it.
Give it to him.
Let him leave early.
Keep the audience involved if you're ever in one of my classes at university or when I am on the road
you will be involved in my class.
I promise you in one way or another end with a call action I'm controlling the process by clicking pressing
the return key.
Anarchy in windows turn on a Mac whatever you want to do.
And we can control how fast or slow the fade happens.
By using this option right here controlling what we do with an animation.
Now let's go to our next one over here.
Number one that's kind of a Star Trek look at that so we can come over obviously and we can change the
theme.
You don't have to do this of course but this is the one we're using.
And it will change it.
Now how did I get those bullet points.
Well let's select everything.
Go over to more right here and you have more options like oh bullet points numbered points changing
things like line spacing etc. and we come over here and say Do bullets in that too and it will change
it make it very happy for us.
We can add an animation just like we did on the other one.
What we're doing is we're adding life to the presentation.
We're changing things the way we want them to be.
We're working with some of our formatting tools and we're just making it more of not entertainment but
we're making our presentation in such a way that it creates interest and curiosity with our audience
which keeps their attention.
Let's go ahead and get out of here for now.
Clicking right up here takes us right back to Google Drive.
All changes have automatically been saved.
There you go.