In this lesson we're going to talk about images but we're going to talk about images in two different
areas in a presentation.
One is on a regular slide and one is in a very important place to know that you have Master's.
So let's go into my presentations and I'm going to open up our demo right here.
Now demo presentation I want an image on this slide so I can come over here and click this button right
there.
Now we've been here before.
If you've got images in your albums Google Drive you can do a search.
I'm going to upload.
I'm going to drag it over.
I've got an image I want to use someone to drag it over here and just drop it in.
Because this is about doing presentations and put him right down there.
And once I've got him there I can expand or contract his size.
That's something I want to do.
I can rotate him by grabbing right here and dragging one way or the other.
I can of course get in there and use my arrow keys to gently nudge him into place.
And now we have a graphic on here.
Big deal right.
But I want all of these slides.
Number one or the send kind of slide.
If we come back up here they are the title and body slide right here.
I want the graphic on those but I want it on all of them.
Do I have to do it one at a time.
And the answer to that is no.
I love this feature.
Go up to the word view and go down to master now now in Master you have a master and then lay outs down
here.
If I put anything on this one right up here like a graphic it will appear on every single other slide.
Every time I create a new slide this is the one that we're using.
So if I come down to that one in select it and I'm going to drag another one over or I can do the same
thing right here I can go an image and I'm going to drag a different one over.
I'm going to take that and I'm going to move it down here.
Say like that.
Notice it's only on this one right here but that represents the master for this slide presentation.
Every time I use that type of slide that's the cool thing.
But we're not done.
Let me mention at least one more thing here.
If I don't like the fun it's using if I change it here it will change it on every slide that corresponds
to this one.
But if I come up to this one which is the master master and change it here all the slides will change.
Masters are tremendously important.
But if we get out of here now you will notice that on this one we had the guy with the alphabet coming
out of his mouth and on these in the exact same position on everyone you can access it.
You have to go back to the master to do that.
It's on everyone one when you're putting together a slide presentation.
You don't like the fonts you don't like the graphics.
Don't forget you got masters because those can really help you flesh out the presentation.
Make it efficient and make it consistent.