You can work on a presentation as long as you want.
You can add graphics to it you can animate stuff you can do well just about anything but sooner or later
guess what you're going to have to do the presentation may not be you but let's assume it is.
So I'm going to go into presentations and open up good old demo presentations if all I do is show you
how to do the presentation.
This would be a rather short lesson.
So let's do something else here let's come down to the end slide.
What I want to happen here is something like this.
I want to talk for a while and then my final words are so long so long and thanks for all the fish and
then I want another graphic to come in.
So I'm going to do this.
Let's go ahead and select here and right click and go into anime.
I want it to fade in on a click.
So I'm going to decide when it fades and I'm done talking.
I say so long.
So I'm happy with that one.
I don't really have to change anything on that.
I'm going to bring in a graphic now.
Now usually we click up here.
You don't have to do that.
This is the Google Chrome experience.
I can drag it in if I want to.
So I'm going to drag in a graphic just like this.
OK.
We got a graphic coming in.
Move him down to about here.
Now here's the deal.
I don't want to have to click for him to come in.
I want him to come in after I've clicked for so long.
So add animation.
This one's on a click.
This guy will have fly in it.
He's a bird.
But after previous previous When I click up here and bring the text in let's make him a little slower.
And let's see how this works.
Click play
so blah blah blah.
Talk glad you're here.
I finally hit the return key whatever.
And that comes in and then the big concern is what I want.
But we have one more thing we have to do.
Our slides don't have transition.
So they're going to come in and out like a jolt clicks stop over here.
So I'm going to come over here and select this one.
Now if we select them all just like this we come over here.
This slide has no transition we can click here and give them a transition I'm a boring person I'm going
fade.
Actually we didn't have to select them all over there you can say apply all here and now they have a
transition.
Let's close this out.
Now the presentation.
How do you do this.
You have a computer laptop whatever you have plugged into say a projector or you've got another computer
monitor that you're projecting it out for people.
You open it up just like we've done.
You go up to the present.
Now at present you can present from the beginning you can present it with the notes understand the speaker
sees the notes.
The people who are watching it on a monitor or on a screen won't where you can present it in a new window.
That's just present from beginning.
Again they're not going to see that up there.
You have controls down here if you want to move between your slides or you can just use your return
key and see the Fade in.
Now we animated the slides so I can talk about each one of these things I'm pressing the return anarchy
to get to the next one.
Goes to the next we didn't animate these goes to this one.
Talk.
Blah blah blah.
So long so long.
And then in comes the bird you've just completed the presentation.
If you press the escape key you get back out of it.
You can come over here
presentations especially if you are a Microsoft PowerPoint or an Apple keynote kind of person are not
that difficult to put together.
They're very similar but remember one thing.
It's not about the buttons.
It's about communication.
Nuff said.