One of the areas that I really find fascinating about the Internet is the capture of information.
So we're going to talk about something called Google Forms and actually how easy they are to make.
We will create a forum.
We will talk about how we format that form.
And don't forget you've got templates for this too.
You don't have to reinvent the wheel.
If something's out there already done you can use it.
Well talk about exporting in sending the forms.
We'll talk about responding to a Forms email request.
We'll talk about Preece filling out some of the areas in the forum and we'll talk about working with
notifications and rules as they pertain to forms.
This chapter is all about gathering information.
This chapter is all about forms.