Before I started this lesson I took the liberty of answering for two of the three people in Starfire.
Mike is the one that's left so let's see how this works.
We're going to sign him in right now.
Now here's the e-mail right here.
Now I like this when you see a time or date with the dotted underline you can click on and added automatically
to what Google calendar.
It's pretty cool.
I mean get out of here.
He's the last one to fill out the form so let's do it for him right here.
Yes I am coming.
I will arrive by submarine and I will bring one other person and I'm going to submit your response has
been recorded.
Thank you very much.
Let's go ahead and get out of this one here.
Let's sign Mike out.
And let's sign me back in.
Anybody can make a form as a user if they're set up correctly and all that means is they own it.
So going back to me I'm the owner.
Let's go into Google Dr. let's go into forms.
Now check this out.
There are the responses and there they are.
There's a time stamp there is.
And are you going to attend In other words for each one of our questions.
Everybody's coming.
Auto plane and submarine 2 1 1 Bonnie brought a point to me.
I'm not going to change it since we're kind of just playing around here.
But she said something to me that made sense.
She said you made a mistake on how many guests and I said What.
She said well you made it a required field.
I said yes.
He said but you didn't give them a zero.
So they have to bring somebody.
So you're saying I'm in I wasn't going to bring anybody but Andy won't let me type in zero.
So obviously that's something you would have to correct.
We won't.
But you know how to do that.
What can we do now from here.
Well some of the things you can do kind of cool if you go up to the Word form on the pull down menu
go down to show summary of responses.
This is really nice.
Now we don't have a lot of data but it's giving us information over here.
And I saw a pie chart over there showing us how we are doing.
Go ahead and close that out.
One more thing.
If on the spreadsheet you go to the Word file and you go down to download as you get a whole lot more
options.
You can download this as a Microsoft Excel spreadsheet open document format PTF there's CXXVI again
comma separated values tab separated values or a web page.
All the information you need tabulated on the spreadsheet to make your meeting a success.