When I'm filling out a form like maybe a survey it's got a lot of stuff in it.
Right.
What I do appreciate about the people that create the survey is filling out for me some of the obvious
stuff.
Say for example I'm doing a survey of people and I know they live in the state of Kansas.
Well if there's a state field right when I type in Kansas and saved them from doing it the more you
can do that on the survey type of forum the more likely people will stay in fill it out.
So let's do this let me show you this.
Go into forms and we're going to go into Starfire right here.
So if you perform open it up under responses you have an option to get pre-filled you RL.
If I select that what I can do is basically fill out some of the information.
Now in our case probably not so much on this type of forum but I do want everybody to come.
So if I click here when they actually get the form that will already be filled out.
Or they can still say no but they're getting the hint that yeah I kind of want them to come.
I could put something into here if I wanted to get them started.
I could say well most people are going to go by plane because we're traveling to the other side of the
planet so I'll fill that out for them creating the form in a pre-filled state maybe not so much ours
but long forms where you can fill things in for people can really as I've said help them stay to finish
the form out pre-fall forms.