The journey of a thousand miles is about to begin.
I promise I won't make it quite that long.
We're talking about Google Apps for business.
Now the first thing we should discuss here is browsers.
I am using a Macintosh computer to teach this and I love Macs been using them for years.
At university we have Windows systems mostly in our labs.
Love them.
Been using them for years.
You might be on a Mac.
You might be on a Windows system that really doesn't make any difference but let's talk browsers Safari
is the browser of choice for most people that use Mac and I would suggest Explorer is probably the browser
of choice for Windows Explorer is no longer supported on a Macintosh and Safari has never supported
Windows.
So what do we do.
Well it really doesn't matter.
But what I want to use is Google Chrome now two reasons.
Number one it puts us on a level playing field whether we're Mac or Windows.
But the other thing as you're going to see as we move along through these lessons is there are some
advantages actually to using Google Chrome that's free.
All you have to do is download it.
I've got it open already.
First thing I need to do is get to Google Apps for business.
Now if you're using Chrome or Safari you can click the search criteria right up here in the area that
you normally put in your you are out Google Apps for business.
Hit the enter key.
Now you should see something like this and this is what we want right here.
Google Apps for business.
This is the landing page for Google Apps for business.
Now it's possible that it might look slightly different than what you're seeing through my lesson right
here and the reason being is kind of like a magazine cover.
They do change it occasionally you will see the get started button and that's where we want to go.
Go ahead and click it.
Most of the information in setting up is rather straightforward.
For example you probably know your name so go ahead and type that in your current e-mail address when
you use orch your business or organization name.
I always hope I spelled it correctly.
Number of employees in my business is between 2 and 9 countries united states don't have to change that
phone number.
Now if you're not from the United States you can use a different phone number pattern right over here
by clicking.
Let's click next.
Your business or domain address.
Now there used to be three choices up there not just to use a domain name I already have purchased and
you'll have to verify it.
Or buy one if you want to.
Now let's do something here.
Let's stop and ponder.
Yes the great game of stopping and pondering.
Give me 60 seconds let's say for the sake of argument that this hits you by surprise that you didn't
really think through the idea of the domain name.
You know you're going to get one but you didn't know you needed it.
Now to start Google Apps for business if that's the case if you haven't done this yet.
What I really want you to do and I'm serious is I want you to stop.
I want you to close me down quick.
You can always come back to me later and really sit down and think through the name of your business
because it's your domain name.
If it's a wanky name or something that people can't remember they're never going to find you.
You realize how much money I would have paid to get.
Andy Anderson dotcom thing that's a pretty common name on the side of the pond.
Not a chance.
I'll never have that domain name so I chose real Indy.
And when I'm talking to people about my web site I say it's real and because there's a lot of imposters
out there and it sets you up to remember real landie dotcom.
Now I've already got one.
But if you don't you can click here in Bayat you can buy it at other places.
You don't have to do it here but I'm going to say I'm going to use a domain name and then type it in
down here.
Click next.
Now we have to create a Google Apps account so I'm going to choose my username name right over here
I'm going to say Andy at real Andy dotcom.
Create a password.
Remember it.
Now we have to prove we're not a robot.
I don't think I'm a robot but I'm probably pretty close.
Type the text.
Now that looks like 29 over there on the left and then six 4:55 6 8 9 4.
Now assuming I did that correctly I then get the choice of saying I would like to receive emails and
I've read and agreed and you have to click this one and then say accept and sign up right.
They're setting up my account.
Really wasn't rocket science the hardest thing really is if the domain name surprises you.
Now there you go.
We're going to stop right now.
We have set up our count.
We're going to talk about users and profiles and that as we move along.