The next step that we need to do after we put our Google accounts together is we actually need to verify
our domain to prove we have legal use to use it.
Now I've gotten out of the admin Council and I did that on purpose.
How do you get back in.
You will receive an email saying welcome to google account for business and you can click here anytime
and get back into your admin account.
But what if you forget that or you just misplace it.
Emails can get misplaced.
Do this go into chrome or Safari Explorer or whatever and come up here and type in admin HDMI and Dot
Google dot com.
Now I've done it more than once it remembers it.
Type in the email you created when you put this together.
That for me would be Andy at real landie dotcom type in your password and go ahead and sign in.
Now you can choose to stay signed in if you want to.
The next thing that we need to do is verify our domain right here.
Now it might say set up.
If it does and you click it the next thing it will say is verify domain.
I'm going to go ahead and verify my domain.
Now what this means is do I have legal use of that domain.
I have to prove it.
Begin verification.
You have a couple of methods.
You have the recommended method.
I didn't use the recommended method but I want to show you all your methods here.
This one is actually the easiest.
If you have access to admin on your hosting provider or if I come down here find mine through the list
and I've got some with Melbourne and I've got some with Network Solutions.
If I select here here's where the fun starts.
It gives you a list of instructions on what you have to do what I need to do is go into Network Solutions
dot com by clicking here access my managed account.
So I have to have the sign in the admin password for network solutions that might be your I-T department.
But before you go there you select this text down here and you're going to have to paste that into an
area.
You drill down down down and you finally get here and you copy and paste it.
So I would go here and basically begin the process.
I'm not going to do that because everyone would be different.
Let's get back to here.
Me show you what I did this process and you're just following instructions.
But this process can take up to 24 hours before it actually becomes verifiable.
Your alternate methods.
The one I chose was an H team Eltang.
I designed my own web sites using a program called Dreamweaver.
I absolutely love it it's a dream come true and I decided instead of going through the recommended method
I would use NHT mail tag.
To me this was actually easier.
So I went in here.
It is very easy it tells you what to do.
You go into your index page and you select this text which is a metal tag and you copy it into your
index page.
That's all I had to do.
Now once I've done that I come back out save the page load it back to the host and then come down here
and say verify.
Now you can see it still says we weren't able to.
In my case I did this just a few minutes ago so it still hasn't gotten to google yet that I'm verifiable.
But that's OK.
Really it is.
Don't worry about it just quick Not now.
Come back in an hour to try again.
That's all you have to remember.