All right here we are back in Google Chrome or Explorer or Safari doesn't matter I'm going to sign back
in.
That's going to assume I probably want to use this one which I do and I'm going to type in my super
double top secret password and not sign in.
Don't forget you can stay signed in if you want to.
Now one thing you might notice right up here.
It says next step.
Now when we last left it said varified domain.
So it did happen.
But let me give you some particulars on that.
It took almost 24 hours.
Now that really surprised me because the method that I used is almost instantaneous usually but I guess
that means something here even if you do everything right it still might take them a bit of time to
verify it.
So don't worry about it it's going to happen eventually.
But it allows us to go to the next step before we go there.
I want to show you one more thing here that will add functionality to google come down to more controls
right down here and click.
Now you have other things in here that you can use.
The one I want to show you very quickly is Marketplace apps.
Now if you click it right here it will open market place apps if you want to add it up here into your
counsel come down and click the plus sign right here.
Now we can close this right here and there it is.
So you can add things to your counsel right up here.
Now go ahead and click it.
I just want to show you something.
These are additional apps be on the Google Apps for business that can help with functionality.
All kinds of things out here.
I've already got one.
You might not have any.
It's mind Meister and it's a mind mapping program.
I like to mind map my projects and it is on for everyone.
So how do I get these things.
Well now that we're here we can click this button right up here and it will open up this little widget.
And here they are here's my mind mapping program.
If you scroll over it it'll give you a little bit more information and the ability to download it or
installing.
So you got a lot of things in here.
Most of them actually are free.
Some of them do cost.
Let's say we want this one right here.
Copy and share your files folders on Google Drive with other users.
That sounds interesting I think I'll install it.
Now when you do this you're going to see different things here because these programs depending on what
they are need control and access.
And in granting this application the right to access my domain data you don't want to do that and don't
do it on here turn it on for me.
I only have one domain.
I do agree to the application terminal service and I click except copy has been added.
We can keep this up all day long close out of here.
Let's go ahead and close out of here and there it is.
Now what do we do with it now that we have it.
Well by default it's on for everyone.
What I can do here is click right here next to it and I can actually turn it off if I don't want people
to have access to it.
You're in control.
You're the adult in the room.
You're the administrator.
Somebody has to be the adult.
And it's you you can turn them on or you can turn them off if you want to run it.
You click right here and you can come right over here and say launch the app or you can say I don't
want it anymore.
Now here's something you want to remember if you remove an app if it's a paid app service and you paid
for this when you remove it and reinstall it.
You are probably going to have to repurchase it.
So you want to think about that before you get rid of one.
But if we do that we can just remove it.
You know I'm back to what these additional services are actually very nice to have.
I'm going to go back into our admin council here because they add more functionality to what you're
doing.