Go into the admin Council go ahead and sign in.
Let's talk a little bit more about users.
Now we've already added one user.
And let's talk a little bit more about how we do that.
So if we come down here and click users you can see we do have one Bonnie Lloyd she's never logged in
yet.
And you got me those are the two users.
But chances are you're going to have more than two.
So let's come up over here and click right here and we have three options invite add them manually or
use a C S V Palma's separated value file.
Let's look at each one of these.
Let's start with inviting.
So I click here to invite users click Continue.
Who do you want to invite.
Chances are there probably is a whatever dotcom out there with somebody named James.
You can add three if you want to add more you can.
Now let's assume we want to send.
So click continue.
And you'll see the letter they will get an email with this wording and they'll have a link to click
to come to set it up and you can add as many of these as you want.
Let's not send this one.
The next one.
We've already done.
But let's look at it again and manually type in first name.
James Lloyd my father in law James that real Andy dotcom and don't forget about the password thing.
Give them a password.
But I would strongly recommend for security that you require the user to change the password at the
next sign that you've already done this one once we did it with Bonnie.
Let's look at the last one.
You have a large company and you don't want to add these things one at a time which frankly I don't
blame you.
So let's come back up here again one more time go into this one add several users with see as free fall.
It gives you an example.
So you're looking at something that was done probably in something like Microsoft Excel and it has to
be in this format or it won't work.
Let me show you one that I've done.
As you can see I've got an e-mail address for each one the first name a last name and password.
Those fields must be filled out correctly.
Now we need to save this as a C S V not an Excel spreadsheet file and you can see I've already done
that right here CXXVI.
So you would go to the word final and say Save As and just make sure you have this option selected comma
separated values.
We've done that.
Let's get out of here.
Let's go back.
Let me come down here.
You've got some options.
Number one create new accounts for the e-mail addresses is a default obviously update existing accounts
with new names and passwords.
That's interesting.
In other words you can use the C S V file to update existing accounts.
And I really recommend for security that you take that one right there require a password.
Let's get our fight.
And that would be in users.
There it is right there.
Upload and continue and cross your fingers.
Now there they are.
If there were anything wrong with them it would tell you confirm and upload.
Now it's just telling me it could take a bit of time but we can leave this page if we want to.
And there they are.
I didn't think it would take very long.
So three different ways to work with them.
If you don't want them anymore you can select them right here.
And come up here and say delete but when you do everything that they have done is going to be gone.
So it's telling you I want to make sure you know this.
So you can't delete them until you say yes I understand.
All documents all e-mail all calendars will be deleted.
Then you can click down here so they give you another option is to transfer the documents of these users
to another account before you do this.
Now we don't have to worry.
There is nothing in there we can delete them and take about a second or two.
And now we're back just to Bonnie in me working with users.
We're going to do a whole lot more with users as we go on.
But working with users we can add them in three different ways.
Up to you.